Okay, let's ask some questions about it; see if you followed
everything I said there. Which of these things regarding cost is
true? Three should be false. As practitioners of Agile
Development, Pivotal Labs does not use contracts. As
practitioners of pair programming, Pivotal Labs estimates the
cost for one pair to do it, and assigns that pair to complete
the project. The cost bid is for Pivotal Labs time and materials
that covers the number of weeks in the estimate, as studies show
that 84 to 90% of projects are on time and on budget, plan and
document managers promise customers a set of features for
agreed- upon cost by agreed upon date. Which of these is true?
Okay, you guys are already ready. Ready, set, vote. All right.
That is again… I'm an easy question answer. The last one there
is, I'm still stunned that 84 to 90% of projects are over
budget and on time, so I'll keep throwing that out. The plan as
we'll see; the plan and document managers do promise customers
a set of features for an agreed- upon cost by an agreed- upon
date, despite the fact that 84 to 90% of all projects haven't
done that. Nevertheless, that's what a project manager does.
Pivotal Labs does not use contracts. They do use contracts, but
it's a contracts that's based on effort. There's a contract
that's signed, but it's not for features. Pivotal Labs assigns
the cost in pairs. They do. They actually, because they believe
in pair programming, they actually say it's pair weeks. They
don't just assign one pair to do it. They can assign as many
pairs as makes sense. You don't want to have too many people
that they can get in each other way and too much time
communicating, but they'll figure out the scoping of the
project and assign people to do it, so it will be done in less
time. More than one pair works on it, so they do actually bid in
pair weeks. It's based on the time and materials that cover the
weeks in the estimate. That was kind of an easy answer.