Let's start our whirlwind tour of Rails, and its Model View
Controller. We're going to more or less go in that order, so
we'll start with the part that's actually the heaviest weight
part. I'll give you an introduction to Active Record. Active
Record is actually a design pattern. It's not just the name of
this library that's part of Rails. It's a way, like we said
earlier, of thinking about how you connect in- memory objects
that are instances of a Ruby class, with the representation of
those objects when they're stored in something like a persistent
database. The thing that Active Record tries to answer for us is
how can we use some of the interesting language features we've
seen like reflection and meta- programming to simplify how this
design pattern is provided to us and how it's implemented? In
this case, the design pattern in question is Active Record,
which bridges the gap between instances of a Ruby class that
you've defined and their stored representation. CRUD in SQL.
Let's start out with some acronyms right away. The Structured
Query Language, if you've never heard the abbreviation, SQL,
most people pronounce it sequel, although I believe technically
that is not correct, is a query language that is used by
relational databases, which is probably one of the most
important, if not the most important, advance that computer
science made in understanding how to organize and query and talk
about the relationships among different types of data. In fact,
Ted Codd received the Turing Award for his contribution of the
relational algebra, which is a formalism for manipulating data,
and the SQL language really is a way to instantiate the
relational algebra in engineering terms and build engines that
can manipulate data according to those rules. The way Active
Record works is that Rails generates the SQL statements you need
at Runtime based on your Ruby code, and I'm going to use this
icon to call your attention to the fact that this is one of many
examples we'll see of code being generated at Runtime. Sometimes
at Runtime, other times at Compiletime, but the idea of code
that writes other code is pervasive in Ruby. We've already seen
a little bit using things like method_ missing and attr_
accessor, where we can create new code at Runtime. This is
another example. There's four things that you can do to a piece
of data when it sits in a persistent storage system, and not
just in a relational database, really in any persistent storage.
You can create a new piece of data there. You can read data that
is already in there. You can update something about an existing
piece of data or you can delete it. We're not going to do very
much raw SQL in this class. We actually don't have to, but it is
worth at least going through a couple of the SQL tutorials to
see some of the basics and to get used to what it looks like,
just because in some cases like all abstractions, Active Record
is a leaky abstraction. Sometimes it doesn't work quite the way
you expect or sometimes, because of your own misunderstanding,
you might accidentally misuse it and not express the query you
thought that you were expressing. At some level, it is useful to
be able to look at the SQL that was generated and say, " 'Oh
okay, that's why my query is not working." Here's a simple
example of what creation looks like if you were writing in raw
SQL. Here, the assumption is users is the name of the table and
I'm going to insert into it values for at least these three
columns, which are assumed to be part of the schema. Columns in
that table. Here's the values that I'm going to put into those
columns. I've got one tuple, which is information about myself,
and another tuple, which is information about Dave. I've added
two rows to the database. I haven't made explicit whether
there's other columns in the table or not, but certainly I'm
assuming that these three exist. I can also read from that
table. I can say select, and the star means when you find rows
that match my criterion, give me back all of the attributes
associated with each of those rows. Select star from the users
table where certain conditions are true. An example of a simple
condition is birth date between two particular dates. There's
many other ways that you can do matching things in SQL. I can
update. I can say in the users table, do an update such that any
user where the user name equals fox, you should substitute, you
should set a new value, for the email attribute to be this. In
some cases, if we assume user name is unique in our example,
then in this case, update would only affect a single row. It's
possible, and indeed Rails relies on the fact, that you can
write update statements that affect many rows. You have a
collection of rows that match some criterion, and on each one of
those rows, you're going to update in place one or more of its
attributes. Finally you can say DELETE FROM, and again, you can
provide a variety of ways to match what the WHERE condition is.
Those are the four basic operations. We're going to use those as
a starting point to talk about Active Record. We briefly
discussed that the Ruby side of a model inherits from Active
Record base and that's the way you connect the model to the
database. Among the many things Active Record does is it
certainly makes it easier to do those CRUD operations on the
model. Let's switch over to a code view. Here's a small chunk of
Ruby code. What have I done here? I declared a class movie that
inherits from Active Record base. That's it. I have not put any
code whatsoever into this class. Because you all know object-
oriented programming, you realize that that doesn't matter
because there's already a bunch of code in the class, so to
speak. It's the code that its ancestor has, Active Record base.
I'm just saying I'm going to create objects of class movie,
they're going to inherit all of the behaviors of Active Record
base. Here's examples of some of them. I'm going to create a new
movie and remember, when we see the capital letters for class
names: Movie. NEW, that means that new is a class method. That
makes sense. You don't have an object yet, then you can't do
anything to it. You need a class method to create the object for
you. Once you've got the object, I'm assuming that it's got
these attributes: title and rating. What we're going to see in a
minute is that rather than declaring in Ruby what the attributes
are and then separately making sure you have a database table
that matches, Ruby will actually infer what the attributes are
by looking at the database table. It saves you some typing.
Another way that I could create a new movie is I could use the
fact that NEW optionally takes a block and it yields, to that
block, the newly created object. If I had to do some complicated
initialization of the object, it's often easier to do this, than
to have a bunch of lines setting up individual things. In Rails,
another thing we're going to see a lot of, which is the
handshake icon here, is convention over configuration, which
means if you stick to certain rules for naming things, there's a
bunch of work you don't have to do to tell Rails the
correspondence between different types of objects. In this case,
the database table name is assumed to be derived from the name
of the model. If the model name is Movie with a capital M, then
the database table is lowercase movies, s- plural. Why is it s-
plural? Because it stands to reason a table contains more than
one movie, so a table called movie wouldn't make a lot of sense.
It's just more satisfying to pluralize it. In case you were
going to ask, if you have a table or if you have a model called
person, does that mean that the table is called people? Yes, it
does. If your model is called sheep, does that mean that the
table is also called sheep? Yes, there's a part of Ruby that
just cares about how to pluralize words. It's called the
inflector. Again, why is this? Because it makes sense. You have
a movie, a table holds lots of movies. Very sensible. The
database table column names become getters and setters for model
attributes. This is really important, because what we've seen so
far is we defined, using attr_ accessor for example, what we
wanted the attributes to be. What I showed you is when you use
attr_ accessor, the only thing that it really does is create the
world's simplest getters and setters. Really just wrappers
around setting instance variables. Now this is going to be
different, and this shows you the benefit of why it's cool, in
some sense, that the only access to a data object's attributes
is through getters and setters. Active Record defines getters
and setters that actually work by talking to the database. The
way that you use these models, and Ruby looks just like plain
old models with attr_ accessor, but the way that the
implementation works is completely different. As we'll see, the
getters and setters don't actually modify instance variables.
There is no underlining instance variable, for example, at title
for a movie, instead there's an internal manipulation that Ruby
manipulates and that Rails causes to be translated to the
database. How does this work? We've created a new movie, but we
haven't actually put it in the database yet. All we've done is
create a new Ruby object and set some attributes on it. If we
call save on that object, or save bang or save or whatever you
want to call the other one, once you call that on the model,
that's actually when the changes happen. That's when the
database actually gets updated with the new attributes that
you've set for that model. Remember we said before, that when
there's a bang on the end of a method name, it usually means
dangerous method, use with care. In the case of the Active
Record methods that have bang on the end, it means they raise an
exception if they fail as opposed to the non- bang methods,
which just return nil if they fail and you have to check. Which
one is more appropriate to use depends on the context in which
you're trying to do it. Once an object's been created, it
acquires a primary key. Remember, we said that by convention,
the primary keys of Rails' objects are integers. It's an ID that
is unique in the entire table. Obviously before the object has
been saved, it can't have an ID, it only acquires one the first
time the database saves it. If you have an Active Record model
and its ID attribute is nil, or if you call new record on it and
you get back true, it means that model has never been saved.
You've manipulated it in memory, you have not actually saved it
in the database. All these behaviors are inherited from Active
Record base. They're not things that are true of Ruby objects in
general.