This is the plan and document perspective. Partly the reason
that we’ re doing this is, in the past when we taught the class;
we get lots of nice comments about the class. It changed my
life. I got a job. It’ s wonderful [ inaudible 00:00:16]. People
say, “ Oh I’ m done internships before. Nobody builds software,
in the real world, we’ ll don’ t do it that way.” Even on the [
inaudible 00:00:23] comments. They were, “ I would never use
software built with Agile. This is crazy. This is the way the
others do it.” We thought we’ d let you know what the official
alternative units look like, because if you become software
engineers., you may do projects like this and you need to know
these things are. It’ ll help you see where Agile came from and
appreciate what it’ s doing. This will take a little bit a while
to be able to do this. They don’ t use user stories, points, or
velocity. What do they do instead? It’ s before… pre- Agile. How
do you make these costs? How do you make these schedules? These
are all the steps. If you get to be the program manager, you’ re
going to do requirements in elicitation, requirements,
documentation, the cost estimate. You’ ll be scheduling and
monitoring the progress of the project. You’ re going to do,
change management, like version control for your schedule, the
cost, and the requirements document. You have to ensure that the
implementation actually matches the features that were in the
contract, in the documentation. Then, to increase the chances
that you’ ll hit the schedule, hit the target in the budget, you
do risk analysis and risk management. These are all your tasks
to do. This will take a little while to go over it. Let’ s do
the requirements elicitation. You’ re looking for both, what I
call functional and non- functional requirements. Functional is
like we’ ve seen. Add a movie to run databases. Non- functional
would be… It’ s a weird word, but it’ s about its performance.
Non- functional; it’ s not features. It should be non- feature.
Nonfunctional means 99% response time less than a second or 4/ 9
of dependability. How do you elicit those things? Again, it has
to come from the customer, so it’ s pretty much the project
manager, primarily doing this. Project manager tries
interviewing. You want to find out how the work is really done,
not the way it’ s supposed to be done. Maybe you sent a
questionnaire to all the stakeholders to have them fill them out
or you just have these informal discussions. You’ re trying to
feel out how should this really be done or how is it done today.
You work with the customer to create these scenarios. You start
off with the initial state. You show the flow for happy and sad
paths, what can be done concurrently, and the final state. A
third approach is what’ s called use cases and there’ s actually
a program… There’ s a language called the unified modeling
language helps you describe these use cases. They have little
stick figures in showing all the steps for the user in the
system to achieve the goal. These are ways for the product… User
product elicitation, what does the customer want? After you’ ve
elicited the requirements, you do documentation. This is serious
documentation. It’ s called the SRS, in the lingo that stands
for Software Requirements Specification. These are big, hundreds
of pages. There is even IEEE standard on how to write an SRS.
You can read a document that describes a standard about how to
build this document. Remember, this is inspired by software
doesn’ t work; we got to make it like civil engineering. Civil
engineering has a lot of documents. We’ re going to have a lot
of documents. How do you figure out if the SRS is okay? I’ ll
tell you the four things to look at. The way you do it, get the
customers to read these hundreds of pages give you feedback or
you build a prototype that has some of the features to give you
feedback or you generate the test cases to test the SRS. What
are you looking for here? Four things: Validity: are all the
requirements necessary. Consistency: that’ s pretty bad. If the
requirements conflict, sounds like it would be hard to be
successful. Completeness: Is everything there and all the
restraints included? Finally, can it be implemented? You’ re
building this book about the project before you build the
project. That’ s requirements documentation. How about the cost
estimation? What the manager does is decompose the software
requirements specifications into tasks. You want to bind it a
little bit like points for use or storage you want to abound the
task between one and eight weeks if it’ s more than eight weeks,
that’ s too big a task; less than one week is hard to schedule.
Your manager’ s looking at the task, breaking up these pieces,
then giving the task estimates. You convert that into dollars,
via salaries and overhead. That’ s pretty straightforward. When
do you do this? You do it before you get the contract and then
after you get the contract. You’ d sure like those cost
estimates to be similar; what I did to get it and what is going
to cost the company to build it. One idea is you have a safety
margin. You, maybe you and your team work through a many weeks.
It’ s going to take to do these tasks and you multiply it by a
number like 1.3 or 1.5. Another idea is you make three
estimates. You make the best- case estimate, the expected case,
and the worst- case and after you look at all those estimates,
then you make your best guess. That’ s the cost model [
inaudible00: 05:11]. There’ s two kind of approaches to how to
do that and one’ s called experiential, which is basically based
on the program managers’ experience and maybe the company’ s
experience. This is what our guess is, how many weeks it will
take to do all these tasks. They were trying to make software
engineering like civil engineering again so they came with
quantitative approaches. The first [ inaudible00: 05:32] was
simply, “ Let’ s estimate the lines of code of each of these
tasks, calculate for the company the lines of code per person-
month and you divide them and you’ ll get how many person-
months it’ s going to take. The problem with that is his lines-
of- code is like… Bill Gates has a code about lines of code
being the wrong way to measure this stuff. That didn’ t work
very well. The researchers decided we’ re going to look… Measure
a bunch of projects. We’ re going to come with a better
quantitative model. They call it the Kokomo model, constructive
cost model. It’ s got two factors and an exponent. They looked
at a bunch of projects and here’ s the three significant digits.
I think the efforts go to be 2.942 to the lines of code size and
lines of code to this 1.23 penalty with the product factor of
1.07. You multiply that together, that will tell you how much
effort it is put that in your cost [ inaudible00: 06:21]. The
guys that came up with the Kokomo; that didn’ t work very well,
so they came up with Kokomo two and had 17 factors. The software
is getting more sophisticated over time. They are trying… We can
make this quantitative, I know if we just try hard enough. Not
surprisingly, survey says 92% of the time the customer just
relies on their experience to make this model. That’ s the cost
estimation. What about scheduling? What you’ re trying to figure
out is what tasks you can do in code and parallel and you may
have heard of PERT charts. Let me show you what a PERT chart is.
It’ s developed in the aerospace industry. He figured how long
it would take, how long it would take to build space shot. Each
of these nodes are milestones. These little rectangles, there’ s
11 milestones for the project and then these names that are on
these arcs say what’ s being done. This is requirements
elicitation. What these little numbers are on the arcs are how
much effort it is say in person- weeks, for example. Then the
arrowheads indicate dependencies. One of the reasons that people
made PERT charts is to figure out what’ s called the critical
path; is given all these arrowheads, what’ s the… the longest
time through this effort till we get to the final milestone. In
this example, here’ s the critical path so you just divide up
all the effort along those lines. Then that’ ll tell you, and
then some kind of productivity factor, and tell you how long it
would take to do the project. It could show you what things you
can do in parallel. If you’ re the project manager, you can do
the SRS to break it up in tasks; you get it in the cost and then
use those to create a schedule using something like PERT charts.
Now that you’ ve made a PERT chart, what you do all the projects
going? Now you want to compare what you predicted to how long
things are taking, so you track both the actual expenditures and
the time for those tasks against the PERT chart. What they found
is that by sharing these intermediate milestones; their 11
milestones on the slide; everybody is aware of whether you’ re
on budget or schedule or not; both the people building it, and
the customers. This is can you build it in time and on budget,
but you’ re not done as project manager. Does it actually do
what you want, what the customer asked for? This is called
requirements traceability, there’ s tools that are developed to
try to tie in all these pieces together, the software
requirements spec. What piece of the software requirements back
is associated with the piece of code that implements it, which
is associated with the test validates that? By having these
tools to keep those together, you can ask yourself, “ Did we
really implement everything the customer asked? Will let me go
in and test.” Is it passing that test? Well, good, because then,
it’ s handled that piece of the requirement. Are all the pieces
of the hundred- page document covered with tests and the
corresponding code in the SRS? If pieces of the code changes,
you want to go back and test that. To try and increase your
chances of hitting the target, there is borrowed from the
business school, is risk analysis management. Basically, are
trying to make this more accurate. You’ re trying to guess what
the risks are going to be before you do it. What you do if you
identify risk? You can do extra work to reduce the risk, do
extra work to repair yourself, or change your plan so that risk
goes away. A technical challenge; the relational database scale
won’ t be big enough. Maybe we could find a bigger machine with
a bigger relational database so we can make that risk away. Our
organization is an familiar with J2EE, which we have to use to
build that. What can we do to mitigate that risk? We could take
tutorials; online tutorials to get them better a J2EE so that
risk is mitigated. Oh boy, the business risk is, it’ s going to
be too late for the market. Maybe we should cut back features so
we can get it in the market in time, so that it will be viable.
If it’ s really bad, then we shouldn’ t do this at all. You can
imagine, you’ re guessing the risks, so what’ s the advice you
should do? Try and guess what the risks are. Make your best
guess of the chances of this risk happening and then on your own
10 point scale, give it a impact factor if this thing happens.
How bad it will be for the project? You multiply the chance
times the impact factor, you come with a number, you sort your
risk by that tack the top 20%, and you’ re hoping that that’ s
most of the risk. The risk analysis is trying to hit you on
schedule. These are all the things you need to do is the
manager. We put the side- by- side in table, which you may be
able to read. Here’ s the seven steps on the left: the
requirements documentation, elicitation, change management,
schedule, budget, ensuring requirements, features, scheduling
and monitoring. That’ s all that corresponds to user stories,
points, and velocity. User stories, points, and velocity, which
I just talked about, in the last couple of segments is
relatively intuitive. This is what that replaces for Agile. Then
the cost estimation is the kind of loosey- goosey thing we
talked about. Instead of trying to hit it and promising it , and
delivering features and doing extensive risk management to make
it more likely you say you’ re doing it on a best effort,
approach. That’ s the alternative universe here, that a lot of
people do use for lots of projects, and you may do yourself, if
it helps you to see what is different about Agile. Let’ s see
with going ahead. Which expression regarding plan and document
requirements and cost estimation is false? The closest to plan
and document scheduling and monitoring tasks are Agile points of
velocity. The closest to plan and document software requirements
spec document is agile user stories. Agile has no equivalent to
ensuring requirements such as traceability. Actually, they’ re
all true. None of them are false. I want you to pause over that
one. Let’ s get them. First vote up there, ready, set vote. Oh
yeah, lots of colors, so talk this one over. Let’ s try and vote
again. Ready, set voters pairs go. Wow, that converged, all
right, working magic. Let’ s go over them. The closest to plan
and document scheduling and monitoring are Agile points and
velocity. Yep. Agile is used in retrospective. What’ s the
experience of your team and assigning points and how fast you
use them to predict the future? Yep, as opposed to in advance,
making schedule. That’ s a big difference. The closest to the
software requirements spec in plan and document is Agile user
stories. Yes, those little tiny 3 x 5 cards are your written
documentation specs that you work with the customer and that’ s
opposed to 100- page book or hundreds of pages book and an IEEE
standard. Agile has no equivalent to ensuring requirements such
as traceability. Yes, that’ s what the BDD is. BDD gets the
requirements into user stories and we’ ll see shortly that we
can take those 3 x 5 cards and turn them into acceptance tests.
We’ re going directly from the customer get them writing cards,
what the features we want, implement them [ inaudible00: 13:43].
That’ s the acceptance test, where make sure those features are
there where it’ s not part of plan and documents, so they have
these traceability’ s tools to try and make sure you do that.
Actually four and three or faults, but that would have been kind
of clever. Questions about this? Questions? Good. All right, so
that’ s what this alternative order of the universe looks like.
When you guys make these comments, “ Oh, I know how software is
really built.” Okay, yeah, there’ s another way to build
software. This is in the only way. It’ s got positives and if I
was doing space shuttle stuff I’ d probably use the plan and
document with all that stuff, but not for a lot of things. Let’
s go ahead and will have time to do one more segment about
comments. This is again another thing about writing beautiful
code. What’ s interesting is two my good friends are Armando Fox
and John Ousterhout. John Ousterhout used to be a faculty member
here, one of the best programmers I’ ve ever met. He and Armando
just do not agree about comments in general Armando believes in
self- documenting code and Ousterhout thinks that’ s evil. Self-
document code is evil. Let me go over Ousterhout’ s advice and
we’ ll talk a little bit about where they agree, where they
agree. Examples of bad comments, which they both agree on this.
Here’ s a good useful comment. Add one to i. Well, thanks I’ m
glad you didn’ t not comment. Without that comment, I don’ t
know what I would have figured out, okay. Here’ s another one.
Lock against concurrent access. Spinlock detects. Yeah, that’ s…
Your writing down what it does. This function swaps panels void
swap panels, panel 1, panel 2. Great. Thank you for doing that.
What the idea is for good comments and Armando would agree these
comments aren’ t that good. What Ousterhout says what’ s missing
is the reason why you did it. What’ s the motivation? Don’ t
write comments about what it is. Put in the why. You can’ t
figure that out from the code, the why, that you did that. That
should be here. You want to the comments at a higher level, so
that if you change; when you change the code, which you
ultimately will have to do, it doesn’ t break the comments.
Here’ s an example. If we’ re going to be scanning an array to
see if the symbol exists, do it that way, rather than basic kind
of implement the code in comments. This is a much better
comment [ inaudible00: 16:12] doing it. What’ s tough about
comments is there is not lots of good examples. Open source has
terrible comments. If that’ s your example, it’ s rare that you
see good comments in this. In Ousterhout code, there’ s as many
comments as there are lines of code, there. That really helps
it. I think Armando agrees with the why part of this, that
writing down why is a good thing. He’ d like to believe with the
elegance of Ruby and good variable names and stuff like that.
The code can be understandable without the comments. He would
agree that you can’ t capture the why in there. One of the big
things about the legacy code when you’ re trying to figure out
what’ s going on is typically that there’ s no comments. They
may want to try and work on that. When I talked to my friend
Ousterhout, and I think he agrees with this point. What I really
love about this course is virtually every time we tell you a
good idea. There’ s a tool that implements that. Good idea. What
about ABC complexity? We got Flog for that. How about Cyclomatic
complexity? That’ s Seguro or Smells. Oh, that’ s Reek. Good
comments. We don’ t have a tool. The problem with that, if there
was a natural language understanding tool that would say this is
a pretty good comment, that would be useful. What I like about
the course is the advice we give you. You can follow and we can
see if you follow the advisors tool to do that. With comments,
somebody has to read through the code to see if you’ re writing
good comments and that’ s not a scalable, so he can make the
classes big students would like. Let me wrap this up. We started
off with giving advice on how to write beautiful code and SOFA:
short, do one thing, few arguments and consistent abstraction,
so you don’ t have smelly code here. These metrics will point to
areas of concern. They’ re not a foolproof guarantee but they
are good indicators. Big idea, behavior different design is the
user stories and Lo- Fi user interfaces to be able to work with
the customer right now to be able to figure what they want, and
you need to do that. How to make good ones; they need to be
specific, measurable, achievable, relevant, and timeboxed,
Trackers, this useful thing to be able to calculate progress.
This other universe has the project manager. They get good pay,
but there’ s a lot on the line to try and be successful. With
that, we’ ll see you next time.