Alright let's start with software as a service. So it's like you
know here's a laundry where you can rent laundry machines don't
have to have your own washer and dryer and you are going to just
rent them with the same thing's true do you wanna rent your
software than own it yourself so here's what traditionally
happens you get this binary you download on your device that has
to work with the right version of hardware and software. And and
that means developers have to take a long time to make sure that
the software runs with all kinds of combinations of operating
systems. And with hardware devices. Um so isn't there a better
way to do this where you only have to work on one platform and
if you could it'd be fewer release cycles no user upgrades and
that's what it gets called a software a service so the software
in the data gets deliberate over the Internet that something
program like the browser running on a client device. So you know
search social networking is examples of software as a service.
It's so popular now that even traditional software like
Microsoft office or turbo tax instead of buying software
installing it you can rent it you can use it um way and so
Armando and I think this is not just a fad that's gonna go way
we think this is a fundamental change that this is a revolution
in how software is being made in we're seeing the impact of that
this decade you read the newspaper lots of things are happening
today in Microsoft reorganising buying companies and stuff like
that and something we think this is fundamentally the shift from
software that you put on your shrink wrap software that's offers
a service that's gonna play out over this decade. So why's it so
popular I know installation worries is like user it's gonna work
you know we're not gonna have about different hardware
capability or you instal the wrong version. We don't have to
worry lose your cell phone the date is up in the cloud you
haven't lost your data if you're gonna have people working
together it's naturally to do in the cloud it's easy for them to
interact if the data is gigantic or changes all the time you
don't wanna have to send the data to all people it's in the
cloud is one copy it's easy to keep up to date for the software
developer. It's great there's only one copy of software it only
has to work on one set of hardware one operating system. So
there's no hassle for developers and then one of the benefits of
it is it's in the cloud before you bring in a new feature you
can try on a small fraction the users that's gonna be A B
testing you know one percent of them at time and finally there
is no upgrade so that the upgrades feel for the users they don't
have to it seems like every time I turn my computer I've gotta
give permission something to upgrade it and the that's a lot
simpler for the developers as well so they can control the
environment. So that's the reason for SaaS So what's a good
programming environment for SaaS there's a lot of them SaaS
apart there's lots and lots of languages but we use ruby on
rails which is called rails in short rails is a really popular
framework it's get used by Twitter for example but it's it's a
reason that it's so popular is got a really great programming
language in fact the inventor of rails picked ruby which is not
a very popular languages because of it's great features. So
rails a ruby is a modern scripting language it's both functional
and object oriented has of course automatic memory management it
has dynamic types it has reuse via mix-ins and closures and and
lots of programming to learn about that so why don't think ruby
on rails causes a lot to learn in this course but you only got
twelve weeks to learn it you get twelve weeks to learn them. But
either you're like you're taking four courses so you divide that
twelve weeks by four you got three weeks full time to learn all
the stuff or people working yeah you're taking the MOOC are
working full time so you only have a slim about time. So we want
very productive so there's a lot of things you learn in this
class we need to be used this productively and in is we wrote an
article about the so that's why we're gonna take some of the
time of the class to learn a new programming language new
framework as beating gonna get multiplied that the other reason
is that's but software engineering in software engineering is
lifelong learning so why but the people are taking MOOC are
taking this class because it's software can musically need
learning things just happen all the rest of your careers. So
we'll give you the chance to do that in this class students
class if you don't like learning things you think this is this a
a good field for you because it what's amazing about Morris law
is allows new things to happen all the time. Okay