Okay, cost estimation in Agile. Sounds like an oxymoron. In the
real world you need to estimate the cost before a customer's
going to agree on the project, but there's no careful planning
and scheduling in Agile unlike [ planning of 00:13] documents
like we'll talk about shortly. How can you estimate the cost? In
fact, that's exactly the question … Armando and I had written
versions of the book, we didn't have cost estimation in it, so
we said, " Hey, how do you guys do this?" This is the answer.
Pivotal Labs, they actually not only do they develop code they
help teach the customer how to develop code by teaching them
Agile. They never promise that we'll deliver these three
features by this date. They don’ t do that. What they do instead
is they're going to commit resources efficiently up until that
date, and they'll work with the customer to define the
priorities to see how things take. It's not a hitting a target
based on features in a time window, it's estimating how much
effort will be and then we'll see how it goes. Where do you
think you get the estimate from? What's the steps they go
through? First it starts off with a one- hour phone call. A
person, a company's interested in working with Pivotal Labs.
They call on the phone, and part of what they do on the phone is
explain how things are done. This is not a contract, this is not
outsourcing a contract of work to do. This is a joint effort
with you and us. You need to make the time commitment for [
inaudible 01:32] and it's after the phone call that goes okay,
they say, " Okay, why don't you come visit?" Then they have this
hour and a half session that's called a scoping session. What
they're doing is, is they are ... the customer has to bring
everybody associated who has some idea about the design, whether
it's design documents they have, developers and designers,
anything that can clarify what has to be done. Pivotal brings
two of their engineers, and they ask these questions. What
they're trying to identify is there anything about the project
that's going to be risky, risky in terms of the schedule, and
try and work that out. As soon as the customer leaves, the
engineers spend half an hour to try and make a guess of how long
this is going to take. If it's not ... it seems pretty solid,
the customer knows what they want, not much risk, then they
say, " Okay, 20 to 22 weeks." If there's a large uncertainty,
it'll have a bigger range. They say, " Well, we think it's going
to be somewhere between 18 and 26 weeks." Then what the manager
does, " Well, it's that many weeks, it's that many programmers,"
we multiply that out, add a small profit. It's time and
material. That's the Agile model. " We're going to make our best
effort based ... and this is how much it's going to cost.
This'll be our cost to you, so are you happy with that?" Okay,
so that's how Agile costing is done.