All right. Next step in Behavior Driven Design, how are going to
keep track of our projects. So this seems kind of an [ inaudible
00:00:12] Agile, this loosey goosey soft development within
formal teams and the Scrum teams and all that. How are we going
to plan this in Agile? How are we going to estimate time if
there's now plan and can we use User Stories? That seems like a
big problem and if we could use User Stories, what would be the
tool that we would use? So when measuring productivity, if we
try to use User Stories per week, the problem is ... that seems
right but the problem is some of them are much harder than
others. So if you got 1 hard User Story done versus 3 simple
ones, are you doing well or not? So what's the rocket science
solution to this? What we'll do is we'll just assign point to
each User Story. Okay. How about 1 for straight forward, 2 for
medium and 3 for complicated. All right. And that's the big idea
here instead of just counting User Stories we'll count points
and the team will make up the points per User Story. And what
velocity is which we've mentioned a few times since it's on the
slide is just the average number of points a team completes per
week. So the kind of the simple beauty of this system is you
come up with points for your team, you estimate your stories and
then your team figures out how many of your points you complete
per week and then given your historical average of how many of
the points that you assessed the User Stories you can guess how
much work ... how long it will take you to finish the rest of
the User Stories you want to do. So that's the big idea. So how
do you actually assign the points? So typically we start off
with 1, 2, 3, that's a good place to start, after [ inaudible
00:01:43] you might have 5 and even 8 so the Pivotal Labs people
which will code here, the Fibonacci Scale is what they use and
even Pivotal Labs, the companies been doing this for many years,
8 is extremely rare. How do you actually assign it? When you get
together your daily Scrum you talk about the User Story and
there it goes 1, 2, 3 and hold up fingers right? And then you
just average them, what they do. Is it 2 or 3 or stuff like
that. Now if 1 person says 2 which is kind of medium and one
person says 5 which is really hard, you don't just average
those, what you do is you stop and ... there's a disagreement
over here. This is one of the things we talked about. There's
some difference in assumptions, some difference in experience
that makes them think wow, this is going to be really easy and
this is going to be pretty hard. And so you want to talk this
out before you go [ inaudible 00:02:34]. Our advise is that if
anything is more than 5 you should divide the simpler stories.
You don't want this big monster on the backlog that nobody wants
to work on is going to take so long, so break it up into smaller
stories as you go ahead. And like I said, velocity is a self-
assessment. It helps you figure out how fast your team, the work
spends your points, it's like you're on currency and as long as
you're consistent overtime, it doesn't matter if you're doing 5
points per week or 10 points or if you want to feel better you
can make the points ... give yourself a lot of points. Really [
'pop wow' 00:03:08] we're doing 30 points a week. Yes, you can
feel ... go to the bar and brag it to your friends. But it's a
self- evaluation. As long as your consistent and it helps you
predict what you're doing and it gives you insight, that's what
you need to do. Now, once again, so this are pretty simple
ideas. But wouldn't it be great if we didn't have to calculate
this all by ourselves or wouldn't it be great if there was a
tool that helped ... that keeps track of the User Stories is. So
this company Pivotal Lab built this tool called Pivotal Tracker
and it's just beekeeping for User Stories, but as long as you're
doing the bookkeeping of how many User Stories you're finishing
and there's points associated with these User Story, we could
calculate your velocity for you and if you put in things like
when you want to release something we could guess how long
that's going to take. So this little bit difficult to see window
here what the Pivotal Tracker which is this ... Armando
mentioned it last time is this tool that runs on 1 database at
this lab that handles all the projects in the world, it's not
that heavy of load, it had the web browser inter- phase has
separate panels for each of the features of it. So 1 is the
current, that's this one in the middle. this is the User Stories
people are working on, it's a little hard ... it's very hard to
see but it's the little blue things are the number of points for
each of these stories that are being worked on. The other panels
there are ... there's the backlog panel which isn't shown,
there's an icebox which are User Stories that have been sitting
around, cold storage for a long time in case you get a back log.
And there's that things that are actually done, you actually
finished something, you can put them there. It shows the ... and
this team is ... this number right here in the corner is what
the velocity is for this team, so it's 10 points per iteration
that's being used. So this thing is really easy to us and I
think everybody who's tried it in the classes says has started
using it. And 1 of the ideas in here is within each of these
windows, these are in priority order, and what Pivotal Tracker
will actually do is take things out of your backlog since it
assumes it's in automatic order and as you finish the thing it
will pop in the next User Story that you're supposed to work on
because it's prioritized order. So that's Pivotal Tracker. I
think I said those things. How do you complete it? I guess I'll
talk about that. So it's completed [ inaudible 00:05:25] panel
and then you can even stick in release points, you think about
stuff or releases, so when all of these User Stories are done
that's I'll do a new release and you can calculate the time to
release by points. Something that they added since we started
this book is with what they call it Epic Panel and what an Epic
Panel is, is you put together a bunch of User Stories that are
related because together they find some important feature that
they might want. So they're independent of the backlog, so you
might also use Epics. What are the roles? So it's not up to the
developer to decide when it's done. You could imagine ... that
looks good enough to me, hit the botton. So they borrow from the
Scrum ideas of a product owner so in the Scrum, 1 of your team
members if the Scrum master and 1 of them is the product owner,
so the idea is before you can sign off, you say I think it's
done, the product owner takes a look at it and then if the
product owner thinks representing the perspective of the owner
thinks the story is done marks done, if not it rejects it and
sorry, it's not ready to go, here are the reasons you have to go
back and work on it. So it's not just up to the developer to do
them. Pivotal Tracker kind of like there's spikes and things
like that. They have 2 different things, features or User
Stories that provide business value to the customer. So let's
add, you have to get the consent, let's add the consent box on
the check out page so that you agree to that. So there's points
that's associated with it, values the customers, those are
features. There's also things called Chores which you can keep
track which is work for the team to do. So they are necessary
but they don't provide any obvious value to customer like find
out why the test suite is low. Okay. So there's no point
associated with that. Now to do this work as a team, you're
going to need besides tracking what's going on some space to
work and let me just talk about it here. So Pivotal Tracker does
allow you to attach documents so you use your stories, kind of
documents associated with them. You may know there's a wiki
associated with your [ inaudible 00:07:25], that's another place
for your team to work. We use Google Documents a lot, teams of
people developing either drawing or presentations, spreadsheets,
all that stuff, it's easy for the group to work on them and then
if you want to use chat rooms, open source 1 is called Camp Fire
where you can have [ inaudible 00:07:44] for your team. So these
things your team might want ti work on now that you're going to
start working with customers.