Okay, so, so far all of our TDD has been concentrated on the
controller, and we've sort of been putting off this idea that,
while the real work gets done in the model, we haven't actually
dealt with that yet, right? We've just faked it out everywhere
that we needed it. So now, let's do that. Kind of as a preview
to doing that, and you already saw sort of a taste of this in
the Oracle of Bacon homework, is, even if the real work is
occurring in the model, part of the real work is talking to an
external service, and as we know, in test suites, it's not
really appropriate to do that. So, one example that the book
develops to show how we're going to handle TDD for the model
method is this idea of explicit versus implicit requirements. We
already know that- we already laid out the explicit requirement
for what this hypothetical model method is supposed to do. It's
going to call this RubyGem, which in turn calls the TMDb
service. By the way, if we didn't have a RubyGem, what would we
be doing? Well, we'd be doing something a lot like what the
Oracle of Bacon homework was doing, right? We would have to
construct the correct type of URI, and get the response, and
parse it, and create a nice Ruby object. It's just, in this
particular example, the TMDb RubyGem does a lot of this for us.
So, that's the explicit requirement. But, the implicit
requirements come from things like, well, what if that doesn't
work? What are the reasons that that might go wrong? Two
specific cases are if you provide an API key that's not valid
for calling TMDb, or if you just don't provide the API key at
all, if you leave it blank. As the book describes, if you go
through this example, those are actually two different failure
modes, and you can imagine why, right? If the key is blank,
clearly that's wrong, because no legal key is ever blank. But if
the key is not blank, then you have no way of telling if it's
valid, unless you try to actually use it. So, the gem will
actually fail in two different ways for those two different
conditions, and this is a good motivation for how to group tests
using context and describe. Here's an example of blocking of the
tests. By the way, I should point out that describe and context
and fundamentally aliases for one another. They actually call
the same underlying method. So, why are there different words?
Because it helps you signal intent, right? Describe is saying, "
I'm describing a behavior generally, searching TMDb by keyword,"
but context lets you say, " These are different situations under
which this behavior might be triggered." One context is if I do
it with a valid key. A different context is if I do it with an
invalid key. By the way, within invalid keys, there's at least
two cases. There's the key not being given at all, so it's
blank, and there's the key being given but incorrect. Basically,
I'm grouping together chunks of tests, and the groupings are
sort of based on whether it's a collection of examples that are
testing related behaviors. Also, as the book explains, if you
have common preconditions that apply to all of the tests in a
group, like, they're all going to use the same stub, or there's
a mock that all of them are going to use, you can put a before
block that applies to a whole bunch of tests, so that you don't
have to repetitively repeat those preconditions in every single
example. So, where are we? The implicit requirements are derived
from the explicit ones, and in the example of TMDb, how do I
know that the gem fails in two different ways? Well, for one
thing, I read the documentation. It's a new concept. Most of
these are well documented. In fact, part of the documentation
for good RubyGems is their specs. By the way, if you're using a
gem, and you can't find the specs that go with it on the
download site, that's a sign that it's either poorly tested or
it's so out- of- date that the specs haven't been maintained.
You don't want that, right? You want libraries that are actively
curated and actively developed, and having a good set of specs
is actually a really good ecosystem indicator of if the gem is
trustworthy. You can also, as you design your classes and you
are experimenting with these pieces of code, you can actually
see how they work, and then you capture that behavior in a test.
We'll have a lot more to say about that when we take about
Legacy code. We use two different stubbing approaches in this
case. In one case, we know that TMDb gem will immediately throw
an error, so the only test we had to create there was, did we
catch the error and convert it to the right kind of exception,
so that the caller always sees an exception of the same class?
In the second case, we actually needed to prevent the gem from
contacting TMDb at all. Now, this is the case where, in the way
the example is developed in the book, and very similar, again,
to the Oracle of Bacon homework, we used FakeWeb to sort of stub
out the entire internet. So, the general question that this
leads to is, when you're testing pieces of software that work in
a service- oriented architecture, where should you stub?
Remember that you can sort of apply this either from the point
of view of, I'm writing tests that are going to reach out-
they're testing code that reaches out to an external service.
So, in that scenario, I am the client, and I want to write tests
that are going to talk to another server, but I need to be able
to stub out that server to keep the test fast and independent.
Another case, as we'll see when we talk about JavaScript
development, JavaScript runs in the client, and you often want
to be able to test it in isolation of the server code that it
depends on. So, the concepts here actually come up in many
different scenarios. Where do you stub? Well, we've already seen
that you can do things like stubbing methods directly in our
model classes, and I think the analogy that one of the students
just gave about a stub as a way of cutting off of a path, that's
exactly how we're going to think of it here. We're cutting off a
path, right? If we say " stub the movie," or " stub the [ fine-
end 0:05:10] TMDb method right in the movie class, in some
sense, we're cutting off the path at the earliest possible
opportunity, right? We're not even allowing the real method to
receive the call. We're just going to- everything below this
line is faked out. We're going to pretend all of this stuff
worked, and we're going to return a canned value. We could also
stub below the level of the gem. This says, look, we're going to
call our movie method, we're going to call the real thing, but
we know that our movie method is going to actually call
something that's in this gem, in this library, so that's where
we're going to stub. We're going to stub the gem instead. This
says, I'm happy to actually test my part of the code, but I want
to stub out the library. Going further than that, we could say,
ultimately, if the TMDb gem is going to call an external
service, it ultimately has to go through one of Ruby's class
libraries that allow you to do HTTP calls. So, we could just
stub that. We could stub the HTTP call, and make sure that the
correct URI is passed, and we could return the contents of the
page. This is the kind of thing that FakeWeb sort of does for
you. Then, if we're going to do that, what we really do is, we
can parse a contrived request. We can look at the real service,
we can do a couple of requests against it, we can capture
exactly what the output of those real requests was, and then we
can use those canned values for something like FakeWeb. This is
what the Oracle of Bacon homework does, and this is kind of the
standard practice when you're trying to code against a remote
service. You learn as much as you can about its API, about what
it returns, you ideally do some interactive tests on your own
using a command line tool like cURLto actually see what happens
when you stimulate it, and then you capture those results, and
you sort of freeze- dry them, and you use a gem like FakeWeb.
Another possibility, which we haven't done, but it's something
that you might do if you were the provider of the service in the
service- oriented architecture is, you could put up a
development version. For example, if you write an app that runs
against PayPal or against Stripe, which are services for
accepting people's money, right, pretty important function, both
of those services have a developer sandbox that behaves
identically from an API point of view to the real production
site, but, happily, it doesn't cause any actual money to change
hands. So, the idea is that you would do these other levels of
stubbing in your own application, and when you're ready to
really test it, there's one more level of qualification you can
do, which is test your full stack against their sandbox server,
which doesn't necessarily do real requests. Not every service
that's out there has a sandbox version of itself. In the case of
the Oracle of Bacon, it's hardly critical. But in the case of
things like payment services or authentication services, if
you're writing a Facebook app- Facebook has some test services
that you can use to test your app against. So, the idea of
stubbing at different levels is pretty pervasive. The rule of
thumb is that, if you're doing more unit testing, where you're
trying to cover a lot of special code paths in a small amount of
code, it's fine to stub nearby, because what you're aiming for
is isolation, right? You want to isolate the code being tested
from the side effects of all the other pieces, but as you move
kind of higher in the testing stack towards integration testing,
with integration testing, you're supposed to be removing more
and more training wheels, right? In those cases, you stub as far
away as you can, because the goal of the integration test is to
be close to reality. Sort of, what's the closest to reality you
can get without contacting a service? Well, it's to get sort of
all the way down here, where you're essentially stubbing out the
internet, and anything that goes wrong would be something that
is in the actual network interaction. So we can, once again,
enhance the things that we know how to do in tests. The book
example develops this in more detail, and I didn't have time to
cover the example in detail in lecture, but just like with stubs
and should receive, you can specify that a method should return
something. You can also specify that under certain circumstances
it should raise an exception, and if you put an action or a
lambda expression inside braces, it will allow you to test that
it raises an error. This is pretty important, because as you
probably figured out during the course of homeworks for this
class, if you have a test case that actually raises an
exception, the test is over, right? Raising an exception is an
instant failure. How do you actually test that something
correctly raises an exception, when that's the behavior you're
interested in? You can basically put the test case itself in
braces, which is just like a block, and that means that you're
creating a lambda expression that can execute, basically, in a
controlled environment, right? Our spec will execute it, and it
will rescue the exceptions, and make sure that the right ones
got raised. So, with that, we're ready to ask a question about
implicit versus explicit requirements. Which statements are true
regarding implicit requirements? That they're often but not
always derived from the explicit ones, that they apply to unit
and functional tests but they do not apply to integration tests,
they're a lower priority for testing because they didn't come
from the customer, or all of the above are true?