So, with that in mind, let's extend that example and say, now
we want to do this. We want to be able to write five Euros in
rupees, or in some other currency of our choice. So, as a
general approach, what would we want to do in order to make this
happen? One possibility is we could say, we could change numeric
method missing and we could detect calls to " in" and take a
look at the arguments. That would be one way. Or... So that's
numeric dot method missing. That's the class method. Or we could
change the instance method, numeric method missing, to do that
same thing. We could define a new method called " in," as an
instance method of numeric. By the way, by now you are getting
used to the notation that numeric dot method missing means
method missing as a class method. Numeric hash method missing
means it's an instance method. That's just Ruby notation, all
convention. Or we could define a class method numeric in. So,
which of these four is likely to be the most appropriate way to
handle this kind of example? Let's take a vote. Vote. Voting.
Finally I have a question that has caused some controversy. So
talk about this one for a minute. Okay. Let's try taking another
vote. Ready, everybody? Ready, and voting time. Voting time.
Okay, far from unan- red and blue have some support. Actually, I
think almost every choice has some level of support. So let's
see what's going on here. This is a good one to talk through.
This is a good one to talk through. Okay, so let's go through
these choices. First of all, just by the fact that when we
called five dot Euros, what kind of a method is Euros? Instance
or class? It's an instance method, right? We're calling it on an
instance of fixnum. And remember how we defined the method. All
it does is multiply the number by something, so what kind of
thing do we get back from the Euros method? Also a fixnum. Okay?
So, if we want to be able to call in rupees, for example, on the
results of this, " in" is also at some level going to have to be
an instance method. Right? That much we can agree on. So answers
that are defining any kind of a class method, probably are
barking up the wrong tree here. Okay, so it's not a class
method. Well, what about this? What about modifying the method
missing like we did before. That was defined as an instance
method, right? It gets called if an instance of the object is
unable to respond to something. So could we augment method
missing to handle calls to " in"? Yes, we could. Is it a good
idea? Not necessarily, right? Because in the previous example,
the motivation for things like doing currencies is it gives us a
general way to handle a lot of different method calls that
really all do the same thing. They're just multiplying something
by a number. So it's much more compact. Instead of defining
twenty methods for twenty different currencies, we just use
method missing to handle it in a much more compact way. But this
is a much simpler thing we're trying to do. We're just trying to
define one new method called " in" that is sent to a fixnum and
will cause the conversion to happen in ways that we haven't
determined yet. So defining an instance method called " in" is
the simplest solution to this problem. The method missing
solution would work, but it would be like killing ants with a
sledgehammer. You don't need metaprogramming to solve this
problem. This is just a plain old function call. So part of the
reason to have this exercise in here is, again, just because you
have these powerful mechanisms available doesn't mean you always
have to use them. In fact, you should do the simplest thing that
could possibly work. Remember, that's one of the mottos of
extreme programming. And in this case, a plain old instance
method will do absolutely fine. Any questions about that before
we move on?