TDD last time and we even got into a little bit of an example
and real soon you're going to be writing your test cases. So
we're going to get through most of the material today that is
really about the part about writing test cases that most people
don't learn when they first learn about testing, and because
they don't learn about these things, they come to think of
testing as this unpleasant, horrible thing to do, kind of a no-
win situation. We're going to talk about mocks and stubs, which
really when I really got comfortable with using them, sort of
the scales fell from my eyes in terms of how to do effective
testing. We're going to go back to the example that we've been
working on so far, where we were talking about this Controller
Method that was going to look up stuff in the remote database.
This is for out Rotten Potatoes app, and we had gotten as far as
looking at the two specs that said that it should call a method
in the model that's going to do the actual work. We got as far
as a spec that will make sure that we're choosing the right
template to render when this is done, and the last ... remember
we wrote down three things that this Controller Method had to
do. The third thing, which we haven't done yet, is if it gets
search results from the model method, it should make those
results available to the template. Now as a preview, we already
know that the way that we make stuff available to a template
from within a Controller Method is that we set instance
variables in the Controller Method and then those instance
variables can be used in the view. In order to do this one,
you're thinking, well, okay then what we really want to check,
because you're a step ahead of me, is we want to make sure that
assuming the model method returns the right thing, that we make
that information that came from the model correctly available to
the view and if you're thinking a step ahead of me, which I hope
you are, that means we've got to make sure that the Controller
Method is setting up instance variables, with values that can
then be picked up by the view. Now notice I said, assuming the
model method does the right thing. One of the things that we
said last time and that I'm going to keep repeating over and
over again because it's so important, is each test really is
there to test one thing. We already know that we're going to
have to do some tests for the model method separately, so for
now we‘ re stubbing out the behavior of the model, and we're
going to assume that it does the right thing. We're going to let
it do the right thing in a controlled way because we want to
focus on the Controller Method. So to test this idea that it
makes the results available to the template, we're going to look
at another addition to RSpec. Remember I said that RSpec is a
basic testing framework but it also comes with some plug- ins,
so that if you're specifically writing Rails apps, there are
some kinds of things you'd like to be able to test and RSpec
comes with additional macros or libraries that let you do that.
We're going to look at one called assigns, which basically
allows you to pass a symbol that names a controller instance
variable and returns what that variable would be if the view
tried to look at it. So basically assigns gives you the view's
idea of what some value of an instance variable is. Now of
course in our current code, we are doing such a simple test case
that we didn't even set up the instance variables yet. Let's
remind ourselves what this looked like. So this is the method
that we've been using so far. Remember this does the simplest
thing possible to make the specs pass that we've done up to this
point. We haven't yet done the spec to check that the Controller
Method is setting up an instance variable that the view can use.
In fact it's not setting up any instance variables at all, so
that's problematic. Again, let's go back to the idea of the code
we wish we had. Well, first of all, what would the instance
variable look like? We said assuming the model method does its
job and returns the right thing, well what would the right thing
be in terms of the happy path? Presumably it would be a list of
something that looks like a list of movie objects, right?
Because we already have a class to represent what movies are, so
here's an example of what we might want the code to look like.
So let's see what's going on here. I'm setting up some fake
results and what's a mock? A mock is an object that pretends to
be of this class. In other words if you ask it, " What are you?"
It'll say " I'm a movie," but it doesn't actually have any
behaviors. It's like a stupid stunt double that can only do a
specific, small repertoire of tasks because it can't do what the
real actor does. So, by the way, no diss on stunt doubles; they
do amazing work, just saying. So what am I doing here? I'm
basically creating the results that I think would come back from
the movie method if it existed and now I'm going to stub the
class method find_ in_ tmdb and return these fake results. So
what am I doing? Again, I'm setting up conditions so that under
the controlled environment of the test, this movie method, which
we haven't yet written, can return a canned result that's
consistent with it working properly because that isn't the thing
that we're testing. We need that information to do the thing
we're really testing, which is what we're looking for now,
right? Now we're going to go ahead and post, to trigger the
Controller Method, we already saw this in the previous test. So
this is going to cause the controller action to run. Only now
what we're looking at is to see if the view tried to dereference
an instance variable called movies, we would like it to get the
value that we set up as the movie stub. Think of the flow that's
going on here. We're going to call the Controller Method,
Controller Method is going to call the model method, which
doesn't exist, but that's okay because we have stubbed it.
What's the stub going to return? It's going to return these fake
results. So we have completely faked out the behavior that's not
essential to this test because what we really want to check is
given this result comes back, can we make it available to the
view. That's what assigns does. It gives us the view's idea of
what the instance variable will be set to and that's how we fake
out the parts of the test that we didn't want to control. So
this really ... now we have a couple of different concepts about
seams. Remember we said a seam is in place where you can change
the behavior of your program without changing the source code in
that place, and it's particularly useful for testing because
that's exactly what we're trying to do, right? We're trying to,
in a controlled way, exercise little bits of the program without
making changes to the other parts of the program on which they
depend. In that example we saw two different kinds of seams. We
saw a stub, which is similar to what we saw last time. Last time
we saw should_ receive which said, should_ receive means if I
don't get a method call on this object, then that was an error,
that should have happened. Stub is a little bit looser. It says,
you might get a method call on this object and if you do, here's
what instructions you should follow, but it doesn't cause an
error for there not to be one. A mock is a stunt double of an
object and you often use it for behavior verification. In other
words, in this case, we want to verify the behavior of this
other thing. It needs a movie or a list of movie results to
interact with, but we don't want to go to the effort necessarily
of creating the real movie objects because we're not actually
going to do anything to them, right? In this limited case, the
only thing the movie objects are going to do is play the role of
a result that we're returning in a canned manner. Having said
that, we can for example, stub individual methods on it. For
example, suppose we were testing a controller action where we
know that when a movie result, let's say comes back from a movie
model, it's going to take a look at the title attribute, for
instance. In that case, we can do something like this, where
we're creating a mock or a double of a movie object and we're
saying if anybody calls the title method on you, just return
this. Again it's sort of ... you can can a very small number of
behaviors so that you can use the object in very limited
circumstances. If you look at the documentation for the latest
RSpec, which I think is 2.14, they are now deprecating the terms
stub and mock, in favor of a single term, double, and the idea
is that it's called a test double like a stunt double. It's a
stand- in that's not really the real object, but can do part of
the job of the real object in a test. As it turns out,
internally the way that stubs and mocks are implemented are
similar enough, that it makes sense to use a single term.
However, I will personally tell you that I find it useful to
mentally keep a difference between the two things. A mock plays
a role of like, look we need an object, we need a warm body to
stand in and it needs to be able to do one or two specific
things. A stub is more like, this method might be called and
since we don't want to deal with having the real method interact
here, we'll provide a canned response. So the semantics are
subtly different. One of them is more of a convenience of like
ignore the rest of the app. The other one is more, I'm going to
set up some expectations because I need for this object to do a
certain number of things. In each case though, the idea that the
seam enables just enough functionality to pass the specific
behavior in that one test. So let's kind of put these things
together, looking at both this spec and the two that we looked
at last time. If we think of what does it mean to write a good
spec or a good test case? Well first of all, it should test just
one behavior and that's really extreme right? Even in our simple
controller method we saw that calling the model method, passing
the right thing to the model method and making the right thing
available from the result of the model method, that's actually
three different behaviors and we wrote three different specs for
them. Figure out what seams you're going to need to isolate the
behaviors you want to test from other behaviors that they rely
on, but that aren't part of the test and therefore what kinds of
expectations are appropriate to use. You could use stubs if
you're not sure about the number of times something would be
called and if the fact that you're calling it is not necessarily
as central to the test. You could use expectations like should
receive if you want to set up a method and make sure that it
actually gets called or should not receive if you want to make
sure that something doesn't get called. For example, you might
be testing that if the customer didn't agree to the terms of
sale the charge my credit card method should not be called.
That's a perfect legitimate code path. Once you've set up your
before conditions, you've set up your seams, make sure that your
test fails for the correct reason. In other words, the reason
you want it to fail is you have correctly expressed what the
code ought to do but you haven't written the code yet. That's
the reason for the failure as opposed to it fails because of a
syntax error or you misspelled the name of a variable or you
stubbed the wrong thing, or you didn't realize there was
something that the method expects to call and you didn't stub it
and now bad things happen. Given that it fails for the right
reason now you're on to the easy part, right? Writing code in
case you haven't figured this out yet is actually the easy part.
Determining what code to write and how to test it and where the
boundaries ought to be, that's actually the harder part. So this
is kind of a way of making sure that you structure the hard part
of it first and once you've got a good failing test and as we'll
see fixing bugs is really similar, right? The hard thing about
fixing a bug is finding it and reproducing it. If you can do
that in a test, once you've done that back- filling the code to
fix it is a lot easier. Once you've got the test to pass, you
look for opportunities to refactor your code, look for places to
make it beautiful. Just like writing. Once you've got your rough
draft down, it doesn't mean you're done; it means you sort of
understand what your intentions were and now you can actually go
back and make it pretty. We can add to the catalogue of test
techniques we've seen. We already saw should receive, we saw
that you can optionally tell should receive what it should get,
what arguments and you can also optionally tell it what to
return if that matters in your test case. We've also now seen
that you can do stubs and just like should receive, you can stub
something and specify what it returns. Now you might ask could
you call stub and say with just like you can do with should
receive. Well syntactically you can do it but the question is
whether it makes any sense. Because the whole point of a stub is
you're communicating the intent that this is not central to the
functionality I'm testing, whereas with should receive, part of
the central functionality is I want to make sure this method
actually gets called so in that case you might imagine that you
also want to make sure it gets called with the correct
arguments. So you could stub something with arguments but the
fact that you're stubbing it already says I don't actually care
that much if it gets called. It's kind of there just in case.
You can also create mocks, which are doubles of an object. They
will behave like the class you say they are. That's what they'll
claim to be, but if you try to actually call any of the class
methods on them, they'll throw up their hands in despair and
they won't know what to do. They're really, really dumb objects
and you can stub one at a time specific methods on them. In a
moment we'll answer the question of what happens if you're
stubbing so many methods that it turns out you ought to just be
using a real object. We looked at the assigns which is another
one of the matchers that RSpec provides that is specific to
Rails which basically says tell me what the view would get of it
tried to dereference this instance variable. And usually it's
used when you want to make sure that a controller action
correctly set up the value of some instance variable that the
view is then going to render. So here is a question: should
receive combines a something and a something whereas stub is
only a something? You can read while I have a drink.