Moving right along. One of the things that we're changing this
time around in the class is we're going to introduce the idea of
testing much, much earlier and we're going to introduce the tool
that we're going to use for a lot of our testing called Rspec.
It actually is a descendant of some ideas that come from the
Java community. Here's a very smart gentleman who says, "
Debugging is twice as hard as writing code in the first place.
Therefore, if you write the code as cleverly as you can, by
definition, you're not smart enough to debug your own code."
Very smart man. In case, people don't recognize him, he's a
Turing Award winner, Brian Kernighan is the co- inventor of the
C language. You might have heard of it. It's one of the
languages named after famous letters of the alphabet. There's
another very smart gentleman who is influential in the history
of programming languages. This is Edgar Dijkstra who won the
Turing Award for his work on the importance of structured
programming. He's the author of a very famous missive called, "
Go To Statement Considered Harmful from Back in the Elder Days,"
and he says that, " Testing can never demonstrate the something
of errors in software, only their something else." Anybody know
what the blanks are? Absences and presence. Testing can
demonstrate that you've got bugs, but it cannot demonstrate that
you are free of bugs. I think an even more pragmatic version of
this that if you ... Any of you have ever visited a Google
campus, you may have seen this. Debugging sucks, Testing rocks.
After three years of doing it myself, I could not agree more. My
goal by the end of this class is you will love testing. You will
love big brother. I mean, testing. You'll love it so much ...
You'll love it so much that just like you get that little
dopamine surge when you get a Facebook message or a text, you
will get a little dopamine surge when you see a test go from
failing to passing. Believe it. In fact, as recently as 2010.
There were surveys done that showed that a big problem with
problems in finding major bugs in software didn't have to do
with the quality of the code, but it had to do with the problems
about the testing process. The way that testing was instituted
in the organization. My other goal is to make sure that when you
come out of this class, you have none of these bad habits and
that your habits about testing reflect best practices now.
Testing is way more fun that it used to be. What is testing like
today? Well, we could start with what it used to be like.
Before, when developers had finished the code, they throw it
over the wall to the QA Department and then the QA staff will
sort of manually exercise the software, they would poke at it
and then after awhile, they would sign off, looks good, then it
would ship and there'd be a ton of bugs. Today, it's quite
different. First of all, testing is part of every iteration.
You're always testing. In fact, you actually will start out
thinking before you write your code, you're thinking already
about how could I test this as I write it. You test your own
code, developers test their own code. There's a lot of
automation. The idea that testing is manual is almost obsolete.
There's extremely few cases where you cannot automate some test
that you would normally have performed manually and this is a
very big insight that saves you a lot of grief. Does that mean
that there's no role for a QA group or a testing group? There
absolutely is a role, but they don't write tests. That's not
what they do. They're like consultants who help you make your
code more testable and who improve the tools and the processes
of the company wide around testing. There's kind of a famous
figure that several years ago was floating around that Microsoft
said that for every test ... For every developer they had one
testing. There was a one to one ratio between developers and
testers and around last year, I asked some colleagues at Google,
what is that ratio at Google? How many testers per developer do
you have and they said, " It's about for every 10 developers
maybe, we've got one tester." Jaw drops to floor. Google, you
know, the home of reliable code that powers hundreds of millions
of people's web activities. It turns out that the testing
engineers at Google don't write tests. That's the job of the
people who write the code. The testing engineers make the
testing environment better. It's a really different view on
division of labor and the message is that software quality now
is not just the result of one specific group saying we're the QA
group. It's the process. The process has to involve developers
in the very beginning. The big picture of how we're going to do
testing is BDD and TDD which is Behavior- driven design, Test-
driven development. They actually are quite parallel to each
other. Behavior- driven design says you sit down with the user
and you develop stories and we're going to call those the
features you wish you had. That's how you wish the app would
work but you haven't written that code yet. As we'll see, using
the tool called Cucumber, those stories actually become runnable
acceptance tests for your app. Remarkable. Now, once you've got
a story for the feature you wish you had. The next thing you do
is you think about okay, how do I write the code to implement
that feature and the way I do that is I've specified in my user
stories the steps that my app has to go through to implement
that feature and for each one of those steps, I'm going to write
tests for the code that I wish I had. I'm going from a feature I
wish I had to the code I wish I had. What does this look like?
Well, we start out with a Cucumber user story in which the very
first step of the story immediately fails, because it's asking
to exercise functionality that by definition doesn't exist. As
we start to think about that functionality, we think how we're
going to write the code. We start by writing tests for the code
before we have the code. Of course, the test fails. It would be
really cool if the test pass without having the code there. Our
lives would be much easier. But that doesn't happen. We have to
work on creating the code until that test passes. It goes from
red to green. Once we've done that, with some point, we've
implemented enough code that that entire step of the story is
now green and passing. Now we go to the second step of the story
and that's how we do it. We do this loop several times until
we've implemented the entire feature and then we check it off
and we deliver it to the customer.