This is like a science fiction to me. We have these 3- by- 5
cards. How come we can't take these 3- by- 5 cards and turn them
into acceptance test because this is what the user asked for?
The user said, " This is what I want and if you'll just do that,
that'll me happy," so you could reach around that. How are you
going to do that? These things are in English, right? How are
you going to turn that? We don't have natural language
understanding systems yet, so this seems impossible. Then, even
if you could do that, don't you have to have a person sitting
there pushing the buttons every time to test your user
interface? This is what Cucumber is about, is going from this
customer- friendly acceptance test users stories to get both
acceptance test and integration test out of them if you remember
that from before. It does this by going halfway in between, so
it's still not code. It's kind of English so that the customer
can understand it yet it's not completely freeform, so the
computer can understand that as well. This is what a user story
looks like in Cucumber. The first thing is called a feature.
This is basically what the user story is, so a user can manually
add a movie. What you have then is one or more scenarios for
each of these user stories or features ... one of the features,
and then this is the stylized form of English but still kind of
understandable, given I am on the Rotten Potatoes home page,
when I follow " Add a New Movie," then I should be on the "
Create New Movie" page, when I fill in " Title" with " Men In
Black" then I select " PG- 13" from " Rating" and press " Save
Changes" then I should be on the Rotten Potatoes page, and I
should see a " Men In Black." These are three to eight; these
are called steps. We have a feature which is user story. We have
multiple scenarios, typically at least one per feature and
there's steps per scenario. Okay, I think I just said that. Now,
where do you put this information away? These are keywords: "
Feature" and " Scenario" and you keep them in a . features file
within the rails framework. Now what we need to is take these
steps that we've defined or we've written. These steps that
we've written out with these given and when words, then words
like that and we have to map them onto the Ruby code that does
the testing. These will be in . rb files so we have . feature
files and . rb files and we'll have some controller name.
These " given" steps mean that's the preconditions, the state of
the world before you start this story. The " when" steps are the
actions; somehow we're going to know how to push ... make the
browser push those browser buttons, and then the " then" steps
are the consequences, what happens after you do it. Then to make
it more readable, there are also conjunctions in there. You can
have and and but, so you can have given and this and this and
this, then and a couple of conditions afterwards. Now the magic
between the steps and the step definitions is you use regular
expressions, so we're going to write good old regular
expressions as we talked about earlier. They're going to match
those English phrases to map them onto the testing code written
in Ruby, so remember the " given." I am on the Rotten Potatoes
home page. There is our regular expression. It's going to match
this and it's going to do that captured string, right? The
captured string is over here in parenthesis and it's going to
remember the Rotten Potatoes home page, which we'll probably use
in the step definitions. To use this, as it says in the book,
you need to install it. Like everything else you install it as a
Cucumber gem. It's going to create for you this kind of
remember. How is rails so productive? It creates a bunch of
things so you don't have to do them. It will create some
commonly used step definitions when you install it. Armando
talked before about having test in production and development.
You need a test database to be working with that, and then
you're going to edit these . feature files to add features. What
about this other part of the question? Who we going to get to
push the buttons? That is a tool called Capybara. Capybara,
probably nobody in the class knows but Armando, is the world's
biggest rat. It's the size of a dog, and that's because the
prior tool was called WebRAT, so this was even better. This is
big rat, Capybara. It interacts with the app to receive pages
and parts of the HTML and submits the form, just the things that
we were talking about, right? We're talking about forms.