A related concept to software as a service it is service
oriented architecture. So sometimes in computer science people
make up a term that's really hard to understand. And or so
general that applies to everything and so people don't use it.
So service oriented architecture is almost so general that it
almost died it actually has a us a good meaning it's not
everything isn't service oriented architectures so kinda
question is here is there a way that you can design software so
they can recombine all independent modules and create new
applications out of it without doing a lot of programming that's
kind of question and service oriented architectures that idea
all components are designed to be independent services like you
go over the internet to access them, that's the idea of service
oriented architecture. So what this means that everyone sits on
services if you went over the internet access it's easy to get
and replace one right one of them's replaceable very easily it's
not going to bring down service. And also recover mistakes in
design throw things out in our put them back together it's much
more flexible. So Armando I had to come up with the the name for
the thing that's not service oriented architecture we think it's
a software silo So it's monolithic it's behind a counterweight
traditional do it there's no APIs that are visible everything's
internal and it's kind of the normal way to do it we would use
this you know a grain silo as the arc. So we had a hard time
trying to explain this and then this thing happen while writing
the book that was fortuitous so if you work at companies there's
often inside a company there will be well- known people who
write a lot of email flame on about how companies so screwed up
we gotta do this because you know we're dummies right well there
was a guy Google who used to be an amazonian value working
Amazon he come the Google successful for while we had to blogs
he has internal Google blogger he'd flame about everything that
screwed up about Google and then he had his public library say
how wonderful Google is right in our last one day probably
because he was multitasking is probably you know playing with
his phone that when he posted his Google flame instead of the
Google blog he went to public one the public one that probably
said nice things about Google that day. So Armando saw it, he
figured it was in going to be up for very long, he grab it and
say so that's what the the next slide gonna be and it is the
best. It's the best description of sovereign servers that we've
seen and so what the person said supposedly only in think he
thinking internally to Google it was talking about Jeff Bezos
the founder and C. E. O. of Amazon and he, the company was about
seven years old time he's in there and they've been using kinda
monolithic software and so you come to work Monday morning it is
email from Bezos in its there seven points here, six of them he
really said one this guy added so I'll tell you which ones
you'll the pre Mailer says all teams will henceforth expose
their data in functionality through service interface teams must
communicate with each other through these interfaces there will
be no other forms of media so he didn't want to leave any holes
here. You gotta do that no direct linking directories on the
team data store no shared model no back doors the only
communication is logged via server's interface never by the way
Bezos as a computer science degree from Princeton,he got a
Bachelors degree so he knew some technical things and you know
so these the first leaving to use he didn't really care what A.
P. I. Just gotta dude you gotta you know pick your own way of
doing sockets RPC really wanna do but it's gotta be and and
network like interface service interface without exception must
be design from the ground up to be externalise that is to say
the team must plan design to be able to expose interfaces
developers to the outside world. No exceptions okay well he's
the CEO company you're a software engineer get the best job in
the world why do I really have to do what Bezos says right well
the next line clarified that anyone who doesn't do this would be
fired so that's relatively clear and then the seven point was
thank you have a nice day Bezos wouldn't have said the said the
last thing you still at the end of the email was if you don't do
this you'll be fired right so that's how we got the attention of
the software engineers. And Amazon and they did transform you
know pretty successful company that was using monolithic
software to be using a service oriented architecture the same
thing interestingly happened at Facebook it doesn't have quite a
dramatic story here but three years they'd have mallets offer
three years into it. They decided to go ahead and go to a
service oriented architecture and if you were using Facebook at
the time Reading the New York Times on your on your computer and
suddenly there's some notice that other your friends are also
reading that same article then you then what they did that by
what was called the Facebook platform. So to make this clearer
let's give an example suppose we do bookstore we'll show silo
and service oriented architecture version so in this particular
example and yeah works. So we have three databases reviews users
in orders and so then we have these different services review
subsystem has to talk to use in users user profiles just users
the buying some system is that orders and users. So you build
this thing is a monolithic interface internal polling and stuff
like that you provide the single interface the outside the book
store service people use it so that's a monolithic approach the
service oriented approach has a lot of the same components but
these are now services so user reviews the review service has
editor and user reviews user profile are buying service and you
can combine those together to get the books or service just like
we had before so that's a bit more overhead paid network
overhead of providing service but it works. Well what's nice
about this we could easily add credit card processing that maybe
wasn't there before you get that server similar self implement
any trade a brand new servers favourite books that you just use
these two pieces to create and tie them into a social networking
and then you could your friends, book sellers. So that's the
idea of service oriented architecture