Alright, let's do another [ fear question. A big
difference . .. which statement is true? A big different between
agile and plan and document is that agile does not use
requirements . A big different between agile and plan and
document is measuring progress against a plan. You can build
softwares and service apps using agile but not with plan and
document . A big different between agile and plan and document
is building prototypes and interacting with customers during the
process . Why don't you take a few seconds here . Ready, set ,
vote. How many  people should have . .. how many people have
cards? That one we could talk over . Let's talk that one over. I
think blue and green are the two ones . Let's talk this over for
a minute then we'll vote together.  That's a minute,  let's
vote again . Let's see if . .. ready , set, vote . Alright, I
think it's greener . Let's see. A big different between agile
and plan and document is agile does not use requirements .
There's this thing called user stories . Those are basically
requirements. It's an informal requirement to [ inquirement
00:01:06] , that's not the right answer. You can build saas
applicants using agile but not with plan and document. No, you
could do saas with plan and document . It changes frequently, it
might be expensive but you could do it that way. These are the
last two . A big different between Agile and plan and document
is building prototypes and interacting with customers during the
process. No , that happens in spiral, right ? Spiral and [rap
00:01:28 ] does meet with them they just meet with them a lot
less frequently. The difference is the speed of interaction. The
right answer here is the second one , the green one. A big
different between agile and plan and document is measuring
progress against a plan . There's really not a plan in Agile
that you are measuring progress against. You're interacting with
the customer and making progress that way.