Now, let's talk about Agile. One question is, what plan and
document was embedded to try make a Software Engineering is
dependable to Civil Engineering? How well does it work? There's
a lot of [ inaudible00: 00:16], but how well does it work? It
requires this extensive documentation, planning, and depends on
this experienced manager, and he or she gets the credit or blame
for the project. What's the alternative model? Can we build it
without a strong program manager, without all this
documentation? If we do, how do we avoid of just being hacking?
Now, what happened before 1970, where people just get together
and start coding? Would it be great if you could just start
coding, and that's the best way to build it? I don't want to
spend time planning. I want to start hacking right now. That was
the best way. We already knew that was a bad way. Well, what's
the alternative that's not documentation, programmer, managers
strong that works? You remember from last time, these four
projects of [ Emfemee 00:01:02] that we mentioned. Well, there's
another 27 of them and collectively in this article from 2005,
they lost 17 billion dollars, and they're using " Plan- and-
Document". These aren't projects from the 1960s, right? People
are using these projects, so there's things going wrong. In
fact, I found three surveys that these pie charts represent of
saying, " How much were on- time on a budget?" Let me go through
them. This one in 1995 said, " One- sixth, basically, were on-
time, and on- budget. Half of them were late or over budget. A
third of them were just cancelled or abandoned. It just so bad
like, the FBI focus." It's like we're just given up. How bad
were their over budget? They are over budget by a factor of
three. I over budget or late by factor three. I think it will
take six months. No. 18 months. That was one survey. The second
survey of projects was saying only one- eighth were on time and
on budget, but that's actually an optimistic view. Because about
half of these projects- they're about a thousand projects- half
of them were simply some minor enhancements to legacy or just
data conversion. About half of them were new development
projects. Only three out of 500 new become a project, so we were
probably thinking of we're on time and on budget, so that's 1%.
In this last survey of very large project. This is 2004. People
start using some processes that worked a little better, but
still only 10% on time and on budget. 20% or at least 35% would,
and the rest of these had major delays or cancelled. All right.
That sounds like this stuff isn't working very well. One of my
favorite quotes is Shimon Peres, which is not somebody has
quoted everyday in computer science classes here. Is, " If a
problem has no solution, it may not be a problem, but a fact,
not to be solved, but to be coped with overtime." So, maybe this
planning thing it leads the problems that ... or change is
what's causing the problem. We have to cope with it. A dozen
years ago, a group people frustrated by these development
processes, got together, ad they went to a retreat, by the
mountain, retreat, and came back with word- for- word, what's on
the next slide, what they call the " Agile Manifesto." Here's
what they wrote: " We are uncovering better ways of developing
software by doing it and helping others to do it. Through this
work we have come to value this group." Individuals and
interactions over processes and tools. Working software over
comprehensive documentation. That's a direct job at the plan of
document processes. Customer collaboration over contract
negotiations. So rather than you sit down there, you come up
with the plan, you will the contract, and you make the contract.
Let's work with the customer to make the customer happy.,
responding to change over following a plan. A big part of a, "
Hey! To make this dependable as building a bridge, we have to
have a plan and stick to it." " No, let's not ... Let's respond
the change rather than stick to plan." That is, while there is
value in the items on the right, we value the items on the left
more. So this is a dozen years ago. They wrote this kind of [
inaudible 00:04:14] graffiti on the side of the plan and
document building, and said, " We're going to do it
differently." Okay. That was a proponent of this. He has a
version of Agile which she calls, " Extreme Programming" or "
XP." So what did he say? He said, basically if things are good,
let's do it more extreme. If short iterations are good, then
make them as short as possible, let's you do days or weeks, not
months or years. If simplicity is good, then always do the
simplest thing will work. Don't anticipate complexity. Just do
the minimum thing you have to do to get that. If testing is
good, let's test all the time. In fact, let's write the test
before we write any code. You're not going to be able to write
code without test. Finally, if code reviews are good, let's do
code reviews all the time, by programming in pairs, and
constantly looking over the shoulders. This was a big change
from the methodology. In fact, Agile embraces change as a fact
of life. It does continuous improvement versus these phases,
like we saw on the Waterfall model. The basic idea is developers
are continuously refining a working, but incomplete prototype,
until the customers happy. You meet with the customer every week
of two, so there's continual loop of working with the customer.
Then, Agile emphasize what's called " Test- Driven Development."
This is where you write the test before you write the code, and
we'll talk about that. We do use our stories, and we'll talk
about that in a couple of lectures. Basically, you cooperate in
an informal manner with the customer to see how you're going to
use the software. Velocity is the way we're going to measure
progress. Predict performance by how you've done in the past.
Here is the Agile flow chart that's from the book. The book is
in two parts. Part one is about software as a service. Part two
is all about Agile. We start off talking with the customer.
Behavior- driven design, and use stories. That's getting at a
high level of design, then the implementation, test- driven
development. We measure progress with velocity. We deploy to
the ... the customer takes a look at it, talk to the customer
again. So you're going to go around this loop four times in this
class for the projects. Now, what about Legacy? The number one
requirement from those half dozen leading software companies.
Well, we're going to do a Legacy assignment. It turns out that
the same methodology works for Legacy, and then design patterns,
architectures. Another important software gave me idea, and
we'll cover that. That's what was going on is kind of the
context about Agile what it is. What was the reaction, the
Agile, when it came out a dozen year ago? It got a strong
allergic reaction intelligence of the software engineering
community. Here's one quote. This is what somebody publishing.
What do they say behind close doors, I don't know, but this is
what they wrote on papers, in magazines. " Agile is yet another
attempt to undermine the discipline of software engineering. It
is nothing more than attempt to legitimize hacker behavior." Not
only that people write articles. People wrote whole books about
it. There's a 400- page book that came in 2001 and 2002, that
says Agile's a bad idea. 400 pages are giving the answer. It got
people's attention. What about today? Today, it worked. It's an
accepted practice. We looked at a survey of 66 software
engineering projects, and most of them use Agile. Even though
they were doing it in distributed environment. One of the text
books to this area actually, and now only covers Agile early now
came up with the set of questions that say, " When we should use
Agile," whether it's a good idea or not. Basically, a yes means,
use, plan, and document, and I know it's Agile. Do you have to
do a specification? Are there no customers? Is it going to be
really large? Is it going to be complicated real- time? Is it
going to have along product lifeline? Are you using lousy tools?
Somehow, if you use lousy tools ... You need good tools go for
Agile development. Is the project team geographically
distributed? Is it part of a culture that is document- oriented,
maybe at a civil engineering from or something? Are the team bad
programmers? If you have bad programmers, you blame and
document. Is it subject to regulation? It has to follow the
certain laws that apply. Basically, if you think about what
we're teaching, the answer is almost always no. Virtually, none
of these questions forwards the answer, " Yes," which is why
we're going to emphasize Agile in this course.