So what have we learned from this sort of quick tour of SaaS
architecture. I like stepping back to look at the big picture
frequently, especially with my eyes going bad with my advanced
age, but the big picture in this case is model- view-
controller, right, and this is the way we are structuring our
apps. It is not necessarily the way to structure all the SaaS
apps, but it is the way that Rails has chosen to target because
it applies to a large number of apps so all of the designed
choices in the Rails very heavily favor this. If you try to
write an app using Rails and it does not really follow MVC you
are going to find yourself fighting many of the things Rails
ties to do, and if you are working against framework, it is a
sign that you are using the wrong framework, right. Your app
really should be using something else. So specifically in our
case we are going to use databases to store the data and very
shortly we are going to talk about migrations, which is how we
manage the structure, the scheme of those databases. We have a
notion of CRUD operations and in the active record model used by
Rails, the CRUD operations are part and parcel of each type of
model. For the controller we know that we use HTTP to
communicate with it. URIs ideally RESTful ones that encode a
resource and the thing that we want to do to that resource, that
is how we specify what is to be done. All of that occurs over
the vulnerable TCP/ IP protocols and for the views we use HTML
and CSS as the was we present step to the user, but we can use a
templating system like HAML or ERB to combine fix markup with
step that comes out of the controller, and you will see an
introduction in one of the upcoming homeworks to XML and XPath,
when you are not presenting HTML design for human consumption,
you may very well be presenting XML design for machine
consumption, and there are a number of really great tools that
have evolved to allow you to write applications that both
generate and consume XML that would come for example from
another service in a service oriented architecture. Around 2008,
there was a meme going around, and the meme basically was Rails
does not scale. You cannot use Rails to build big application.
Based on what you have seeing so far, you should realize that
this is a content- free assertion, okay. Scalability is not a
property of a framework. Scalability is an architectural
concern. It speaks to, as you increase the number of users, what
does it cost to increase the application’ s capacity so that you
do not incur a higher cost for each one of those users. You can
continue to serve the model with good performance and the cost
per user to do so, does not go up roughly speaking. Now we saw
that one of the choices that was made in the design of the HTTP
protocol was to keep it stateless and that allows you to set up
multiple copies essentially of an application server and direct
incoming request to any copy that you wanted. That is sort of an
obvious way, especially with cloud computing that you can add
more capacity for that particular functionality. We also
mentioned the traditional relational database has some pretty
serious limitations in how far they will scale. We talked
briefly about alternatives like sharding and partitioning that
are often used to work around those limitations, but at the end
of the day, relational databases do have some limits that are
imposed in part by the functionality that they try to give you.
So, Rails does not scale is not really true. Another statement
might be relational databases have a limit in how they can scale
and maybe we address that by starting to use some of the so-
called no sequel solutions in conjunction with another models
like DataMapper to alleviate the scaling problems in those parts
of the app. We will also see the intelligent use of catching,
essentially keeping a nearby copy of results that you have
computed recently, can go a long way towards buying you a more
mileage out of the database before you run out of scale. So,
that is not to say that it is impossible to write bad code,
right. Even given a good scalable database you can write bad
code that will [ inaudible 03:36] the database’ s attempts to be
scalable. So, I think what a lot of people said when they said
Rails does not scale was Rails encourages the use of an
architectural pattern, the active record design pattern in these
models, which in turn requires a relational database to support
some of its most advanced features and if that is what you are
doing it is not in some cases pretty easier to write bad codes
that will hit your scalability limit sooner than it otherwise
would. In particular, if you are a novice you do not follow some
of the good design patterns that we are advocating here, this
could be a pitfall that you would run into, but people blame the
framework right. They should have been blaming inappropriate use
of the abstractions that the framework tries to provide you. Now
looking back, we can look at there are these different ways to
structure web apps, there are different templating systems,
there are frameworks to support each of those choices but when
the web became a consumer mass market thing in the mind 90s, it
was the wild west, right. The biggest web severs at the time
were not running in anything that looks like cloud computing
today. They were running on minicomputers. If anybody is old
enough to remember the Altavista search engine, the Altavista
search engine ran on what my PhD adviser Erik Brewer called the
forklift upgrade model which is that the way you add capacity to
the app as you forklift out the old minicomputer and you
forklift in a much bigger minicomputer and when there is no
longer any bigger minicomputer available to buy, then that is
it. That is the [ inaudible 04:56] of your capacity, right. In
fact, one of the contributions that came out of UC Berkeley at
the time and out of Professor Brewer’ s research group which I
was very fortunate to be part of was the idea that you could
think about these apps differently, you could use clusters of
commodity computers to build them out and overtime that idea and
the ideas about statelessness and replication and so forth that
were embodied in [ inaudible 05:16] became perfect marriage, and
today this is the way that substantially all well apps are
designed and deployed. So I think Berkeley can rightfully claim
credit of being very influential in that aspect of web
development. I think the most interesting thing is that over
time, and yes it is probably fair to say that some money was
made by certain individuals during some time as a result of the
great execution of those ideas. What I think is remarkable is
that not only have the patterns, the best practice has been
extracted into frameworks, right. That is something that as
software people we get accustomed to. Once you enough versions
of something manually, so these all have something in common,
can we pull out the common parts so other people do not have to
reinvent them, and in fact that is how Rails was invented. Rails
was pulled out of a specific application that was built and then
its author said you know this particular way of structuring
model view controller apps could be used by other people. So,
they pulled the Rails framework out of it really. What is
interesting to me is that we are still using protocol that
really dates from late 1960s. We are using a markup language
whose ancestry is in the 1960s. We are using browsers whose
basic architecture was developed in the 1990s, but despite all
that a websever from a couple of decades ago still works, right.
The amount of interoperation afforded by following these
principles of separation, having protocols, understanding data
serialization and deserialization, these principles are really
powerful because it means that the degree of compatibility that
we have across like 30 years of the Worldwide Web is truly
remarkable. So that is really where I see the big value of
frameworks in applications and design patterns. It does not
always get the credit it deserves. Lastly, remember that
architecture is about making choices among alternatives, and we
have tried to show everytime we are making the choice in this
course what are some alternatives that we are leaving on the
table and why. So, because we are designing web apps, the web is
fundamentally a client server system, but there are some systems
for which a peer- to- peer architecture would make more sense.
We are going to be deploying on cloud computing which has shared
nothing. We have individual machines that can handle multiple
copies of the application server, but there are scientific
applications for example, where that organization gives you
terrible performance because the applications are such that
sharing is required among different machines working on
different parts of the problem we are going to use model view
controller because it is a natural mapping for applications that
are user facing and have to manipulate data, but [ inaudible
07:36] that for simpler application there are also other ways to
organize them that might actually be simpler, might actually
help you get your app off the ground faster. Rails has chosen to
use active record because as we will see when we talk about some
of the more advanced features, it makes it very easy to
establish very powerful relationships across different model
types and to manipulate those relationships because it takes
advantage of what relational databases already let you do.
However, you might be in a situation where for scalability
reasons perhaps you cannot use a relational database. In that
case it is nice to know that there exist other patterns like
DataMapper that allow you at the expense of more complexity and
giving up some functionality to be able to get around those
limitations. And finally, we talked about RESTful URIs. The idea
is that that the URI describes a resource and a thing to do to
it. It is entirely self- contained. You might notice that there
are a lot of even modern web apps out there that do not work
according to this principle. The same URI does different things
depending on what you did last on the application, or there is
the sequence of URIs you have to follow to do something but if
you try to issue any of those URIs out of sequence you just get
a meaningless result. So, if you want to think about your app as
a way of collecting a bunch of related services that could use
in a service oriented architecture rest emerges naturally from
that. So as you work on other apps outside of this course this
is what you should be thinking about. What are the architectural
choices that you should be making, what are the choices that you
are constrained to make, either because of the technical
limitations like scalability or because you have to be
compatible with some existing piece of the system but should
always find yourself questioning architectural choices because
that is the way the software really moves forward, is to
understand what is the right tool for the job at different
points in the evolution of your systems. So to summarize, we
have seen model view controller, a well known architectural
pattern but not the only one for structuring applications that
could user facing. Rails chooses to codify its structure at MVC
so all of the choices it makes are designed to make it easier to
do that kind of app. If you are doing non- MVC apps you will
find yourself trying to work around what rails gives you, and in
terms of the way that those components have implemented views
are done with either HAML or embedded Ruby, it is transformed to
HTML before the browser sees it. Models are stored in a
relational database and active record gives you a lot of
automatic support for mediating between the stored
representation of a model and the database and the version that
you operate on in Ruby and controllers just tie those things
together by being connected to a routing subsys and that allows
incoming URIs to be mapped to controller actions and allows the
controller to name what views should be instantiated to return
to the user, what data gets interpolated into those views and so
forth. And that concludes our high- level tour.