Okay so quick question. So what type of software is an epic
failure? beautiful code is that an epic failure? is that how we
pick that choice? legacy code unexpectedly short-lived code both
legacy code and unexpectedly short-lived code are epic failures
and the C. there's diversity ready set ah! we actually I found a
question you can talk over okay so talk over with your neighbour
and argue with each other which is the best one Alright let's
let's try voting again pairs of you should be voting together
okay ready set vote and I think it's redder than it was last
time okay so beautiful code is obviously not a failure
unexpectedly short-lived code is a failure this is the sad thing
that can happen like you know the FBI file case it was so
short-lived it never even lived right it was canceled they
didn't make it so this can happen you don't wanna do that so why
isn't legacy code a failure legacy code makes a lot of money for
people right it is satisfying the customer's need it's one half
of quality it's just not it's hard to evolve so it's
unattractive but it works. So an epic failure isn't necessarily
legacy code alright let's go ahead And that kind of introduces a
quality assurance in testing. So what is software quality? what
is quality? what does quality assurance mean and you know what
does it mean for for software and then you may have heard the
term. V&V. or validation and verification what's the difference
those sound like synonyms to each other what's the difference
between those two so in general if you were to take a class a
business classes what is product quality they had this phrase
fitness for use So what that means for quality is business value
for both the customer and for the manufacturer. And what quality
assurance Q. A. is is either processes or standards that result
in high quality products and also to improve the manufacturing
process that QA involves both of those things. So what does
software quality mean So it satisfies customers needs like we
talked about the legacy code it's easy to use get great answers
doesn't crash and stuff but it's also easy for the developer who
is kind of the manufacturer to be debugging hands. And so what
software quality assurance is ensures the quality improves the
processes of software organization So the QA team will be
looking at the value of the software itself and then see if
there's processes that can be improved and this generally gets
called quality assurance what's the difference between
verification and validation. So verification is did you meet the
specification that's what that term means So another way to say
it is did you build the thing right. But validation is is is the
specification really what the customer wants does the
specification correctly reflect what the customers asking for so
another way to say did you build the right thing. Alright So
that's verification and validation pretty much for hardware,
people have a really good idea of what the hardware should be
like for processors so it's generally verification but with
software it's really validation because the customer as you
learn in this class the customer doesn't really know what they
want til see it right once they see it working on on that's not
quite what I want and so they want you to change it. And the way
we assure software quality is testing. So testing is you know
you can't do it exhaustively even if you have one sixty four bit
variable you could do a test in one nanosecond with sixty four
bits there's two to the thirtieth nanoseconds in a second two to
thirty four nanoseconds is five hundred years. So it would take
five hundred years to exhaustively test one sixty-four bit
variables so obviously, you can't do it So what people do is
divide and conquer they have a variety of tests at different
levels of the system and then you rely on the test at a lower
level to do their job and you'll do this higher piece So
classically the way the system that tests at the bottom within a
single class is called a unit test the method does what was
expected a modular function test would be across classes or
these units integration test would be putting higher level
things together to make sure the correct assumptions remember
the problem on the Mars orbiter they were using different units
the integration test should have noticed that and then system or
acceptance test is the customers satisfied with it and accepts
it the other phr you'll hear about testing is black box versus
white box testing black box means you just look the specs white
box means you look inside these limitations to come up with
reasons test coverage is percentage of the code paths that are
covered have you exercise everything with your test are the
pieces of the code that haven't been exercised regression
testing is the idea is what you make changes to it rather than I
assume all the tests will work you try all the tests you made
every time to see if you broke anything as you edit it in
continuous integration gets called C. I. sometimes is every time
you add a new feature it's constantly running the code all the
time overnight rather than later in the process you tested it's
continuously being checked test every time you check in. we are
ready for another question