The most exciting part is let's get them rolling here. Let's get
Cucumber and Capybara moving. This is what's called ... it's
another fun part of this tool. It's incredibly magic. It's
colorful; it's a very colorful tool. It colors the steps when
you use them, so green means the step passed. This is of your
scenario, right. The green steps pass, yellow means you haven't
implemented it yet, red means it failed, and if it fails it's
going to stop there so all the steps afterwards it's going to
color it blue. The goal is to make this red- yellow- green
analysis. You want to make all your steps green. Make all your
steps green and the story is the girlfriend of the guy who came
up with this tool decided that to make it all green then
cucumber would be a cool vegetable to name it after because you
want to make everything green. I guess maybe she's vegan or
something like that. Now we're going to do a live demo with
Cucumber here, our cuc as it's called. There's a screen test
that you can look on but we will see if the video lets me do the
demo. What we're going to do is do ‘ add movie. '  This is the
one we saw before and I'll show it to you in the editor here.
This is what we're going to try and we'll start off trying to
run Cucumber on this thing, and we put this in the features'
directory and this is addmovie. features. Let's go to Cucumber
and you see under the command Cucumber, Features, Add Movie and
let's see what happens. Presumably, since we're doing the red-
yellow- green analysis, this better not be all green and it's
not. It says right here at the bottom we did one scenario that
failed. There were eight steps there, one failed and seven were
skipped and now we scroll up the screen. Here it is, it says, "
Given I am on the rotten potatoes' homepage," and this is in red
so it failed and here's the other message, " I can't find the
mapping from the rotten potatoes' homepage to a path," right.
That's what we should be doing to associate that, not only that.
This is like a navigator. It doesn't just say, " You made a
mistake. Here it is," it says, " Now here's how you fix it,
Dave. Dave go add a mapping to the paths. rb to fix that missing
path," so it not only found what was wrong it tells you what to
go do, so let's do that. That's the Cucumber page and so paths.
rb, it gives you the full directory name there but that's over
here, and let me go back. I almost forgot. This is what it wants
to find so I'll make a copy of this. That's what I'm going to
have here on my ‘ when' condition. I'm going to copy that now
and let me go to paths. rb and here's where it is. It says here
in the file add more mappings here. You can see here's an
example, here's a ‘ when' condition and here's the regular
expression with the hat, meaning the beginning of the line.
We're going to copy that line, put the paths. rb, so I do that.
Now I'm going to want to add this path to figure that out like
Armando showed earlier. I'm going to run rake routes, okay, and
this is going to list what's on the page so this is the index
action. Here's the command ‘ get, '  so here's the path that I
want which is ( slash) / movies. Again I copy that. I go to
paths. rb and I add that after this with the quotes around it,
right there, okay. Cuc found the message and then told me where
to go fix it and I used rake routes to do that. Let me go to the
end there. Let me just clear the screen so it doesn't get
confusing. Let's try it again and it found a mistake. Let's try
and do our red- yellow- green analysis and see if hopefully we
made some progress, and it said, " Look" at the bottom again.
The scenario failed. We have eight steps, two passed this time,
one failed and the rest were skipped. This one's got a pretty
big error message. It should be very similar to this one. When
I'm on the rotten potatoes' homepage and I add a new movie, then
I should be on the Create New Page, movie page. It says, " I
can't find the mapping from Create New Movie page to path," and
this kind of reminds me of a navigator, when you're going in the
car and navigating and you don't follow it after a while.
Doesn't it seem like it starts getting mad at you? " Come on,
turn right." " Dave damn it, go add a mapping to the rotten
potatoes' homepage with the thing." Tell me what to do. I'm
going to make a copy. Now let's go to path. Again I'm going to
want to say ‘ when' in the beginning of the line in the Create
Movie Page. When I'm on the Create Movie Page, now let me go
back to the rake routes and this time I'm doing new right here,
and this is the path I need, movies/ new, so let me copy it. I
go to paths. rb. Let me add that. What we've done is added a
user story around an existing something that worked. We were
just having an extra test to see if it worked. Let's see what
Cucumber says. Let me clear it again, run it to see if it's
happy now. Green, one scenario, one passed, all eight steps
passed and you see it's green analysis so cool as a cucumber, so
to say. Okay It was already existing. We didn't add any new
features. We didn't add new functionality to the app. We just
added a test to make sure it could do that and that we could
see, and then we added Men In Black. It really showed up.