If I define ... here, I've got three savings accounts that I've
initialized with three different balances. Suppose I try to put
those three savings accounts in an array and I try to call a
sort on that array. What happens in this case? Does it work
because the account balances are numbers and we know how to
compare them? Does it not work, but if we added a comparison
method or if we passed a comparison method to the sort method
then it would work? Do we say it doesn't work but it would work
if we defined a spaceship operator for savings accounts, or it
doesn't work because since this isn't a basic, it would be tight
and there's no built in way to compare it to the operator?
Initial vote. I already see some cards even before I finished
reading the question. Alright, overwhelming votes for red. You
guys are on fire today. Let's go through the answers here.
" It
works because the account balances get compared." Well, that's
certainly what we would like to be the case, but comparing
accounts isn't the same as comparing integers, so that's not it.
If we pass a comparison method to sort, that's not the Ruby way,
right? The Ruby way is sort makes some assumptions about the
thing you're trying to sort, in particular that the thing knows
how to compare itself to other instances of that thing. The
correct answer is: If we define the spaceship operator for
savings accounts ... and by the way, how would we define it? An
easy way would just be to say, as in this example: Here's a way
to define comparisons on bank accounts. Here it is. It's coming
now. We have two minutes left, yes. Here's the way you define
comparison on bank accounts. I'm lazy, so I'm just going to
define spaceship and then I'm going to include [ comp- pra- bowl
00:01:40] to get the other ones for free. In case you don't
believe me, I will copy and paste that code. I already had the
class account defined, so now ... remember I had these accounts
with high balances? I can say ... okay? Speaker 2:	[ Inaudible
00:02:03]. Speaker 1: True in so many ways. ( Laughing) What's
the message here? Ruby provides a lot of useful functionality to
already do the work you need to do. Your job ... it's already
varies in ... you need to do the least amount of new work
possible to get the functionality you need. When you have
behaviors you want to reuse, you can put them into a module.
That module can be mixed into many classes as long as you make
clear what does the module expect from the classes that you're
mixing it into. If you want to reuse implementation, then you'd
use the traditional thing. Classes have ancestors, they have
sub- classes. As we'll see, contrary to what you might think
coming from the JAVA world, remarkably often, what you want is
the first one. You don't want to reuse implementation; you want
to define behaviors and reuse them.