We're back. Rotten Potatoes again, but this time we're going to
do some stuff. We're going to add this new feature using the
TMDb and we're going to do routes and just everything that
you're going to do at a small scale. Let's go back here. Because
this is a new feature, we're going to create this feature in its
own file in the features directory. Let's see what it looks
like. I showed it on the screen there. Here it is, the feature
and here's the little extra format as movie fan and this is
doing the sad path were we have to do all the setup and then at
the end, we said, we should see " movies does not exist here".
That's the feature. Let's just go to Cucumber. I'll clear it
again. We're going to want to do Cucumber, not for add movie
feature but for search TMDb. Let's try it. This shouldn't work,
but let's see how far it gets in this feature for searching
TMDb. It said " The scenario failed." There are six steps in
this case. One pass, one failed and the rest were skipped. Given
I'm on the Rotten Potatoes homepage, you can have that, then I
should see search TMDb and it said, " It failed" here. What we
said earlier what was missing ... We said earlier what was
missing; we want to add this Haml code to create the view. We
don't have the view, so let's create the view. We're going to
copy it. We're going to copy this code. The commercial slips
right in there. I keep forgetting to do that. We've copied that,
now let's go back to the terminal window and it says, " Add this
to this Haml file under views." Use the Haml file under views
and it actually said to add it to the end of this, so we'll add
it to the end of that and let's write that out. Now, go back.
Try Cuke again. Let's try it again. I tried putting Jeopardy
music in but I'm afraid we get sued. What happened? A lot of
message. That must have really made a bad turn here. Speaker 2:
You probably did the indentation syntax error on the Haml.
Speaker 1: No. There's no route. It looks bad but it's not a
disaster. There's no route, so I just added the route. That's a
lot of error messages for a route. Speaker 2: That's that pass
before. Speaker 1: What? Speaker 2: That's that pass. Speaker 1:
Let me show you what happens when I add the route. Yes, it did
pass before when I add the route. Here's the route I'd have to
add. Let me just copy it in. Copy it. Let me go over here and we
need to add the route. It actually says to put it right here
after resources movies, it says that in the comments in the
code. It says to do that there. Now, I have added the route and
let's see what Cuke does with this. It's always exciting when
you're giving a live demo. Look, three passed. Let's go back.
Given I'm on the Rotten Potatoes homepage and I searched TMDb.
When I fill the search terms and I press, it says, " Search
TMDb." What it says is, and this is a much more comforting error
message, I can't find the action, the method in the controller
that you're supposed to invoke. That's because we haven't
rendered it yet. That seems good. Let's go back to Pastebin,
find that fake controller methods that often does is writes to
the flash. It's never going to find a movie. It's a terrible
search method. It always fails. We copy it, go back to the
controller. We're going to add this to the controller. You can
save it. You can add it anywhere, so let's just add it at the
top. We've seen it, it looks like. Now, we've got the view,
we've got the route, we've got the action. The route is supposed
to be mapped too. Let's go back to Cuke and try it ... Okay, do
it again. The suspense. Yes, everything passed. All six passed
and everything is green. It's kind of visually exciting when you
do the Cucumber and it works. When you do it and I did actually
do it ... You didn't hear Armando said. Because Haml is not
parenthesized, it's based on indentation, I did enter it one
time with VI and it put extra spaces in and whole thing broke
in. It's very disconcerting but it was exciting when it happens.
Let's go back to PowerPoint here. How will we do the happy path
part of that? We would repeat a whole lot of steps but the path
is lovely and they also go off, but there's a whole lot of
steps, the same between the happy path and the sad path. That
doesn't seem very dry or repeating ourselves. So what do you do?
What is a background thing in Cucumber that says, " You'd run
this before you run any of the scenarios." It's a bunch of stuff
that's common. You can just do it once. If we see this, this is
the sad path; it's shorter than it used to be because we put the
pieces of the sad path over here. But now, the happy path can
use it too. Before any of these scenarios are run, no matter
which one is running, it does all the background work and then
you can just do the pieces of it and we'll do the happy path
after we define the real method. Summarizing Cucumber, it's this
amazing thing. I just can't believe it. When we go around and
give talks about this, I was just at the University of
Washington last week, I think of it as a magic trick. I showed
them the three by five cards and turns into an acceptance test.
It brings all these together that you know, the color step
green. Like I said, usually, you do the happy pass first and we
do this intermittently with BDD and TDD as you'll see. It let's
us dry out these scenarios with the background.