Ready. Set vote. What do we got? We got reds and blues. Reds and
blues. Okay. Why don't you talk it over? Red and blue can't both
be right. Talk it over and come up with a vote. Let's try it
again. Voting together. Ready. Set. Vote. It's still pretty
colorful out there, so let me go over them. The easy one, number
one. The purpose of a Lo-FI UI, you bought the UI before you
program it. Yep, that's what we're trying to do, debug and reach
agreement with the customer, I guess, both of those things. A
BDD downside is requiring continuous contact with customers,
which may not be possible. We've tried to find you customers
that are desperately care about what you want to meet with you.
Sometimes the customer won't care, they just rather you figure
it out and come back then BDD doesn't work so well. A BDD
downside is that it may lead to a poor software architecture,
since the focus is on behavior. What about that one, which we
haven't talked about much? Kent Beck, who is one of the
signatures of the Agile manifesto, he wrote his John Hancock on
that, and he came up with the idea of extreme programming, which
is the form of Agile that we are practicing in this course. He
said about this statement, " Is it possible you'll end up with a
poor software architecture?" He said, " It's not possible, it's
guaranteed. You are guaranteed to have a poor software
architecture because you're concentrating in behavior." A part
of the magic of agile is, you are expected to be continuously
evolving the code and Armando will talk about two important
ideas, refactoring and design patterns is how to get good
software architectures. That's a part of the Agile model. You
start off, you build things and then you refactor the code as it
becomes more elaborate to make it have a good software
architecture. Yeah, that's a valid criticism, although we
haven't talked about it very much.