Since this is our last segment, we have a last question. Since
I've just been assuming, as I said, when you get to the
controller action, where is it going to look for a view to
render? Implicit in that statement is the assumption that
something must be rendered. Here's my question, why is that the
case? Why must every interaction with a SaaS app eventually
cause something to be rendered? One possibility is it's
convention over configuration. This is the default way that you
do things. If you're going to follow that method, then you don't
have to do anything special. Second, it's because HTTP is a
request- reply protocol. Third, because in Model- View-
Controller, the implication is every action should be rendering
its own view, or all of the above are true. Why must every
interaction with the SaaS app eventually cause something to be
rendered? Initial voting is ... initial voting is varied. This
is one to talk about, since we actually have a couple of
minutes. Let me give you a hint to inform your discussion.
Here's a hint to inform your discussion. Note that I did not
say ... hint to inform discussion. I did not ask why must every
interaction with a Rails app, blah, blah, blah. Also, I did not
asked, why must every interaction with a Model- View- Controller
app, blah, blah, blah. I asked every SaaS app. This is a pretty
universal question. I guess I could say, every interaction that
does not result in an error, but you know what I mean. One more
vote. Voting now. Voting now, voting now, voting and ... the
good old days. Let's go through the answers to this. Why must
every interaction with the SaaS app eventually cause something
to be rendered? I hate to oversimplify, but let's go back to the
very beginning. HTTP is a request- reply protocol. If you ask a
question, an answer is required. The only way you can give an
answer is by rendering something that gets sent back over HTTP.
If the user asks you to do something stupid, the thing you
render might be an error page, or the web server might render an
error page saying, " You're not allowed to do this,” or “ You're
not logged in,” or, “ The hell with you.” At the end of the day,
it has to say something, otherwise, there's an error. The
question has to be answered. Convention over configuration, it's
a nice thing that's in place so that as you're constructing your
reply, you can save yourself the time of telling Rails where to
find the various pieces needed. Model- View- Controller implies
that every action renders a view. You could make that case, but
that's actually not strictly true. Model- View- Controller is
not as strict, because remember, we said you could use MVC to
structure things like peer- to- peer applications. Peer- to-
peer applications don't follow the client- server request- reply
pattern. This question is even more general than those. It's
really just because HTTP was designed around the fact that one
person asked the questions, or the client asked the question,
the server has to give the answer. Therefore, anything that hits
the server eventually has to have a termination which is, " Here
is what the answer is." There we are.