Okay, we're almost done with CRUD; we've done create, we've done
read, and now we just have to do update and delete. The good
news is you pretty much have now at least seen all of the basic
machinery. We're just going to be putting it together in
different ways here. When we did the create action, we saw that
doing a create really amounts to 2 interactions, when you're
talking about a human- facing web service. There is getting the
form to fill out, and then there's submitting the filled out
form and those are 2 different controller actions, usually. By
the way, I am going to point out, and we're going to come back
to this in just a few minutes, that the idea that creating
something is 2 actions, it's important to realize why that's an
artifact of us doing a human- facing application. If you're
thinking of Rotton Potatoes as a remote service that
manages movie information reviews, then you would think,
logically, creating a new movie listing is one action. It's,
here's some data to create a new movie. Just create it and let
me know if it succeeded. What we are going to see in a moment is
that with basically a 1- line controller change, you can make
the same logic in your app work for both a human- facing site,
where the user has to do 2 interactions to do a create, as well
as a service- orientated architecture- facing site, where it ‘ s
a single action. You can basically repurpose your code to do
that really trivially. Having said all that, the edit update
action is exactly analogous, that if I want to edit information
about an existing movie, I've got to do two things; I first have
to get the existing information in front of me, usually in a
form that already has the values prefilled, and then I have to
be able to submit the form with the modified information. We're
going to use the same technique in that the first action
retrieves the form, the second action submits the form, and just
as with create, at the end of our update action we'll use a
redirect, in this case, back to the action that shows the movie
details, rather than just having a view that says update
successful, and nowhere to go from there. Now, what's different
about this case is that, when you're creating a new movie, the
initial form should be blank, but if you're editing an existing
one, it makes more sense for the existing values to already be
filled in. So, how would we do that? The edit update pair is
really similar to what we've seen before. The difference is in
the action. The edit action which is going to serve the form, is
first going to grab the movie ID of which existing movie is
being edited, and it's going to use that to populate this
@movie variable, so that when we first display the form, the
existing information is going to, essentially, be pre-
populated. Then, the update action looks a lot like the create
action. We're just going to grab the ID of the movie to be
updated; this is a difference, because before we were creating a
brand new one, and we're going to call update_attributes, which
you've seen. We're going to pass that hash of values that the
user filled out on the form, and a flash message and a redirect.
So, all of the same machinery, really, that applies to what we
just did for the create action. The other difference is that,
where we were using a post to do the creation of a new movie,
we're using a put to do the update of an existing movie. First
of all, why is that, and second, how could we even do that given
that web browsers generally only support get and post, but not
put. What's going on there? Well, one reason here is that,
again, Rails really is trying to say think about building a
RESTful app first, and then secondarily think about how you
would make a human- facing interface for it. During your design
process, you really ought to be thinking in terms of RESTful
actions. One way to distinguish different kinds of RESTful
actions, as post versus a put, and it's becoming an increasingly
common semantics, the put is what you use to update something in
place, versus post is what you use to submit brand new
information. It's sort of an emerging consensus. It's no problem
to have different RESTful routes whose only distinction is which
verb they use, whether they use put or post. Now, what about the
second problem where web browsers can only generate either get
or post actions; they can't generate puts. How do we do that?
Well, happily, as it turns out, anticipating this very question,
what happens in the Rails world if we actually specify method
put, which is what we're going to have to do with this form,
we're saying we want to trigger the RESTful action that updates,
in place, existing information. But, what actually happens here
is that, when html gets rendered from this, it will be rendered
as a post, which the web browser knows how to handle, but there
will be an additional hidden form field that is basically
embedded in the form, and is a trigger to Rails to say this was
supposed to really be a put, but web browsers don't know how to
do a put, so on your way into the controller method, change the
post into a put. It's interesting, so the effect of all this is
that in your controller action, you can ask which HTTP method
was used to submit this form, and the answer is, it was put,
even though it really started out back on the web browser as a
post. Again, why would you want to design Rails to support this
behavior; it's because you're really designing a RESTful service
interface, and you'd like the controller method to say, okay,
I've got a put, and I got this verb; I know what that means, it
means update. The only thing I really need to know is is the
result going to be visible to a human, or the result going to
another programmatic service. I want the semantic of put to be
the same, whichever one of those 2 it is. This is a build up to
the fact that, in a moment, I'm going show you exactly how to do
that. Given that you can take my word for the fact that the put
gets changed to a post, the only other thing we haven't done is
destroy, which is simplicity itself. Remember we said destroy is
an instance method and the reason for that is you would think
that you call ... on a collection of movies, say destroy this
one. But no, what you really want to do is destroy the instance,
because you want to give it a chance to clean up after itself.
That's a topic we'll talk about more when we start doing
associations and advanced Rails methods. Because destroy is an
instance method, we have the same strategy where we can find the
movie first, based on the params hash. We can call destroy in
it, and then we can include a little flash message to confirm
that everything worked, and redirect somewhere interesting.
Redirect is this general mechanism for saying I did what you
wanted me to do, and rather than just show you a boring page
that states that fact, I'll save you a step and take you back
some place potentially more interesting. But, that's it'; you've
basically now seen all of the CRUD actions that you can do, and
the relatively small amount of machinery required to do them.