We're going to talk about ugly code, which is something you
probably don't spend a— hopefully you don't spend a lot of time
talking about that. Can we do something beyond just correctness?
Can we talk about beauty of a code? What's our guidelines on how
to make beautiful code? Can we actually evaluate beauty
qualitatively? Can we do it quantitatively? How well will these
tools work, these metrics work? Then, do we have tools to be
able to help that out? That's our motivating question. We’ re
going to start off with smells. We're going to talk about
smells. Does code smell funny? That actually has a technical
concept associated with it, and people do write these books
about smelly code. Depending on what you refer to, there's 20
common mistakes, code smells, [ Code Smeller 60 00:51] depending
on what you do about that. We'll give you some examples of that
going ahead, but one idea that we wanted to get across was a way
to avoid smelly code. We use the SOFA acronym. First of all, is
it short? We're talking about kind of a method at a time doing
it, so keeping the method short makes it less likely to smell.
Does it do just one thing versus doing lots of things? Does it
have a few arguments to the method or lots of arguments?
Finally, is it a consistent level of abstraction? What tends to
happen is that smelly code tends to violate a bunch of these
things, and these will help make your code more fragrant. It got
started short. What does short mean? In the good old days
terminals were 24 lines, baby characters, so pretty much short
was it fit on one screen. These days with modern big old
displays, you could get hundreds of lines of code. Fitting on
one giant display isn't short. The idea is you kind of look at
it and figure out what it's doing. There is a tool for this.
Because it's about smells, it's called Reek. Reek does it— it
catches bad smells for you. The single level of extraction is a
little bit of an abstract idea. The idea is that it's not trying
to do everything all in one task. Here's a task, I'll throw it
all in one big method. You try and to divide and conquer, but
yet keep at that same level of abstraction as you're going on.
Typically often calling other methods to be able to do that, but
that all the methods being called are about the same level of
complexity. The best analogy is like writing a good news story.
If you took an English class or to become a reporter, you start
off with a good summary and then each paragraph goes into points
in more detail. There's exactly one topic about each paragraph,
as opposed to the rambling style where it jumps back and forth
between the lots of ideas. The single level method is
orchestrating everything that's going on. That's one of the
goals to try after the single level of extraction. Who cares
about lots of arguments? First of all, if there's a lot of
arguments it can be difficult to get test covers. If really
there's many different things you have to cover to be able to
test it, then that's going to be difficult. It also, lots of
arguments can make it difficult to do mocking and stubbing so
that you can isolate pieces of your design to do testing
differently. A real danger sign is a Boolean flag. A Boolean
flag is one of your arguments, so chances are what that means is
there's really two methods hiding in there and for some reason
you put a single Boolean flag. What you've taken has just made
one really hard to test method out of two things that should be
separate methods. Try and avoid that. The other thing you may
see is a bunch of arguments traveling in a pack together across
a bunch of method calls. If that's happening, you should really
extract them and create a new class so that you aren't funneling
these arguments, funneling this [ inaudible 03:44] along. Let's
take a look at a smelly program here. This is an actual program
that [ Armando 03:52] found that was in the book, and that was
what it was. You look at it there and kind of stare at this
thing, and you see letters like y and d. If you're a native
English speaker you think, " Well, what might that mean?" Then
you see numbers like 365, and if you're on the Gregorian
calendar 365 is a number, so this has probably got to do with
years or something like that. Now this actually, this program
actually has a bug in it. It'd be difficult to figure out … you
don't even know what it's doing, much less what the bugs are.
When we run it through Reek, Reek is this thing that's looking
for smells given this qualitative evaluation, what does it say
about this program? What it says at the top is that it talks
about dryness. Don't repeat yourself. It says this y+ 1 is used
twice here. At the end of each of these if and else statements
it's the same statement, you're doing it twice where you could
get away with it once. The next thing it says is the method is
long. Length is kind of in the eye of the beholder. Now the Ruby
code's really powerful, so even a bunch of statements like that
is pretty long. A lot of it is this nested if- statements. It's
kind of hard to figure out. It's suggesting it's kind of a long
method. After that it starts complaining about these single-
letter variable names, both as a parameter and then in the while
loop and again. That's what this, whatever this is, 15 line
little method here. There's a bunch of things that Reek says it
smells funny. Again, if you weren't an English speaker or if
you're using the Hebrew calendar or something, these numbers,
you wouldn't kind of guess what these things mean. That's the
qualitative judgment, and there's a tool to do that. How about
quantitative? What people tried to do in the... We're trying to
create software engineering is, isn't there some things we could
try and measure complexity just by looking at the source program
itself and adding some things up. One of the oldest one of these
things is called ABC Complexity, which is a function of the
assignments, branches and conditions. The formula for looking
lots of programs, looking lots of procedures and trying to
figure out what's complicated is somebody came up with the
formula, " Well, let's take … we'll square the number of
assignments and the number, square the number of branches,
square the number of conditions, take the square root of that
and that's going to be a quantitative measure of complexity."
Believe it or not the National Institute of Standards, which
seems like it has plenty of other things to work on, has come up
with a ( laughs) cutoff for government contracts about what you
have to do to make your method— it has to be not too
complicated. The square root of all that has to be less than 20
for a method, for it to be government approved. ( Laughter)
Rails of course, because it's easy. What's fun about the Rails
environment because it's easy to build software and it's ...
you're building software for programmers. Programmers make tools
for programmers. There's a program called Flog that'll
automatically calculate your ABC Complexity for Ruby methods.
The most well known quantitative measure, it's called cyclomatic
complexity. The idea is to try and figure out how many
independent paths are there through a method, because that'll
tell you something about what you have to do for test coverage
if you have to cover all those methods. Again, somebody … this
guy was … his name was Charles McCabe; he did this almost 40
years ago. He invented this complexity. His formula was, " Let's
talk about these nodes," but nodes are basic blocks, right? One
branch in, one branch out, there's no branches inside them.
Let's count how many nodes that's in. The edges are between the
node, that's the edges there, and then connected components are
these things that kind of are connected near each other. The
Charles McCabe complexity or cyclomatic complexity for this
little outline of a one would be nine edges, eight nodes and one
connected component. When you pull it through like that you get
a connected component of three. Once again the National
Institute of Standards has stepped in, defined what government
contracts has to do, and it's supposed to be less than 10 per
module. Again in the Rails community there's a tool, Saikuro,
which calculates cyclomatic complexity for you. Let's go ...
we'll take a look at that first method we did, go back. Let's
just say basically about the quantitative measurements. It's not
like these are foolproof methods, if you get a bad score it's a
bad method. These are indicators that something's going on. If
you try a bunch of these methods, and Reek and Flog and Saikuro
all suggest the numbers are too big or give you lots of
warnings, you probably should take a look at that and see what
you can do about it. There's other tools as well. We talked
about simple coverage in testing, are all the statements
executed? That's C0 coverage, Armando talked about a while ago.
SimpleCov is a tool that'll do that for you in your projects and
your tools. You'll want to get above 90% on SimpleCoverage.
There's rake stats will actually talk about the ratio of code to
testing. A big part of test driven development and behavior
driven designs we'll talk about today is having a lot of testing
that you're doing on it. It says what the ratio should be, it
should it be twice as much testing code as executing code. Let's
take a look at that program, which actually is trying to do some
leap year calculation. The ABC Complexity, assignments,
branches, conditions, does get a score of 23, which is above the
National Institute of Testing Standards, so that suggests it's a
problem. The code complexity score is under 10. It's not a very
complicated— it's a couple of conditions, if statements that's
there, so it's not a lot of parallel pass and the number
indicated, it's not a problem. How could we fix that up? Let's
go through. First of all, we're pretty sure d was day and y was
year. We can put that in here. Let's do that leap year
calculation, we got the leap year method with a question mark so
that's returning a Boolean value and we stick that over there to
be able to figure that out. We've broken that out into a
separate private method. When we put that through Reek instead
of the six warnings, one of the warnings was it was too long and
uncommunicative variable names, I can't remember what the other
one was, but all the warnings go away. The ABC Complexity, now
instead of above 20 each method is down around 10, and the
Saikuro score is below that. This is intuitively easier code to
figure out what's going on. It's nice when you're saying if it's
a leap year that gives you intuition what's happening here.
Okay, so that's a little bit … you should be thinking about
doing this with Ruby. The next assignment that we will give will
include these tools. We're not going to grade you on it, but
we're going to let you see what the [ inaudible 10:35] of the
tool. When a time to do the project that's in this class, we'll
be running these tools over your ... your code so to help you
improve the quality of what you write.