Which statements do you think are true regarding behavior-
driven development and test- driven development: that
requirements drive the implementation, that BDD and TDD are used
only in Agile, or that they are designed to embrace and deal
with change? Initial votes? Okay we have a majority opinion here
for red, but there is by no means unanimous. Take about 30
seconds. Let's vote again, and we have convergence on red. Red
is correct. Certainly, requirements drive the implementation
both from the features you wished you had and the code you
wished you had. That's your starting point. In both cases, that
is certainly true. They can be used only in Agile development.
No, that's not true. That's where they came from, because it's a
very convenient way to quickly iterate over new features, but
there's nothing stopping you from first going to the customer,
getting a whole volume of features, going off for six months
implementing those features, coming back and having the customer
tell you they changed their mind. You're free to do that. B is
not correct. You can use these outside of Agile, but they fit
very well with Agile. That's where they came from. Lastly c,
that they embrace and deal with change. They certainly do,
because if you're actually doing a feature at a time or if
you're doing one set of functionality at a time, that gives you
small increments to make progress so you don't take a big risk
in building a lot of code that may or may not be what the
customer actually turns out to want.