What happens if you embed code that tries to directly act as the
model? So I mentioned active record give you the ability to
essentially do operations on the model without explicitly naming
the database. The database machinery is hidden inside the active
record module that comes with Rails. So a question for you to
think about this, if you try to do that in the view what would
happen? Would it work, but be bad form and you would be naughty,
would it work when you are developing against the toy database,
but it would not work in production necessarily, will it not
work because views cannot communicate directly with the models
in MVC, it has to go through a controller or does it vary
depending on what it is specifically that your app is trying to
do when it manipulates the model directly from the view. So,
think for a moment and I will drink for a moment. … Initial vote
says preference for orange but also a representation for blue
and green. So, choices one, three and four are all represented.
I do not see any support for green, so talk it over for a little
bit … Okay, I submit that it is time to vote again. So let’ s do
that. … Orange has received a lot more support. Just to prove
that I am not staging it that want to go through a totally
different random order two, three, four, one. It will work when
developing against a toy database but not in production. No, not
necessarily. There are a lot of things that you can do to be
cruel to your production database and some of them have nothing
to do with this. So, it is really not a matter of distinguishing
between the toy versus the real database in this case. Another
way to put that is, this is always a bad idea whether it is
development or production. It will not work because views cannot
communicate directly with the models. Remember that whenever you
make architectural choices, it is very rare that the framework
you are using will be so draconian that there is absolutely no
way to escape your architectural choices. You can always
exercise bad habits. So a model view controller says that in a
properly architected MVC app, it should be the case that views
do not communicate directly with models, but there is no
machinery that will explicitly stop you from trying to do that.
It is the enough rope to hang yourself philosophy. Behavior
varies depending on the app. No, it does not vary depending on
the app. It is just always a bad idea. This will work, you can
do this and in fact you can argue that many PHP apps do exactly
this. But it is bad form. It violates the guidelines and it
ought to be making you wonder why it is that you find yourself
putting code like that in the view. What is it that the view is
viewing that is so important that it needs to the talk to the
model directly? If it is that important, why is not that code
already part of the model? So those are the kind of things that
should be asking yourself. Another guideline that we are going
to come across that is very similar is if you are writing a
controller action, what do controller actions do? They handle
what’ s coming in from the user. They tell the model, “ Hey,
here’ s what I need,” and then they make that data available,
usually by rendering that data through some kind of a view. That
is all they do. That is not a complicated job description. So if
you writing control methods, and there are more than like five
or ten lines long, there is a problem right. There is a real
tendency for code to creep into places where it does not belong.
The province of computing interesting things and dealing with
data is the province of the model. So if you find yourself doing
stuff like that in controllers or in views, that should be a
sort of a self check for you to ask why did not I put this in
the model before, why is it in there now?