With that let's do another one of these things what is not true
about software and servers for service oriented architecture in
cloud computing clusters are collections of commodity servers
connected by land switches internet supplies the communication
Saas apps that cloud computing uses hardware cluster and
software using redundancy predict that the bill private data
centres could match the cost of warehouse scale computers if
they just use the same type of hardware and software And, ready,
set alright okay this is this is this is these are just too easy
yeah you'll hear people say this who have private data centres
well if I use the same software when you Eucalyptus software
that buy the same PCs they don't have any same price advantage
but it's economies of scale that they don't get when they do
that I alright the next we're going to do some terms about what
type of software we hope you will build. So why do I care if
what others think in my code if works does it matter what looks
like. Well that's the kind of the motto, who cares what it looks
like is a what's called legacy code. It's what that means a
software that keeps meeting customers needs but its difficulty
evolve due to inelegant or antiquated technology so give you an
idea is we had to give an alternative that which we call
beautiful code that does make the needs but on the other hand is
easy to evolve so it's high quality software. So sixty percent
of the cost of software maintenance is adding functionality
legacy software versus just 17 percent for fixing bugs. So the
thing was kind of we knew about legacy code but this is
something that's tradition left out of software engineering
courses and textbooks so when we Armando and I figure out what
to do teach software engineering we went to talk to these half
dozen companies who know how to build software like Google and
Amazon in places like that. And they said the number one
question every single company was the students need to learn to
deal with un-documented legacy code. So the first three
companies went to we tried to argue with them and "no you don't
wanna say that" because we did not do it but after the fourth,
fifth, and sixth we said okay we gotta do that so while we're
gonna do that in this course. So we'll have lectures the talk
about how you deal with like this legacy code in a programming
assignment later in the course where you will deal with legacy
code I'll show you the surveys later we also survey the alumni
from this course to see what was important. And we certainly
alumni from the course who were still in school hadn't graduated
and the alumni who had gone to industry in that people still in
school you know we need legacy might be okay to people in who
from the course who are alumni in industry this is right at the
top of their list you have to deal with legacy legacy code so
that's what we're gonna do