Here's an example for you try. Which string will not appear as
a result of running this code, that's assuming the code runs it
all? Perhaps the code has some syntax error and won't actually
run. Take a look at the code for a moment and think it over. By
the way, match is a regular expression. Yeah, we got to do a
first vote, I forgot. Vote. I think that's orange, right? Based
on the lighting, is that orange? Since you guys are so quick,
let's go talk through the answers here. What's happening in this
expression? We've got an array of three things and when we call
map, what is map going to do? It actually returns another
collection, right? It's going to take this anonymous function
and it's going to apply it to each of the elements and return a
new collection with those application. What's inside the
function body? It takes an element and it calls reverse on it.
We've seen that string. reverse will reverse a string so what
we're getting out of here is ananab, anana, isn't that cool that
I picked a palindrome and naan which is another palindrome,
three great foods by the way. The middle one means pineapple in
Spanish. At this point, after the word end, that's where we are.
We've got a new collection that has the three strings but each
one of them has been reversed. Within that collection we're
going to select, in other words filter for all of the ones that
match a regular expression that begins with A. Ananab and anana
will fit that criteria and naan does not fit that criteria so it
will not appear and therefore orange is the correct answer. Well
done.