Okay, the booth has voted. Everybody else vote. Okay, this is a
good one to talk over and while you guys talk it over, I'll set
up a fun thing that we'll do for the last two minutes. Okay, so
we're voting the second time then we're going to go through the
answers and have four minutes reasoning fun. I would say we have
a majority for green and we have a few people saying blue. Let's
go through this. The top one result should not be empty. That's
perfectly fine. We've seen stuff like that before. Result should
not match a regular expression, absolutely reasonable. That's
also one of the built ins. This is problematic though because
when you say something, should be something, you're asking for a
bullion argument, right? Either five is result or is not result.
There's some property we are trying to get true or false on and
the spaceship operator isn't dual value, right? Spaceship
returns one of three possible values depending on whether the
first thing is less than and the same as, or greater than the
second thing. Whether this is in tactically legal, it's besides
the point. It's confusing because there's no way to tell what it
means. If I had said five should be less than result, that would
have made sense. The spaceship operator isn't something that
returns true or false. In fact and technically speaking, it
always returns a non- false value, right? Zero, one, and minus
one are all ... Because they're not Neil from Ruby's point of
view, that makes them true. The correct answer here is that,
five should be spaceship result isn't that appropriate because
it actually wants a binary valued thing, bullion valued thing
and this isn't one.