So, which of these is poor advice? Poor advice. Initial vote,
poor advice. Okay, people are either internalizing the message,
or really want to be on Facebook. Okay, let's briefly talk about
why the correct answer is blue in this case. So mock and stub
early and often in unit tests. Certainly good advice because the
whole power of unit tests is the ability to isolate the code you
really care about, and mocks and stubs are a big part of how you
do that. Aim for high unit test coverage. Nothing wrong with
high unit test coverage. If you're obsessive about it, and
that's all you aim for, that would be bad. But in and of itself,
it's a reasonable goal, right? If you have unit test coverages
in the high nineties, you should be happy. Sometimes, it's okay
to use stubs and mocks in your integration tests. Well, we've
seen that sometimes you kinda have to, right? If you're
testing ... if you have an integration test for something that
runs against an external service that's a perfect example of
where a stub or a mock makes a lot of sense. You don't want to
be hitting the TMDB database every time you run your Cucumber
scenarios. You hit it once, you capture the results, and it's a
pretty realistic playback because it's based on the live site.
But having said that, keep in mind that, the same pitfalls that
apply to your regular test cases apply here. Namely, if I have a
test case, for example, a unit test that stubs out the model and
all of my tests are passing. And now, somebody goes and changes
the behavior of that model method that I stubbed out. They may
have tested their change, but if I wasn't made aware of the fact
that the API changed, my test is now going to be assuming an API
that doesn't exist anymore. So, my test is gonna still pass
because I'm stubbing out the method. But once I actually run an
integration test, it'll fail. Because now, when you remove the
stub and you call the real method the API's don't match anymore
and boom! So, the same thing can happen in a service- oriented
architecture. We used TMDB, we played some real, live requests
against it. We captured the output and fed it to fake web and
now TMDB goes and changes the way they return output, or they
change something about the restful behavior of the API. Unless
you know this fact and change your tests to match, you'll be in
this scenario where all of your tests seem to pass, and it's
because you're mocking up the thing that mattered most. You
mocked out the interface. So, you have to, sort of, reach a
level of peace with yourself about how much you mock and stub,
how much you do an integration test? You always need some. So,
that leaves the only piece of bad advice as unit tests giving
you higher confidence of correctness. It is neither higher nor
lower. It's a different kind of correctness. It's correctness
about code paths and special cases, as opposed to correctness
across interfaces, or across code paths that touch many
different pieces. You need both.