Okay, so the next logical step as we'll see in a moment,
fixtures and factories, answers the following problem. It's easy
once you learn about mocks to start going mock and stub crazy,
and step back and look at your tests and really that all you've
done is test a bunch of nothing. In fact sometimes what you
really need is the real thing. Let's take a look at an example.
What's happening here, the premise of my test set up is I want
to test this method called " Name with Rating". That is supposed
to put together the name and the rating of a movie, simplest
thing in the world. What I've done is ... Oh, I know how to use
stubs and mocks. I'll create a stub double or mock of the movie,
but I know that this name with rating method is going to look at
the title and rating attributes. I have to stub specific methods
on that mock. This is the long hand way of stubbing them. I
create the mock first, and instead of also passing additional
parameters of what to stub, I can do it separately. They mean
the same thing. Basically I end up stubbing two things, and then
call them " Name with Rating". Once my hangover abates and I
look at this and say, " You know, why didn't I just use a real
movie?" I mean, it's like it was more work to create this fake
object with certain fake behaviors, than it would've been to
just create a real object and let it use it. In cases where you
need the real thing the question is where do you get a real copy
of an object? One thing you can do is you can create a fixture;
it's a term that comes from the manufacturing world. Basically a
fixture is a harness that you put a piece of machinery in, or a
thing that you've manufactured. You're going to probe it and
poke at it and do a bunch of tests. The fixture is sort of the
part that doesn't move, hence the name. In the SAS world what it
corresponds to is, because models tend to live in tables, it
means we're going to pre- load some known data into some of the
model tables. We're going to then have tests that expect to find
those data objects there. One possibility in the example I just
showed is you could create a couple of movies. You know that
they're going to be there, you know what their attributes are.
Then when you have some tests you can rely on the presence of
those movies in the database. That's one possibility. The other
possibility is a factory, not to be confused with the factory
design pattern, or the factory method when you are constructing
objects of an abstract class. There is the concept of creating,
and the idea is in a factory you create only what you need for
this test. If I just had a test that needed a couple of movies,
I'll create the movies just in the set up for that test. As you
might have already guessed, our spec is helpful enough when you
run it with [ rails 0:02:27] apps ... If you create database
records within a specific test case, because that test case
needs to use them, it's actually the case that after that test
runs those database records are wiped out. For those of you who
are in the database world, what actually happens, in case you're
curious, is that each one of the R spec tests gets run inside a
transaction. Once the test finishes the transaction is rolled
back. You can create a whole mess of temporary data inside one
test case; and with high confidence you can know that data is
going to evaporate when the next test case runs. That helps keep
your tests independent. That brings up the tension between
fixtures and factories. The database is wiped and reloaded
before each spec. If we add this line at the beginning of one of
our described blocks it basically says, " Before you run the
tests on this block, pre- load all of the fixtures described in
this file." The file is " yml", yet another mark- up language.
You've seen " yml" files already in rails, they're trivial. You
can basically specify a handful of movies or whatever, and
they're going to be loaded into the movies table. Convention
over configuration says, " As usual, I'll look at the file name
and I'll infer which database table these fixtures are supposed
to go on." You could do that, and the nice thing about it is
that now you know what the data is. It never changes; it gets
loaded before every test; you can rely on it. On the other hand
you might end up introducing accidental dependencies into your
tests. For example, if you've got a test someplace else that has
to do with counting the number of movies that match some
criterion, if you start adding or subtracting fixtures for other
tests, that may affect the counts that would be performed by the
tests you don't care about. The bad side of a fixture is it's
sort of there for all the tests, whether you want them to be
there or not. As opposed to a factory where, instead what you do
is, you have some helper methods that make it really easy to
create versions of objects that have simple default attributes.
You know they're valid. You can create them for each test and,
because they're only created inside the tests, they're wiped out
after each test. You don't have to worry about independence.
What would this look like? Well, if you're going to do this
don't do it yourself, find a good library [ or a gem 00:04:40].
I have started to use one called " FactoryGirl", if I can find
it. Here's an example of how you would use FactoryGirl to create
a factory for movies. In one of my factory's definitions I
say, " Whenever I want to create a default version of a movie,
just give it this title, give it this rating, and give it this
release date." On a per- instance basis if I have specific tests
where I want to override those, I can certainly do it. This
basically means whenever I need a sort of, a real movie object,
not a stand- in, but an honest- to- goodness movie, I can just
say, " Build". Here's an example of where, in this case I chose
to override the title. For my own purposes I need the movie to
have a different title. The idea is you have one place where you
put some basic logic that lets you create these objects. Then
creating them is sort of a one- liner, right? It's almost as
easy as creating a mock version of the object, only you get a
real object. The reason you'd want to do this is, as we'll see
when we start doing more complex apps, often there are objects
that have relationships among them. For example, you can imagine
that if I have a movie- goer object, and I have something like a
street address. You can't imagine a movie- goer without a valid
street address. Really, when you create a movie- goer you also
have to create these other ancillary objects that go along with
them. Factories let you do that pretty easily because you can
put all the logic in one place for saying, " This is what it
means to create a usable version of this object." Even if it
also involves temporarily creating these other side objects that
it's going to use. Maybe the usable version of an object itself
relies on mocks that are set up to do these ancillary jobs; all
of those things can be captured in one place in the factory
definition. Which one do you use? As I said, one potential
downside of factories is if you have complex relationships you
have to set up, the factories could get complicated. On the
other hand, whenever you find yourself in a situation like that,
what it should be telling you is, " There's something about your
code that's not well- factored." If doing a simple test requires
setting up a lot of complex relationships, there must be a
function somewhere that knows way more than it should about all
of those relationships. You should be looking at how to re-
factor your classes, so that they don't have such dense cross-
connections. We'll talk about that quite a bit when we talk
about re- factoring. How do you know if you've committed one of
the blunders of factories versus fixtures? One of my favorite
ones is called the " mock train wreck". To motivate it here is
an example of we want to test a hypothetical method that would
search for a movie by its director, or by the Oscars that it
received, by the awards it received. This is the thing we'd
ultimately want to write in our tests. Here's the same test we
want to check for the name of a director. If we wanted to put
things like this into our test, that means that we have to have
a movie object. The movie object has to be associated with the
director object, which has to have a name attribute. The fact
that we're chaining these three things together means that the
movie object knows a whole lot about an object that is its
grandchildren. If we wanted to actually set this up we could
mock the award, we could mock what a director is, and then we
could mock a movie that has those two things as attributes. By
now you really should be asking yourself, " Wait a minute. Why
is it again if the award type is an important thing for the
movie to know, shouldn't the award object expose that as a first
class attribute, as a first class getter?" By the way if it did
that, we could just stub that getter directly. We wouldn't have
to go through this dance of creating a sequence of mocks, hence
the name " mock train wreck"; they're all chained together. The
real problem is that the movie shouldn't know things about its
descendants. It should know things about awards, but it
shouldn't know the sub- classes or the attributes of awards;
that's too much information. We'll talk about that more when we
come back to refactoring. As a preview, that's called "
inappropriate intimacy". A movie has no business reaching into
award and understanding its internals. Take that any way you
wish. Now that you've learned about fixtures and factories
here's a good intuition question. What are examples of kinds of
data that should not be set up as fixtures? Which one of these,
if any, would not be a good candidate for doing a fixture?
Movies and their ratings; the API key for TMDb in the TMDb
example we've been doing; or time zone settings for the
application wherever it runs. Would not be a good candidate for
fixturing, and of course why?