Index cards to the ready. Here we go, I've defined a
function of three arguments and my intention is that the
function take a first argument which is some scalar and then the
arguments that are hashes. The question which was alluded to you
earlier is, which of these is not a legal call to that function?
A hint is that the thing that would make a call not legal is
that there is ambiguity about how the argument list ought to be
parsed. Think about that for a moment. Let's do an initial vote.
Ready, initial vote. Wow, you guys caught on really fast. Let's
discuss it. The vote is for green and happily it's still true
that you guys are really smart and here's the reason why. In all
the other three examples, in this top example you can tell that
here's an argument, here's an argument, it's delineated by
braces and here's the third argument that just happens to have a
single key value pair. That's totally fine. Likewise, here, this
third choice, it's basically the same except that I've chosen to
include the optional parenths around the arg list. In this last
example, I've omitted the prenths but I've got braces around
both the hashes. In all three legal parses, there's no question
about where one hash ends and a different hash begins. Whereas
in the green example, there is three key value pairs here but
the function wants two hashes. There's no unambiguous way to
figure out where the first hash ends and the 2nd hash begins.
Again, how do you know for a specific function call, if I didn't
show you the definition of foo you couldn't necessarily tell
that this green one was illegal, right? If foo had been defined
as a function of two arguments, the 2nd of which is a hash then
this would be perfectly legal call. In some cases you have to
understand or look at the functions documentation to understand
what makes an illegal call and where you can get away when [
he's 00:02:00] in poetry in mode.