Armando talked about forms. Let us add a form to fill in. How
about a User Interface? If we are going to add a view for the
user interface, we are going to have to add a route to connect
it. Typically, there is usually a happy path and a sad path. Let
us show it working and not working and see what happens. What we
are going to do, our application is going to be ... it is hard
to type all that stuff in, so there is this thing called The
Movie Database, TMDb, probably all know about it. Instead of
typing in what the new functionality we want to add, is populate
the form directly from the TMDb so we are going to have the
ability to search the TMDb from the Rotten Potatoes home page.
We are going to need a LoFi User Interface and a storyboard to
do that. We are going to put all the pieces together of what we
are going to do in projects. Here is my attempt to do this. This
is my LoFi UI for the Rotten Potatoes home page and we added a
new movie from TMDb and here is the search button. In the happy
path, that is, we find the movie, it comes down here and it
fills in Inception and all the information you want and you
click Add and you go back. In the sad path where it does not
match, you get this message, No, sorry, could not have it and
you could try it over again and search again. That is the happy
path, sad path in the User Interface that we are going to do.
Let us go over what the feature looks like using the cucumber
format here above the feature. User can add a movie by searching
in The Movie Database, TMDb. As a movie fan, I can add new
movies without manual tedium. I want to add movies by looking up
their details in TMDb. We are going to write down the sad path
first. Let us try and add a movie that does not work. Given that
I am on the Rotten Potatoes home page, then I should see "
Search for a TMDb movie?" When I fill in " Search Terms", and we
will make up a name of the movie, " The Movie That Does Not
Exist", hopefully there is no movie with that name. That would
be a bad name for a movie, probably. Then I press " Search TMDb"
then I should be in the Rotten Potatoes home page and I should
see " Movie That Does Not Exist" was not found on the TMDb. That
is the sad path there. Now, let us try to figure out what we got
to add to make this work. We are going to need to have a view
for this. What we're going to have, that Armando just talked
about this earlier, is we are going to do a form, where the
action ... and we have to name a method that is going to handle
the form ... we are going to call that 'search_ tmdb'[= form_
tag : action => 'search_ tmdb' do]. Here is the label for the
form that we are going to create in haml [% label{: for =>
'search_ terms'} Search Terms. The next slide is what does this
look like in html.
= text_ field_ tag 'search_ terms'
=
submit_ tag 'Search TMDb This haml gets turned into this
code:
Search
Terms
This will be able to implement the form for us. That is the
view. Now if you were to try it ... when we do try it, it will
say it is missing the route, so I am just going to go through
this slowly. We have to add a route in movies_ controller. rb.
What we could do, it would be to build the method that can
handle all this. Both ... when it fails, if it does not work, it
will give an error message, but it can go out into TMD and find
that. Unfortunately, what you would really do is start using
Test Driven Development, which we have not talked about yet.
What we will do right now is just do the sad path by having a
fake method that is just going to always fail. This method will
never find a movie, but it will let the sad path pass. What
Armando will do in a couple of lectures sooner, he will
implement the happy path, where it goes out and search TMDb. The
problem is you go back and forth from BDD and TDD, but
pedagogically, we have to them one at a time, so we will just do
BDD today. This is going to be the route that we need to be able
to make the connection. post '/ movies/ search_ tmdb' We are
going to add this to routes. rb and then here is our dummy
method, and you can see just what Armando talked about, we are
going to use the flash.
[ flash[ : warning] = " '{ params[:
search_ terms]} '  was not found in TMDB. We are going to use it
as a warning rather than notice and it is going to give the
error message there and this is our method that we are going to
do that.