Which statements are true regarding routes. They consist of both
a URI and an HTTP method. You need both pieces to make the route
unique. It must be generated using these URI helpers. It may be
generated by these URI helpers. Clearly B and C are not both
true so you know notice that they don't appear in choice, but of
the four choices, voting ... I'm going to call it nearly
unanimous for blue, module like three or four people, but let's
walk through which of A, B and C are true. A route consists of
both a URI and a method. That's absolutely true, and in fact, we
saw that when we did rake routes up here ... I'll just do it
again so we can read the output. We already saw that we have ...
here's two examples of routes that are distinct, right. They
called different controller actions. The URL part of the route
is the same, but the HTTP method is different, and that makes
them distinct. It is true that you need both the URL part and
the HETP methods, so A is true. What about B versus C? Well,
remember from the web browser's point of view, the only thing
the web browser knows about is URLs. It doesn't care how that
URL got into the view, it just cares that when you click on it,
it knows what URL to send you to. The idea that there's these
helpers to help you generate the URLs, that's a Rails thing that
it provides because it is nice. You don't have to use them,
although life is often easier if you do use them. At the end of
the day when it gets to the web browser, it won't make any
difference. The web browser has no concept of restfulness, of
URIs or helpers or anything like that. All it knows is you click
on a link, there better be an H- reft that tells me where to go.
That is it.