Let's talk about actual object orientation in Ruby. I've kept
saying this mantra, everything is an object, everything is a
method call, Ruby's a dynamic language, so the question is, why
should you actually care about this? How does it actually
simplify object- oriented programming? Let's look at a simple
example to walk through. I'm going to define a savings account
and hypothetically I'm going to say it inherits from an existing
class called account, although we don't have an existing class.
I just wanted to show you the syntax for inheritance. Of course,
I need a constructor, and in Ruby, the constructor for a class
by default is called initialize. Why is it called initialize,
but you call it with new? It's just the way the world is. Sorry,
kids. What is this initializer going to do? It's going to take
one argument which is the initial balance, and note that because
of giving the argument an optional value or a default value in
the function definition, I can actually call the new function
with no arguments and balance will default to zero. So you can
have optional arguments with default values in Ruby as well.
When I call the constructor, it's going to take the balance that
I passed in and assign it to an instance variable. Long ago, in
a previous lecture, we said that instance variables begin with a
single @ sign, so @ balance is an instance variable, not to be
confused with just plain balance, no @ sign. That's just a plain
old local variable that disappears once we're no longer in the
scope of the function. So that's the only thing the constructor
does. Now we have a local variable or instance variable in Java
terminology to track the value of our account balance, but of
course, we need to be able to get access to that. Unlike Java
and some other languages, there's no notion of a public
attribute. This instance variable, @ balance, is visible only
from within this specific instance of the object. If somebody
outside the object, and certainly outside of the class, wants to
get access to that information, you have to define an accessor
for it. So here's my simple accessor. Wow, I hope you got that.
All it does is return ... and by the way, in Ruby functions, if
there's no explicit return statement, the value of the last
expression evaluated in the function is the return value.
Everything has a return value and if you don't say return, what
you get is the last expression evaluated. So there's my really
simple accessor, or getter, if you prefer. I also need a way
maybe to set the balance. Who knows? Maybe I'd like to launder
money into my bank account. Here's another function, and yes,
balance= is the name of a method. Remember I said everything is
a method call? This is where we're starting to get serious.
Balance= is a different method from balance. There's a special
case in Ruby for methods that end in the equal sign and that's
how you can define your own setters. So balance= will take a new
amount and it'll just set the instance variable to that. Of
course, real bank accounts are not quite this easy to add money
to yourself, so we'll get more realistic in a moment. We can
also deposit. That's easy enough, we just add the deposit amount
on to the instance variable balance. We can also have class
variables. Something like the name of the bank might be a
variable that is independent of any particular instance and we
get those with the double @@ sign. Again, class variables are
accessible from within the class. If we wanted to have access to
that variable from outside the class, we would have to design a
specific getter for it, and here would be an example of that
getter. Notice the difference in how we define it. We define
self. bank_ name. The reason this works, and this is going to
take a little bit of getting used to, is because once we've
started this declaration class, inside of this declaration, the
value of self is the new class being created. So, if we say def
self. some method name, all we're really saying is we're really
defining this method on the class itself as opposed to these
methods which are being defined on an instance of the class.
Right on? We'll just return the bank name. Notice that we're not
providing a setter for the bank name class variable, so you
can't set it. An alternative to saying self. bank_ name is we
could also put the name of the class. bank_ name. Why is that?
Because inside of a class definition, the value of self is
exactly the new class that you're in the process of creating.
That's the end of our class definition. In a moment, I'm going
to fire up the Ruby interpreter so that we can actually try
these examples live in real life, but before we do that, let's
test your recollection here. Remember that I said, remember,
everything is an object, everything is a method call, a. b ...
okay. Which ones of these are a correct way of getting access to
the balance of a bank account instance? Let's do a quick initial
vote. Quick initial vote. You guys are quick. You guys are
quick. A sea of blue is what I see. Let's discuss the answer.
What's wrong with A? Volunteer from the audience. What is
manifestly wrong with A? One possibility is you can't directly
access @ balance and while that is true, there's an even more
superficial reason why the first one's wrong. Sir? There's no
method called @ balance. There's no method called @ balance. A.
b always means call method b on object a. Method names don't
ever begin with an @ sign, only instance variable names can
begin with an @ sign. So on its face, a just doesn't work. It's
not even syntactically legal. B and c are equivalent, except
that one of them omits the optional parentheses around the
method call to balance, and that's it. So, back into our
discussion, I am now going to actually take some code and paste
it into the Ruby interpreter. I also took the liberty of
creating three accounts we can play with, my account with $
1,000, Dave's with $ 5,000, and Bill Gates with a lot more than
either of us. So we'll come back to that. Now you know instance
variables. You know that you have define explicit getters and
setters on instance variables. On the other hand, the getters
and setters that we defined are pretty darn trivial, and it
would be nice ... this to me, as soon as you start seeing stuff
like this where you've read this method and now you know what's
coming, this is a sign that the language isn't supporting you.
Might there be a more concise way? If these accessors and
setters are such a common case, shouldn't there be a way to
support them that is a little more elegant and indeed there is.
Let me do that again. Old way. New way. I just made code
disappear. What is this magic attr_ accessor thing? It's not
part of the language. It is just a regular old method call, and
in a moment, we're going to start talking more about
metaprogramming, which is code that defines and writes and runs
new code at runtime, and one thing I said when I began
introducing Ruby is, I'm only going to talk about these
highfalutin language features because I believe they help you
write cleaner code that is easier to read and understand. This
is an example. In fact, in the next homework assignment, one of
the things you're going to do is you're going to essentially
create your own more sophisticated version of attr_ accessor.
But when you say attr_ accessor  : balance, what you're saying
is please create for me these two methods, a default getter and
a default setter, that just do the obvious thing. You can figure
out how it does it. If you had to print out the text of those
two methods based on attr_ accessor, you could do it. The
difference is, in Ruby, pretty much if you can print it out at
runtime, you can also execute it at runtime, and that's very
cool. So, a quick review of Ruby's distinguishing features that
we've seen. First of all, it is object- oriented in the extreme.
Even the lowliest integers are objects. There's really no such
things as attributes. There's instance variables, but you have
to define explicit getters and setters because you have to get
at them through methods. Everything is a method call. Usually
the only thing you care about in a method call is whether the
receiver responds to the method you're trying to send it, and
we'll have a lot more to say about that in a moment when we
shortly talk about duck typing. We've talked about the fact that
objects can have different types, but the variables that refer
to those objects are not typed. As we'll see, most of the
expressions that we've seen are non- destructive, so we gave
examples of like adding strings together, adding arrays
together. We're going to see some functions that let you select
and remove elements and rearrange arrays. In almost all cases,
with a few exceptions that we'll identify, those functions don't
modify the receiver. They return a new copy of an object. That's
part of Ruby's heritage as being functionally flavored from the
functional programming community.