Speaker 1: Our next topic is one of the areas, at the same
time, one of the powerful things about Ruby and also one of
things that people new to the language get a little tripped up
on because there are features that are not nearly as common in
other modern languages that most people are using. Certainly not
so in Java, a little bit in Python but even there not so much.
Let's talk about blocks and iterators and the functional idioms
that they enable. Functional programming, if you have the good
fortune to take a course that no longer really exist here. It's
called structure and interpretation of computer programs. It
used to be taught in a language called Scheme. That course among
other things had an introduction to a really deep idea called
functional programming that has been in the languages community
for a long time. Some people including me think it doesn't
always get the airplay that it should. What we're going to talk
about in the next few minutes here is how can techniques from
functional programming actually help us rethink some pretty
basic programming concepts, for example, iteration, something we
do so often we take it for granted. We do for loops, we traverse
data structures. More importantly, why should we care? Why is it
worth rethinking our approaches to some of these pretty
fundamental programming constructs? Let's just start up with
some examples. As usual, you'll get used to seeing the examples
and you'll quickly come to realize as you use the language more
why these are valuable things that you can do. Here's a
collection of three things, an apple, a banana and a cherry,
it's just an array of three strings and I can say with each
string just print it. That looks like a loop. The tendency, if
you come from an emperative language like Java is to say, “ I
get it. That's like a way of writing a for loop over the array
elements.” It's not. Take it on its own merits, it's each.
Here's a collection and with each element of the collection do
something. Let's do a couple of more examples to drive that
home. You could do this but that's really just syntactic sugar
for something that's more like this. What's going on here? What
is this up to business? We know it's a method call, we know it's
a method on an integer. We know it's a method call that takes
one argument. It can be followed by a block. A block is just a
lambda expression, it's a procedure that has no name. In this
case it's a procedure of one argument, num. What it does it just
print out that num. Really, that's what it is. It's a procedure,
it's a function call and what I'm really saying is I'm going to
generate a list of numbers and for each one of them I'm going to
call a function passing that one thing as an argument. Here's
another shortcut that Ruby provides, rah, rah, rah. I've also in
this case substituted braces for do and and. Less common of an
idiom but sometimes you'll see it. Don't be too confused. There
we go, sorry about that. Don't be confused if you see the idiom
of substituting braces as opposed to substituting braces for do-
and. What's going on on all these other examples? I mentioned
this briefly in a previous lecture, what all of these examples
have in common is that we're allowing the objectives manage
their own traversal. In this case, we have a range of objects,
the integers one through 10 and we're saying, traverse yourself
and for each element that you give me back in the traversal, I'm
going to provide a function that you call with that element as
an argument. An anonymous function, an anonymous lambda
expression. Your friends would be really impressed if you used
that world regularly in a conversation. They'll also stop
inviting you to parties. Whatever. That's an example of range
traversal. What about this thing with arrays? Well, we saw that
we could take an array and say for each element in the array,
again, I'm going to give you a function and you're going to call
that function with each of the array elements. What's
interesting between these is that you have no idea as a
programmer internally what mechanism is being used to grab each
element and provide it to you. You're giving that responsibility
over to the target. You can do a similar thing with hashes.
Remember that hashes have keys and values. There's actually a
couple of different constructs provided for going through the
key value pairs. You can say for each key, give me that key and
do something or you could say for each key value pair, because
the anonymous function can take more than one argument and can
take zero arguments in fact. Again, the simple example I gave
before, 10. times, that's really just a short hand for something
like this except that it's an iterator of arity zero, it takes
no arguments because if we're saying 10 times, presumably you
don't' care about the value of the index. If you cared about the
value of the index you would do something like one of these
first cases. What this leads to is something that a lot of Ruby
programmers call expression orientation. You don't think in
terms of, “ I'm going to do something to this collection.”
Instead you think in terms of, “ Hey collection, I'm going to
ask you for things and I'm going to do things to your elements.”
For example, I can have a collection x which is just an array of
strings and I can say, “ Sort yourself.” I can say, “ Take your
unique elements.” which by the way, what is that do, it returns
a copy. X is not modified here, no x's have been harmed in the
preparation of any of these examples. I'm getting a new copy
which is x with the replicated elements removed and then I'm
going to reverse that. I get banana, cherry, apple. There are
versions of some of these that are dangerous. Remember, I said
that sometimes, if you see a function name that ends with bang,
it means this function is dangerous or it may have side effects,
so use with care. In some cases like reverse, there's variant
that ends in bang that does modify the receiver. X reverse bang,
or x reverse actually means x will be modified. There's also a
map. If you use language like Python or even Scheme, map is, for
each element of the array, I'm going to do something to each
element and the result is to return a new thing. Whereas the
result ... before, when we're traversing the elements, we're
just saying, “ Here's a function call and it's going to do
something with each element.” Map goes further and says ...
actually, the result of overall map is a new collection in which
each element is the result of calling the anonymous lambda. In
this example, I take my original collection of fruits and for
each element in the collection I'm going to call reverse which
reverses the string, which turns a new copy of the string with
the elements reversed. The result of this intermediate step is
just an array in which each of the words has been individually
reversed. By the way, since the result of the overall map is
itself a new collection, I can call sort on that. What you'll
see in Ruby is you'll see A. B. C. D, you build up a list of
things you want to do. It's almost like a UNIX pipeline, but the
idea that everything returns a copy of something and has a
value, it evaluates as an expression and then you can continue
to do more things on that expression. That way of thinking
really comes from functional programming. We're going to see
some cases where it's very, very useful. Here's another one that
reve provides, collect which says, “ Give me every element of
your collection and I'm going to collect all the elements for
which this function returns a true value.” One thing that you
can test for is whether a string includes a character. You can
test whether an array includes a character. In a moment we'll
talk about why things like include seem to work all over the
place with many different classes. I can ask, “ Is it the case
that any of these elements satisfies a particular condition?”
There's a real life example of it. I would suggest you check out
offline because I don't want to take the time to walk through it
on this video. Just to give you a preview of it, I'll just show
you the code, we're not going to walkthrough in depth right now.
Anybody have a clipper card who lives in the Bay area, it's your
public transit card and you can check your balance online and
things like that. I wanted to write a script that would
basically let me go to a single URL and check my balance without
having to login to their website which I'm not a huge fan of. I
use the library called Mechanize which lets you write scripts
against your remote web server. I created a new mechanized
object. I post to the URL of the clipper site with my username
and password. Notice the dot at the end of every one of these
lines. This is all one line. Remember, I said A. B. C. I'm
calling a variety of different methods to build up this
expression. I'm posting a form. The result of posting form is
whatever their site sends back then I'm going to look for a link
that has this H ref, click on that link, parse the resulting
page looking for these HTML elements. Go to the first row of the
table, go to the second, third column and look for content that
matches a dollar sign followed by a decimal amount and return
HTML. That's one statement kids. I'm not saying that was
beautiful code, don't get me wrong. I needed something quick and
dirty that would work. The fact that I was able to write that in
such a compact way is really what I'm talking about.