Okay, vote. Vote, vote, vote. Statements that are false ...
okay, we're just going to go through it. Most people got this
right. I should have guessed that a crowd that has done a fair
amount of programming would certainly not buy into number 3,
that testing eliminates the need to use a debugger and indeed,
you're right about that. Testing does not eliminate the need to
use of debugger. However, what I hope that I've persuaded you of
is that it eliminates many unproductive uses of a debugger.
Sometimes you really will be in a quandary as to why your simple
test case and your simple code are not behaving the way you
should and that's when the debugger comes out but you shouldn't
be using it for most of that. Most of your actual debugging
really should be in the form of writing tests that fail. That's
your bug. Then you write the code that fixes the bug. As we'll
see when we talk about how you close out bugs in other people's
code, it's actually the same process. All of these ideas are
going to come back when we do bug fixing, when we do legacy code
refactoring, all this stuff, the idea of test cases that cover
you knowing that that's the target of where you're going to
focus your bug fixing efforts. We're going to see this over and
over again.