So we're gonna try the three by five cards here alright so the
actual model the way it works see if people get a variety of
answers this time is if we disagree then we'll have to talk
about yourselves and vote again as a pair So what is the weakest
argument these are all arguments for Google app's popularity is
which of these four you think is the weakest so don't lose data
in gmail cooperating group and drive or you know Google
documents a large changing dataset YouTube or no field upgrade
when you improve the app so I want you think about a few seconds
and then pick a card hold up and I'll see if there's
disagreements here okay ready set okay this where you vote on
your own pick everybody has a card everybody must have a card
the colors. I see a wide variety of colors so then what we do
next is talk to the person next to you and if you agree that's
easy if you disagree talk it over and try to convince other with
red one and then you the pair you vote on a single card   okay
let's let's trying trying vote so there should be either both of
you hold the same card or one hold hands with the card or
something like that ready set vote Uh bunch lots of oranges yeah
pretty much all the colors so this one is there probably be more
definite this is a matter of of opinion so don't lose data gmail
I think that's a pretty good reason cooperating groups that's
our group on we go to Google docs that's because a bunch of us
are gonna work on it together a large changing dataset You Tube
is one exabyte video exabyte I think that's about a million
terabytes right that's amazing no field upgrade when improve the
app well that is the benefit of search but at least to my taste
probably the main reason for search is that they have petabytes
of information that they collected web everywhere and probably
that's the stronger reason to search but but this is this one is
really kind of argue you know you can argue about what's the
right answer here so that it's not a single answer