A few last words about testing from the plan- and- document
perspective. We added a lot of stuff about the plan- and-
document perspective recently in the book because we wanted to
make sure that we're not perceived as sending the message that
Agile is always the right way to do things and it's the only way
to do things. In fact, there's a lot of testing activity in
plan- and- document. In fact, one of the criticisms of plan-
and- document in a classroom setting is that people feel there's
so much of that that they don't get to actually write any code.
We've seen that in the BDD/ TDD Agile extreme approach. We write
the test before the code. We start from user stories. The
developers are responsible for, generally speaking, for writing
tests that go along with their own code. The question is, what
happens in a plan- and- document setting for these same tasks?
There's a very important role in the P& D family of approaches.
There's a project manager who documents the project management
plan, which includes a software requirements spec, SRS, and in
case you were wondering, yes, there is a standard for how you
write an SRS. The standard itself is actually tens of pages. The
SRS is enormous and the idea is that that captures the
requirements. It captures the test plan and then once you've got
this overall plan, you're going to now divide the plan into
programming units and essentially assign different teams to work
on each unit. Teams of different developers are assigned to
different units. They do their own unit testing, but when it
comes to putting a lot of pieces of together and doing system
and integration tests, there's often a separate QA team that
does that. There's different ways that the QA team can do its
job. One way is you try to do top down integration. This is more
like what we think of as user stories, where you look at the top
level, or the customer's view, as what the app should do and
that drives you to get some of the customer- facing
functionality working early on so you can start testing it. On
the other hand, it means you have to do a lot of stubbing below
that level, so the customer- facing things have something to do.
It's the equivalent of doing a wireframe but with code. You
could also go the other way and say we're going to build out the
pieces and we're going to test as we go and as we put the pieces
together, but that means that the customer- facing part actually
might not be testable for quite some time. In this approach, you
have the benefit that you're relying a lot less on stubs. As we
all know, the problem with relying on stubs is if the stubs get
out sync with reality, then your stub tests will all be passing,
but the reality may turn out to be that they fail. The downside
of the second approach is it's very late in the game before you
can really put the pieces together and start getting rid of the
stubs. Sandwich integration tries to go from both ends. You work
downwards from the customer- facing stuff and stub where you
need. You work upwards from the unit test and you start putting
modules together. The idea is that at any given point in time,
you have at least some customer- facing things that actually
might talk to real app code, the rest of them are being stubbed
but they're working toward each other. It's like digging a
tunnel from both ends, so you try to get it both ways. When
you're ready to do the more serious testing, you turn it over to
the QA team. They are the ones who are doing the system test and
at this point, they're really testing the whole app. They are
also testing non- functional requirements, which we're going to
talk about when we talk about operations. Things like
performance, are there performance targets they have to meet,
targets of robustness in terms of defending the data in the app
against malicious attacks. How do they know when they're done?
It depends on the project. In some cases, it's based on things
like coverage and metrics. We saw different versions of
coverage. They are not only about the control paths followed,
but things like define and use coverage, which talk about data
production and data consumption, have you tested all of those
paths. Once the QA team has signed off, now the customer gets to
test it. You can see why the Agile methodology tends to put the
customer first. The amount of work that has happened by the time
the user acceptance test comes is pretty much everything in the
project. The assumption is, the customer is going to like it by
the time it's done. This is the validation versus
verification, " Did I build the right thing as opposed to did I
just build the thing right?" It may turn out that in the user
acceptance test, the customer changes their mind. Again, it's
not that Agile is good for all projects and it's not that Agile
does things fundamentally differently in terms of which tasks
are involved compared to plan- and- document, but the tasks are
factored into a different order and you carve them off in small
chunks. You do use mocks, you do write unit test, you do
integration tests, you do put the product in front of the
customer, but you do that for small slices at a time and then
you come back and do another slice. As we all know, we saw it
very early on that testing can be used to show the presence of
bugs, but never the absence of bugs. Again, what do we do when
we can't do testing? Formal methods have been ... yeah, I know,
Dave made the animations for these slides. I can't take credit
for the happy dancing robots. Formal methods are a completely
different approach to program correctness. Basically, testing is
about engineering. Testing is you've got this code artifact and
you want to see what it does. Formal methods actually take a
formal representation of the program and they try to prove some
things just based on the formal specification. For example, you
might want to guarantee that it can never enter a certain state.
In fact, this is gaining traction in industry in both hardware
and software. As late as last decade, Intel, for example, was
using formal verification to model the bus protocols for their
multiprocessor systems. Because what you want to do is prove
that, for example, you can never have a sequence of events that
results in a bus deadlock. There's a big issue, which is that
often the formal spec is not necessarily a thing from which you
can generate program code. You may have proven that the formal
spec is correct in the sense that it never goes into these bad
states, but you still have to prove that the thing that gets
built also follows the formal spec, and that's a different
problem. A human might be able to do these proofs, but more
commonly computers do them using theorem proving. You can also
use model checking which is a combination of symbolic execution
and checking to whether ... what sequence of states might be
reachable, depending on input values and control paths. These
are pretty computationally expensive. They tend to be used on
smaller- size systems, on systems that are expensive to repair,
because, for example, they might be out in space or they're
difficult to test. Safety critical software systems are usually
a good candidate for these. Just to give you some metrics, the
largest project that I know about that's been formally verified
is the L4 operating system kernel, that's about 10,000 lines of
code, and the research effort required comes out to about $ 500
per line of code. NASA has managed to beat that. The space
shuttle software costs about $ 80 per line of code per year to
maintain. It doesn't change very much and the process for
changing it is extremely heavy weight, but there has never
really been a software failure in the space shuttle program,
ever. The methods do work if you apply them correctly. Since we
are doing software that is relatively easy to change, easy to
repair and relatively easy to test, we won't be doing very much
in terms of the formal methods, but I would say if you're going
to the software engineering field, within 5 years, you can
expect these to be widely used across many companies. Summing
up. In the plan- and- document world and versus the Agile world,
we actually are doing all of the same things. We're creating
customer specs, user stories and so forth, but the order in
which we do them is really what's different and how the teams
are factored to do them. Rather than having a top down plan and
a project manager, we're doing things piece by piece and row by
row. Let's, very quickly, do a formal methods statement, then we
have three minutes to do, a fun thing. Which statement regarding
testing is false? Formal methods are expensive, but worthwhile
for important applications. In P& D development efforts,
developers code before they write test, which is the opposite of
agile. Agile developers perform module integration, system
acceptance test, but P& D developers generally don't do this
themselves, and sandwich integration tries to get the best of
both worlds, reducing the number of stubs while getting some
general functionality going early. Which is false?