What do we mean when we say all programming is metaprogramming?
What are metaprogramming and reflection? They're $ 20 words. It
should make you feel smarter to use them, but reflection means
we can ask an object questions about itself at runtime. We can
have it modify itself at runtime, and metaprogramming means when
we write code whose job is to write new code that at runtime
actually causes interesting things to happen. The question is,
are these just $ 20 words to make you feel smarter or do they
play some role in making your code more dry and more concise or
otherwise easier to read. Of course, I wouldn't be explaining it
unless there was an affirmative answer to that question, so to
illustrate it, let's modify a bank account to make it
international. We want to be able to deposit other currencies.
We can already say, deposit $ 100. It'd be nice if we could
deposit, let's say Euros, so we could deposit Euros to dollars (
20), but that's pretty ugly. That looks like something a
programmer might write. Twenty Euros is like a dollar in today's
currency or something. Okay, so that's ugly. What else might we
do. If we were in a traditional object-oriented language,
we might be forced into something like this, substantiating a
currency converter ... yeah, I know, right? Groan with me.
That's terrible. So, that's not beautiful. We're all about
trying to write beautiful code. So what would we like to be able
to say? What would be a more readable version of what we want to
do? That's dollars. How about that for Euros? That's pretty
clear what you want to do. This is no problem in Ruby because
one of the nice things about a dynamic language is that we have
open classes. That means that we can modify, not only creating
our own classes, but modifying and extending the classes that
Ruby ships with. How would we do this? We already know
everything is a method call, right? So if we write this, we're
saying that Euros must be a method that we can invoke on the
receiver 20. That makes it an instance method of the numeric
class. No problem. We open the class. We define our Euros
according to an exchange rate that is what we call 'the good ol'
days' in the United States, and we're done. Does this really
work? Let's try it. I reopened the class. I added a method.
Pretty cool. Before you gasp in further astonishment, let's go
further than this. What about that? What about that? This is
problematic because our function is called Euros, not Euro.
There's a dry solution to that, but to motivate the solution
further, let's try something even more ambitious. Let's go
beyond that and say, I also want to support other currencies.
But it'd be kind of wasteful if all I'm really dealing with is a
list of currency names and conversion factors. I don't really
want to write end separate methods that look like my three- line
method, so surely there's a drier way to do this. There is in
fact a drier way to do this, and here's one possible solution.
I've reopened the class numeric just like before, but now I have
a more general ... here's my hash, which just maps currency
names to conversion factors, no surprises there. This is the
cool part. One of the facilities in Ruby is called method
missing, so method missing gets called when you call a method on
the receiver and the receiver doesn't know any method by that
name, but if you've defined a method called method missing in
your class, it will receive the call instead. Method missing is
passed up to three arguments. The first one is the actual name
of the method you tried to call, but which doesn't appear to
exist, a list of the arguments that that method would have
received if it existed, and optionally a block. We'll learn a
lot more about blocks shortly, but because most Ruby methods are
written so that they can take a block as an argument, there's
the possibility that our method could be allowed to as well.
What method missing does in our case is, it looks at the method
ID, converts it to a string, gets rid of any final S ...
remember we had the problem of wanting to be able to call 1.
Euro as well as 1. Euros ... so we're basically going to
canonicalize the name of a currency to its singular, and then we
just ask whether we already have a key for that currency and we
convert it. Minds are slowly being blown. I can feel it. I can
feel it from across the screen that minds are being blown. Let's
actually see what happens here when we do this. I will copy that
code. I'm back in the interpreter. Hmm. So what's going on here
if I do something like ... this didn't work, right?. So what
went wrong here? Method missing got called, right? In fact, the
debugger is helpfully telling us that where things went sour is
in method missing. Here's my method missing that I defined.
Here's the problem right here, right? We don't have a key in our
currencies array for pound, so that fails, and when that fails,
what happens? Then I call, I try to basically punt up to my
super class. As in all object-oriented languages, there is
the idea that if you don't have a function, but your super class
or one of your ancestor classes does have it, it gets control.
Well, Ruby has the same thing with the difference that method
missing is called first, so before my ancestor gets a chance to
handle it, I get a chance to handle it using method missing. So
this is a nice extensible way to do the thing that we were
trying to do before. Get it? Dry. So what does this mean?
Reflection and metaprogramming are not just these fancy big
concepts. You can ask Ruby objects questions about themselves at
runtime. For example, method missing gets to look at the name of
the method that would have been called and the arguments that
that method would have received. We can use that information to
generate new code at runtime. That's what attr_ accessor is
exactly doing, right? It's creating, on the fly, getters and
setters for instance variables, which means you can have code
that writes code, and as we just saw, you can reopen any class,
whether it's your own or whether it's one of Ruby's built in-
classes, at any time, and you can add stuff to it or you can
modify what it does. Now, one of the things about Ruby that when
I first explain this to people who come from another language,
one reaction that is very common is, " Oh, my gosh, that's
chaos. You mean you could reopen any class and if I'm working
with somebody's code, I don't really know if a string is a
string or if it's a special kind of string, and if I call a
method and they've got all kinds of method missing hooks, then
I'm not really calling the method that I thought I was calling,
that's chaos." Here's my message to you. You're all grownups. At
least I assume most of you are grownups, and with great power
comes great responsibility, right? Any language that gives you
enough rope to hang yourself, demands that you have a certain
amount of taste in when it's good to do this. If in doubt, you
can ask somebody who's more experienced. You can look at other
people's code, and it's true that there are some abuses of these
features as there are with any good features. Any good
technology can be used for good or evil purposes. We will try to
present examples of good purposes that lead to beautiful code,
but things like code review, pair programming and so on are
going to help us avoid some of the worst excesses that would
lead to poor usages and/ or abuses of these features.