Next stop is explicit versus implicit and imperative versus
declarative, so different types of scenarios and different ways
to think about scenarios. The motivation slide that we try to
start off everything with is are all the requirements come
directly from user stories? We said scenarios are from three to
eight. How do we keep them closer to three rather than more like
eight so that it doesn't take as long to write them, it doesn't
take as long to understand them? In terms of the outcome from
the user stories, that gets referred to as explicit versus
implicit scenarios. The explicit ones are the things that come
directly from the user, from the customer. They are basically
acceptance test. We added search TMDD. That is to list all the
movies. That's examples of things that the customer want to see
in the page. Things that the customer doesn't maybe care about
would be like that in example when you list them, you list them
in the order that they were entered or in alphabetical order or
chronological order by when the movie came out. Maybe the
customer doesn't really care so you're going to have to figure
out what to do. That's an example of an implicit story. Just
keep that in mind. There are some things that come directly from
the three by five card and some things you're going to figure
out, the customer asking questions all the time. Now when we've
been writing these things up, we've been writing in what's
called an imperative way. Here's a given state and here's a
sequence of steps to get us to this next state so we're ready to
do the test that we want to see, to see if it's doing acceptance
test as we want to do. If a lot of your user stories are
imperative, a lot of them will have the very same steps. Once
again, [ inaudible 00:01:55] goes off, we see a lot of the same
things. There must be some way to try and avoid this because we
want to not repeat ourselves. Basically, the way to try and do
this is what's called declarative, declarative approaches which
is that is we're going to try and say the state we want it to
be. If you think about declarative programming languages versus
imperative programming languages, that's inspirations of these
names. This should take a lot fewer steps. Let me try and make
this concrete. I'm going to talk about listing the movies
alphabetically. I'm going to show you first how you do it
imperatively in a lot of steps and then show you how to do
declaratively. How are we going to say it's in alphabetical
order? What we're going to do is go through these steps. Here is
the imperative approach. Given I'm on the Rotten Potatoes home
page and then I follow add a new movie and then I fill in the
title Zorro and press save changes, then that should be on the
Rotten Potatoes home page and add a new movie and add the title
Apocalypse Now and then give it a rating and I save changes. I
should be in the Rotten Potatoes home page and I should see
Apocalypse Now before Zorro. That was a lot of steps to write,
to go through, to create changes from the state that I wanted
was originally into the state of one of these so I could do this
one test here. That's the behavior I'm after, that it's in
alphabetical order. Remember the BDD, the B in BDD is about
behavior. It seems like it's a little weird that we're trying to
describe behavior. We do it imperatively like you're
implementing it. The idea here is to think of it as making a
domain language, not a domain specific language but a domain
language. You try and come up, think of it in terms of your
applications, in terms of the feature you want to do and the
concepts. This is just an informal language. You're trying to
write the declarative steps in this language. Your step
definitions will define those. How about a declarative version
of the scenario for keeping things in alphabetical might look
like. The feature's the same. View the list after adding a
movie. Given I have added Zorro with a rating, that's just
describing the state that I wanted it to be. Given I have added
Apocalypse Now with a rating, then I should see Apocalypse now
before Zorro. That's a lot better. That's three steps versus 15
steps. One step of those three steps is behavior. That's a lot
better. Declarative scenarios are focused on behavior being
tested rather than steps needs to set up the test. How are we
going to do this? The way we're going to do this is some more
step definitions. The next slide gives you an example. Here's a
step definition, [ inaudible 00:04:49] declaratively. Basically,
you're taking the single step and turning it into a bunch of
smaller steps. Remember we said a step is like a method call and
a step definition is like a method definition. You could think
of that just like we've done it. You do this hierarchically. You
use code. Similarly, you can do that with steps and step
definitions. This example on the left, that's handling the given
statement, given I want to add this movie and it takes these
steps, these more imperative steps in the side. The idea here is
that you may get started writing imperatively but you should
start minding them to try and make step definitions or method
definitions out of them so you could [ inaudible 00:05:33] so
you don't have to write as much codes. You'll start off
imperatively and hopefully migrate to declaratively. With that,
we're ready to see how this works. Let me read this. What's true
about these types of scenarios, implicit and explicit, and
declarative versus imperative. Explicit requirements are usually
defined with imperative scenarios and implicit requirements are
usually defined with declarative scenarios. Explicit scenarios
usually capture integration tests. Declarative scenarios aim to
capture implementation as well as behavior. All of these are
false.