We've talked about a simple protocol between clients and
servers. We've talked about the idea that URIs and HTTP name the
thing you want to get. The next logical thing to talk about is
what is that you return to the browser? Everybody has sort of
seen HTML through osmosis, I guess. Just to remind you where we
are here, we are still in a second level, but now we are going
to look at what happens on the client side. So far we've been
looking mostly at the server side of this picture. The goal of
HTML really is to get from this by adding this into something
like this. Really simply HTML is a markup language. That means
that believe it or not, despite what you may have seen on other
websites, it's really supposed to describe the structure of text
on a webpage, not the visual appearance of text. That's a
different job. The Hypertext Markup Language actually has a
fairly long and illustrious history, which we won't cover,
except to tell you that it's a descendant of a markup language
that IBM invented in the ‘ 60s for reading business documents,
for making business documents that could be machine- readable.
An HTML document is really a hierarchy of elements. That means
that an element can contain other elements as its children. Some
of these elements represent content that is sort of inline right
on the page like text, headings, tables, paragraphs. Sometimes
the tags represent embedded content, things that are separate
from the page itself but can be loaded in conjunction with it
like images or JavaScript code. Sometimes the tags represents
forms, which provide a way for the user to give input and click
on buttons and fill in text, which can then be supplied to the
server in order to get it to do something. Elements in HTML are
surrounded or delimited by tags. A tag appears in angle
brackets, a closed tag has an angle bracket and a slash. Some of
the tags have content. For example, here is a paragraph or P-
tag whose content is the string " Hello World." Some have
attributes. For example, here is an image tag that has an
attribute source that tells the browser where the image is
located. Some tags have both attributes as well as content.
Because it's a hierarchy of elements, tags can usually include
other tags as well. Now, of the various attributes the tags
could have, two that we are going to focus on, because they are
particularly useful when it comes to describing the structure of
a page in a way that allows you to style it easily is the ID and
Class attributes. The reason we care about them in part is
because we do want to control the visual appearance of our
webpages and we want to make them look nice. We want to do that
in a way that respects the structure of the page. As we will
see, there is many reasons to keep the structural and the visual
concerns completely separate. Cascading Style Sheets or CSS
helps us do that. The way we use Cascading Style Sheets is we
will put identifying link element at the top of our page. In
fact it goes inside the Head elements, one of the children of
Head that says, " This is a style sheet and this is the URI that
you download the style sheet from." The style sheet is just a
URI accessible web resource like anything else. Among the most
commonly used HTML elements when we are talking about CSS are
the ID and Class elements because they give us a very compact
way to quickly identify an element or group of elements to which
we want to apply a common set of visual styles. In this simple
example, I have a Div element, which is a way of identifying
different parts of the document structurally, and I’ m giving it
an ID of " right" and a Class of " content." The ID has to be
unique within the page, so nowhere else on this page can I have
any element of any kind that has the same ID " right" as this
Div element. The Class could be attached to many elements. It
can even be attached to elements of different types. It would be
perfectly fine to have many other elements on this page that
also share the content Class. How do we use these? Well, in
general we use CSS Selectors as a way to identify what elements
we want to apply some visual styling to. Here is a very simple
example that we can use as the basis of showing how some
Selectors work. The simplest way we can select an element is by
the tag name. This Selector says any elements that have an H1
tag, no matter what Class or ID they might have and that paints
a pretty broad stroke. That's usually more general than you
want. We can also restrict it to say only elements that have a
certain class, so in this case class pageFrame that would only
match this Div out here or we can match an element with a unique
ID. Remember that we said the page head, in this case the ID has
to be unique on the page. Only one element can have a page head
ID and sure enough it's the same Div. Now, in this case I have
written two different Selectors both of which could match this
outer Div. In general, you need to be careful of not doing that
in your CSS files because then you have to worry about
complicated rules regarding which set of rules gets applied when
multiple rules match. If you are using a good CSS editor
program, they will usually warn you if you accidentally do
something like this. We could also use the tag name combined
with the Class, so this would match any Div elements that have
an ID of page frame, or we could use the tag name and ID, but as
you have no doubt already realized that's usually redundant,
why? Because if an ID has to be unique on the page, then only
one element can have this ID anyway, so why bother saying the
element tag? The reason you would do that is really informative.
For the designer who is looking at the CSS file wanting to make
changes, this notation tells them specifically that the
welcome … the element whose ID is welcome is usually an image
element. That's useful because there are some styles that only
make sense to apply to certain element types. The more
interesting version of Selectors allows you to use descendent
relationships. For example, I can say, I want to match any
element that has the Cust Name Class, but only if it's inside of
an element that matches Div. In our example, we have got a Div
element out here, and inside one of its children actually does
have the CSS class. In our case, this entire Span element is
what will be matched by Div space Cust Name. If we don't specify
any styling for an element, then whatever its parent element
gets it inherits those attributes by default. Now, the Holy
Grail, the goal of separating markup, structural markup like
HTML from visual presentation with CSS is to really have
complete separation of the two. One reason is that people with
disabilities for example might be relying on reader software
that tries to take an HTML page and read the contents to them
and allow them to navigate. If you've mixed in styling
information along with your HTML structural content, it can make
life more difficult for the reader programs. You might be
wondering how far you can actually go if you are trying to
really and truly separate out the HTML markup from a CSS? Just
to give you an example, here is a site called the CSS Zen
Garden, and really it's just an illustration of the power of
CSS. I am in the Safari browser here, which allows me to disable
style sheet. What would this page look like if no CSS styles
were applied? Well, it will look like this, pretty basic, but
notice that the structure of the page is quite clear. We can
immediately see where the headings are, major and minor
headings. We can see things that are obviously intended to be
lists of bulleted items. We can see the presentation order of
things. If we turn styles back on, the remarkable thing is that
we can choose a different set of styles. Let's click on one of
these at the bottom. What's interesting here is that none of the
HTML text has changed. In fact if I go back and disable styles
one more time, you can see that it's the same exact HTML content
that we had before, but the page looks totally different. This
is sort of an extreme example, and in fact you can click through
here and look at other styles like a robot named " Jimmy." The
moral of the story is you could do a tremendous amount of visual
styling just using CSS, so don't mix style information into your
markup.