nitial vote says? Initial voting? I wonder if I should get
clickers. Initial voting? Okay, good. Talk about it. This is
little bit of everything. Little bit of everything. Second vote.
Second vote? Second vote? Would not be a good candidate. Not be
a good candidate for fixturing. Second vote says? Second vote
says? You should talk more. No. Let's take a look at this. What
make something a good candidate for a fixture? Remember, what
would be the downside of fixtures? A downside is that you create
them because there's one or a couple of tests that might want to
use them, but they're there for all of the other tests, too,
whether you want them or not. There's the possibility that they
can end up creating dependency you don't want. What that says is
if it's a piece of information that doesn't change very much and
pretty much has to be there for any test to do something
sensible, that's probably something that is okay to fixture. In
my view, the TMDb API key is a reasonable thing to fixture,
because over the course of a single run of testing or single run
of the program, it won't change much. The places that might
change are tested or specifically about what happens if you pass
the wrong key and we're going to look at those next. Generally
speaking, this is not a piece of information that changes around
a lot and most tests are going to need some value for it to be
in place if they get as far as the part of the code that talks
to TMDb. Similarly, the applications time on settings except for
if there's some part of the code that test specifically things
around time zones. Time zone settings have to be there, but they
don't change very much across the tests. On the other hand,
movies and their ratings are central to the app. There's going
to be a million tests to do a lot of different things at movies
and ratings, and that's where the danger creeps in that
fixturing them for one test [ kind of 00:01:44] having
unforeseen consequences for other tests. My view is that things
like the TMDb API key or the time zone settings, those are fine
for fixturing. Movies and their ratings I would not want to
fixture them, because there's just going to be too many tests
that want too many different things out of that type of data,
and the likelihood that the fixtures will screw up something
else would creep in. Okay?