Let me just make sure you understood that. Ben Bitdiddle says, "
Put arbitrary things in the session and it's that okay?" Yes and
you can do it? Yes but you shouldn't do it? No because you can't
generally arbitrary things in the hash? No because session isn't
really a hash, it just quacks like one until it's time to save
it between sessions and then it's not a hash anymore? We're
going to keep with the high octane mode today. There's enough
disagreement on this one that I think you should probably talk
it over for a minute. We're doing updated vote. We have
convergence on the ... I've seen green right? People, I think in
green? Good. Let's go through and understand why green is the
right answer. There were usually some votes for blue. Blue is a
plausible choice but I think green is a better choice. Here's
the reason. When I say session isn't really a hash, it just
quacks like one. Remember the whole point of duck typing is it
quacks like a duck. It's a freaking duck. Its fine that session
just quacks like a hash. You can indeed do everything to the
session you would expect to do to a hash, and the session will
not complain. You can abuse it, you can throw it against the
wall. The problem is that at that some point the session has to
be serialized. It's got to be saved so that they can be restored
on the next request. Now, it is absolutely the case as I said on
a couple of minutes ago. You could chose to store session data
in the database or store session data in a no sequel database.
If you do that you can make the session arbitrarily big. You
just got to make sure that the part of the session is persisted
in the cookie is not too large. That isn't a problem with the
session; it's a problem with the cookie mechanism. Some people
did different ways you can solve it. You can solve it by saying;
I'm going to put my sessions in the database that lets the
session object bigger. You could say I'm going to re- factor how
I think of my session. I'm going to create a new model to
represent the information I really care about. That model is
going to be persistent in the database just like all of their
models. My session is small because it only has to store like
the ID's of which model instance I care about. That's the more
elegant re- factor and then probably more likely to be restful
but it's not the only one. Indeed, green is the right answer
here. You can technically do it, but it's a bad idea because at
some point you'll probably end up shooting yourself in the foot.
You can indeed put arbitrary objects in the hash. The red answer
is not correct. Knock yourself out, no, don't. This is the time
to actually exercise summary strength.