Okay, let’ s try another cards again, so which of these stories
is … Which of these features is least smart? User can search for
a movie by title. Rotten Potatoes should have good response
time. When adding a movie, 99% of the Add Movie pages should
appear within three seconds, and as a customer, I want to see
the top ten movies sold, listed by price, so that I can buy the
cheapest ones first. We’ re trying for SMART User Stories, which
one of these is dumbest, I guess? Okay. Ready, set, vote. Let’ s
see what we got. A lot of you aren’ t voting. All right. I think
that’ s kind of overwhelmingly green. Which of these letter they
violating here? Search for a movie by title, that’ s not very …
That’ s okay. The worst one is Rotten Potatoes good response
time. It has the word “ good” in there so that’ s, you know,
good is in the eye of the beholder. Certainly, three and four
are pretty specific, right. 99% of the movies in less than three
seconds, that’ s very specific and measurable and again, if the
customer, it lays out who the stakeholders are. Top ten specific
and measurable as well. Hopefully all of these are achievable
and you Timeboxed them and can you figure out their business
value by asking to Five Why’ s you can do that. User search for
a movie title is a little vague but it’ s not as vague as the
Rotten Potatoes having a good response time. Okay.