All right. With that, let's ask some questions before [ our
trend in 00:00:03] demo. Again, this might not be too hard,
which is true. Usually, you complete Behavior Driven Design
phase with Cucumber before starting the Test Driven Development
phase with RSpec. Usually you code the sad path first. A sad
path can pass without having code written needed to make a happy
path pass. None of the above is true. Ready, set, vote. Which is
true? I think everybody got this one right. Usually, you
complete BDD a separate design phase. No, it's either to back
and forth in BDD and TDD. Usually you code the sad path first.
Usually, you code the happy path first. You like to see it
working, but we just got this pedagogic problem and we're going
to do this example, so yes. Okay.