Okay, first vote. First vote. Okay, I think enough people got
this and I think we're just gonna go and explain the answers
here. So, which statements are true about implicit requirements?
First, that they're often, but not always, derived from the
explicit requirements. That is certainly true. We just saw a
simple example where the explicit requirement really just talked
about what a method should do, but it didn't talk about what
happens when the method fails, or what are the ways in which it
could fail, and how do we handle those. So, that's an example
where we had to sort of derive some additional implicit
requirements, even though they weren't part of what we wish the
code would do, right? Usually, when we think about what we wish
the code would do, we tend to think in terms of what it would do
when it works correctly, all right. We tend to think about the
happy path. Sometimes, the implicit requirements come out of
also considering what are the various sad paths. They apply only
to unit and functional tests? Not necessarily. Implicit
requirements can come from integration tests as well, or from
user- level acceptance tests. In fact, the users tend to have
the same issue, right? They tend to think of a flow in terms of
the happy path, and often at each step there are many different
ways that something could go wrong. And you need to have a
sensible response when either the user makes an error or the
user tries to do something that they thought would work, but it
doesn't work. So again, in those cases, you're really deriving
these implicit requirements of ... Okay, well what about when
we're not on the happy path? What's a reasonable behavior to do
then? And you have to test for those as well. And testing them
is not really any lower priority because the reaction when the
user does something incorrect, but expected, is in some sense
just as important as when they do something correct but
expected. From the user's point of view, if they see a cryptic
error message, as opposed to seeing a helpful, " Oh, you tried
to do X, but here's why you can't do X right now." You have to
implement and test those code paths because from the user's
point of view, the app doesn't work if they don't understand how
it failed, right? If they're not getting feedback about what
they did wrong so that they could use it more effectively. So,
my view of the answer to this question is that the first
statement is true. The second and third statements are for the
most part not true. And that makes the fourth statement also not
true.