Right next segment is about cloud computing. So the question is
so all these people are using these services like a Google
search and Youtbe and Ebay and Amazon all that stuff. What's the
hardware to use? What all these companies use to have millions
of customers? Do they use supercomputers in these giant
expensive computers are mainframe computers these kind of gold
plated things that almost never fail. So that's a question.
Another question is will suppose I don't work for those
companies? I've got this great idea, but I'm I would love to be
able to millions of users but, do I have to build a warehouse
computer and spend a get some venture capitalists to invest a
hundred million dollars in my idea? And we don't even know it
works. So, am I can be shut out? Right? So what's the answer to
this? It turns out, let's first list what you need right. To do
software as a service over the internet you need to communicate
to interact with that service you need scalability so what does
that mean? So, if you're doing like a photo sharing service in
it's right around Halloween you know that suddenly all these
photos are gonna show up and you're gonna need a lot more
computing. Or, if you're doing sales of like Amazon does around
Christmas there's going to be this huge demand but the rest of
the year not so much. You have to be able to scale up to be able
to handle the load "'cause" if you can't scale to handle the
load, then customers get frustrated and go to your competitor.
It has to work you've only got one copy of the the software. You
only have one copy the hardware, if that one goes down you're
off the air. You're not making money and you're making customers
mad. If you know with shrink wrapped software you can you know
of you have millions of copies if you crash so what. Right? If
this is the only copy it's gotta work. So what the hardware that
people ended up doing was clusters. Clusters actually got
started here at Berkeley is part of the network of workstations
project that Armando and I are involved in. With the cluster is
is you put a a bunch of computers together like like P. C.s are
workstations. And you connect them with ethernet switches. So,
just like what's in the buildings here on campus but you
dedicate them for this service you wanna provide. Now what
happened was and that this proved to be much more scalable data
network as a fundamentally more scalable and then other choices
out there it was a lot cheaper. The people's purposal in Louise
Verosa wrote a book about warehouse scaled computers make things
about a factor twenty cheaper. So, for the same amount
computation or disk storage or memory it cost twenty times as
much to buy the book gold plated stuff from the mainframe like
I. B. M. versus P. C.s and the way they get dependability in
clusters is to have a lot of redundant copies. So if it's twenty
times cheaper you can afford to have three replicas of
everything it's still you know one seventh the cost of gold
plated version, so they just it's. The parts aren't very
dependable but you have a triplicate them and so the
collectively software makes that dependable. And it turns out if
you have thousands of computers all, pretty much the same, all
running the same software, they're not that hard to manage. So,
that a few operators can handle thousands of servers and then as
we talked earlier a virtual machines can really help make this
work so that's another thing that can simplify the task. So
warehouse scale computers soon grew yeah the first ones had
maybe a thousand servers, but as customers increased over time.
They have now a hundred thousand servers is demand increased
what they discovered is when you build a warehouses heaters you
order a hundred thousand computers at the time you get huge
amount of timings to scale. If you were to go Dell or H. P. and
say I want hundred thousand computers they're gonna give your
really good deal. If you're gonna build a warehouse rather than
just for a thousand computers, but a hundred thousand that's
much more efficient way to build it and if you get network
bandwidth by the you know you gigabits this opposed to by the
megabits that's much cheaper that way. So by factors of three or
eight, so I factors of three or eight per computers it was
cheaper to do the warehouse scaled computing. Also, what happens
is traditional data centers are underutilized so there was a
hundred data centers used for the thousands computers maybe
these ten or twenty percent of the time to consolidate them
together to get more utilization. So, what ends up happening in
particular starting with amazon, they realized they can earn
money to offer a pay as you go service, because their costs are
so much less that they could sell for less than the customer
cost, but they still make a profit. And so the characteristic of
this, what's called utility computing or public cloud computing
is that offers a computation storage communication at pennies
per hour and remarkably there's no cost for scaling. Usually, if
you wanna a thousand times faster computer you pay a lot more
than a thousand times more for that privilege. Here a thousand
years one hours the same price is one computer four thousand
hours. Their job that companies are providing us to makes you
think you have as many computers as you want and their job is to
fulfill that pledge, which is a very attractive and Amazon Web
Services Google App Engine, and Microsoft Asure were the leading
ones to do this. Over the years now Amazon's been doing this
about seven years I think they're model has won, so now Google
App Engine, Microsoft Azure are pretty much imitating what
Amazon Web Services has done and so the slides took together
which is now there's seventeen different types of instances that
you can get there. The the original one the small one which
seven years ago was ten cents an hour is now six cents an hour
and that's kind of the building block you see things the cost
seventy five times as much down here. And you can see things
with a hundred times as much memory or a hundred times as much
computing. All kinda flavors different one so you can whatever
your task is you pick the one you pay the price so when Amazon
came out and they said they announced doing things for ten cents
an hour and you say oh they gotta be losing money doing that.
Well that was seven years ago with Moore's law right. So seven
years later they went from ten cents an hour to six cents per
hour. Only forty percent drop despite Moore's seven years of
Moore's Law, which could be a factor of a hundred cheaper, so
that they are perceived as making up a lot of money doing this.
I went to a conference last year from Amazon their first public
conference. And they said a remarkable statement they said every
day they rollout is many servers as it took to run Amazon.com in
two thousand three one of the five billion dollar your six
thousand employee company. So in the beginning when this started
the person who made the argument for Amazon to get into this is
we have all these computers we only need them near Christmas.
Let's rent them out the other eleven months per year. Well then
it's an interesting argument what happens across Christmas
right. Well they got started in it and suddenly became so
popular that roles reversed now Amazon.com, where you go buy
books they don't have any computers they're just a client of
Amazon web services they're relatively small client of Amazon
Web Service and Netflix and many others are doing that. So and
and the rolling I don't know five thousand servers today I don't
know how many servers they're putting out. Another thing we did
kind of show off was that they could build a supercomputer out
of these rented services. So they put five hundred these larger
ones together and they were able to do two hundred forty tera
flops which at times but the top one hundred of the fastest five
hundred supercomputers in the world. That cost about thirteen
hundred dollars an hour. So that you can rent a a supercomputer
with your credit card to take advantage of this? Well when Zynga
did Farm Vill and they could've built their own data center,
then go to venture capitalists and say what we need a bunch of
servers to do this the biggest online game before that happened
five million users so we need of servers five million that's or
maybe that's that's the biggest ones will start small.
Fortunately, for them they went to Amazon Web Services and so
every time the number of customers increase they just increased
their credit card limit and got more servers. So in the for four
days they went up to a million you know. From zero to million in
four days. In two months ten million, nine months of seventy
five million. If it hadn't been on Amazon Web Services they
couldn't have done that. So, that they're able to take in as
much income as they could get computers. So, without having to
do that. So, think about that for a a minute you all heard of
the jeopardy champion Watson. So, that bottom harbours about
ninety these servers let's say we we picked one that's like two
hundred dollars an hour. So what's two hundred dollars an hour
that's like what you know what these people we talked about
earlier an attorney or accountant is paid. A good attorney or
accountant gets paid two hundred dollars an hour Think about in
your careers as machine learning starts to work and A.I. starts
to work kinda for what task is A.I. as good as a highly trained
person two hundred dollars an hour. That's today's prices is
right? It's gonna go down. So, what is gonna mean for society
right? What this is going to mean is computers get smarter can
do more things. And we know what jobs are out there I have this
sense that we're this you know tremendously efficient job
killing industry. I think the reason I think the reason
attorneys is to be pretty cool jobs is dropping. I think it's
got to do computer technology. They're good at discovering
things that they use to use law clerks to do. So, yeah so this
is a really good job this is this is a good one to pick, cause
I'm sure there's gonna be a demand for this I just hope that
we're gonna start getting into the job generating side of
things.