With that, let’ s break out our cards, and ask which may be an
opinionated piece. We’ re going to ask for the SOFA guidelines;
short do one thing, have few arguments, stick to one level of
abstraction. Which is the most important for unit testing? What
you think of these four things which one is the most important
for unit testing? Why don’ t you find your cards or find your
iPod and think about it for a few seconds? Will you get to vote?
I’ m pretty sure were going to get to talk about this. Ready,
set vote. We’ ve got lots of green and then blue and pink. Why
don’ t you talk and then we’ ll give you my opinion. Let’ s try
and vote as partners again. Raise up the cards and boy, there’ s
a lot of votes for green here. Now this would be a terrible
midterm question, because this is basically Armando’ s and my
opinion and you could probably make a case for each of them, but
we’ ll relay what we were thinking. How about short, which is
one of the ones you didn’ t pick? Well, it could be long and as
long as it straight- line code it could still be pretty easy to
test. How about sticking to one level of abstraction? That idea’
s to make code easier to understand. It could be actually pretty
easy to test even though it’ s hard for a human being to
understand it. The last two here; doing one thing. Yeah. That
probably would help with testing, but if each thing is simple,
it might still be easy to test. What we were actually arguing
for was few arguments, that if the arguments really matter than
the more arguments, there are more test cases for you. If the
arguments just kind of fit into a formula and there’ s nothing
to do in a method, but calculate that formula then it wouldn’ t
be so bad. I think the main thing about this question is, where
you think about what matters in terms of testing. Arguing about
doing one thing with few arguments, I think, in our experience,
we think that arguments can be both ways, but you can certainly
find example codes where it’ d be a strong case where for any of
those things that was more important than the others, but in
that was the kind of perspective….