Given that background, cards out, which is a not true statement
about Model- View- Controller? In SaaS apps on the web,
controller actions and view contents are transmitted using HTTP
protocol. Model- View- Controller apps have both a client part,
like the part that runs in your browser, and a cloud part, like
the part that runs in Rails on an app server. Model- View-
Controller is just of the several ways that you could structure
these apps, and although we've been talking about client server,
you could also use Model- View- Controller to structure peer-
to- peer applications like File Sharing, stealing, whatever.
Think about this for a moment, we'll do a vote. Let's do an
initial vote. Initial vote, initial vote. There's not agreement.
There's almost representation of every answer, so this is a good
one to talk about for about 30 seconds. Which statement is not
true? Shall we try voting again? Let's try second vote, second
vote, second vote. This question is obviously very contentious.
Let's go through these answers one a time and see which ones we
can determine to be true or not true. Controller actions and
view contents are transmitted using HTTP. What's a controller
action? A controller action is just an HTTP request. That's the
only way we have to communicate with an app. What are view
contents? View contents are things like HTML pages. HTTP is
indeed the one and only protocol that is used for web SaaS
applications. Orange passes the test, orange is a true
statement. All Model- View- Controller apps have both a client
part and a cloud part. Who made that rule? They absolutely don't
have to. You could write an app that runs entirely on your
iPhone, but Model- View- Controller really is just talking about
how you organize the functionality of the app, that there's a
notion of the data or the app manipulates, there's a notion of
some user interface and there is a mediation between the user
and the data, and that's that controller part. You can apply
that structure to an app that's got a client and cloud part. You
can do it to an entirely cloud- based or an entirely client-
based app. The green statement is not true. What about the
remaining two statements? Just one of several possible ways, if
you were not asleep during the last slide, you should realize
that it is just one of several possible ways. I showed two other
ways, three other ways. What about the last one, peer- to- peer
apps versus client- server? Again, a peer- to- app as distinct
from client- server, that just means that, unlike client-
server, there aren't necessarily different pieces of software
specialized for different roles. There's a single piece of
software that both serves your files to other people and lets
you steal … I mean, copy files from those other people. Again,
if we're just talking about the way the data is organized, the
way that users interact with it and the mediation between those
two, you can apply that concept to any type of app. Indeed,
client- server, as well as peer- to- peer apps, could be
structured as Model- View- Controller.