Now it's time to get specific. We've talked about the
architecture of SaaS apps in general, we talked about Model View
Controller and now it's time to start the tour of the actual
Rails framework that we can start tying some of these concepts
concretely to what Rails does for each of these things. If you
create a new Rails app, or if you use the Rotten Potatoes app
that we've created for the course and you take a look at what's
in the directory, the root directory of the app, here's a bunch
of stuff that you'll see. We're not going to look at everything
that's in the main directory, but you'll find a Gemfile, you'll
find a Rakefile, and now you're going to start seeing the
directories that correspond almost exactly with the concepts
we've been talking about. In terms of a little architectural
diagram, which I have cleverly reproduced in miniature, there's
a directory called App, which has subdirectory models, views and
controllers. You could probably figure out what's in those
directories based on our walkthrough of the app so far. We know
that the app is organized around MVC and we know the roles that
each one of those things plays. For example, given that we said
each type of thing, for example a movie, has its own model, own
sets of views, and its own controllers, you can imagine what you
might find in these directories. If we continue our tour, we
talked about using stylesheets as a way to style the
presentation to the user. There's a directory called Assets in
which you'll find stylesheets, you'll find a place you can put
Java Script, which we're going to learn about later, and other
interesting stuff. We talked about the idea that Rails has a
separate routing sub system that you don't have to mix in
hardwire URIs into your code, instead, you specify what actions
you want to support and what resources, and Rails provides
machinery for generating those URIs for you. In the Config
directory, you'll find a file called routes. rb, which is how
you specify what actions you want to do, and as your app starts
up, the information in that file is used to automatically build
those mappings at run time. There's also a directory called db
for database, as we know, the database is where the models data
actually lives, and one thing we're going to see very shortly
when we talk about how Rails deals with databases is that you
can have more than one. In particular, there's one that you use
for real in the production, there's one that you do your
development on and there's another one that's just for running
your tests. You'll find all of those, or at least the
information about how to get at them, in the db subdirectory.
What about how ... does Rails act as an MVC framework? Here's a
picture that we used from a long time ago, showing that your web
browser goes in through the presentation tier, that's where
webserver lives, it hits your Rails app and at some point, it'll
probably get data from the database. Specifically what's inside
your app? In the Rails world, the first thing that happens is
where your incoming requests from the browser is going to hit
one of the controllers and where is the controller code? It's in
the Controllers directory, just where you would expect to find
it. This is a theme that we're going to keep coming back to. If
you do things the way that a reasonable person would expect,
there's a lot of work that you don't have to do. The Rails
routing subsystem is responsible for mapping the incoming URL to
the right controller and the right action or for signaling an
error if there is no match. The controller will probably ask the
model to do some work for it, and what is a model? It's a bunch
of codes somewhere in the model sub directory, appropriately
enough. We know that because Rails is using active record, that
means that there's a relational database, and each model has a
table in that database where instances of that model start. Once
the model has returned some data back to the controller, the
controller can hand that off to a templating system like Haml.
The views will get rendered by interpolating the data that came
via the controller, that gets returned back to your browser.
What are the models? As we're going to see the subclasses of
active record base, the views are subclasses of action view and
the controllers are subclasses of application controller. This
is an example of how you use the features of a language that has
class hierarchy and inheritance to support a framework. If we're
saying that Active Record has common machinery that all models
can use, and then there's specific machinery associated with
your particular type of mode, that's exactly a case of using
inheritance because we want to reuse implementation. The
implementation of the common functionality of Active Record
should be shared by all models, it makes sense to make models a
subclass of some base model that has the functionality that's
common to all of them. You can make a similar argument for views
and controllers. This is a good use of inheritance. We have
commonality across different kinds of things, there's a certain
amount of that commonality that we want to capture, a common
implementation that they all can reuse, inheritance is the way
of reusing the implementation. Let's take a trip through a Rails
application, a very quick one. What happens ... I'm putting some
detail and text behind that diagram. We have routes that we
define for our own application in routes. rb. They map the
incoming request URIs to controller actions, as we saw, those
controller action routes can include optional arguments, like an
argument that identifies ... or a parameter that identifies a
particular resource, those get extracted for you. Here's an
example where we're visiting an app running on our local
machine, and we're going to do get/ movie/ 3 continuing the
example from the previous segment. In this case, routes. rb is
going to be consulted and there will be a mapping because this
is one of the default routes that Rails provides for us, saying
you should be looking at the movies controller and call the show
action within that controller. Where are these things going to
be located? We'll show, in a moment, that convention over
configuration means that if we choose to follow some default
rules about how things are named and where they're located, we
don't actually have to explicitly tell Rails where to look. It
will basically figure it out. The controller actions can do
pretty much whatever they want to get up the data, and once
they're done, they can set up instance variables that will be
visible to the views. This is how information is actually
communicated from the controller's subsystem to the view
subsystem. Any controller instance variables that are set up in
the controller action automatically become visible to the view.
Now you might say, and I hope you would say because you've been
listening so closely, “ Wait a minute, Armando, you just said
that the views are subclasses of one thing, action view, but
controller are subclasses of this other thing, action
controller. How is it that setting instance variables in
something that is a controller could result in those instance
variables becoming accessible to something in a totally
different class?” That makes no sense at all and you'd be right.
What Rails actually does, remember we talked about
metaprogramming, Ruby allows you to write code at run time,
modify classes at run time. What basically happens is action
view instance is created, and new instance variable attributes
are injected into it using metaprogramming. Its instance
variables will match the ones that you setup in your controller
method. It doesn't matter what they are, remember in Ruby we can
ask any object about itself, the controller method can ask,
about itself, what new instance variables did the programmer
create and use in the controller method that were not already
instance variables of the controller itself? For every one of
those, I'm going to create a version of that variable with the
same name in this other object of another class called action
view. Why would you do this? Because it's easy for programmers.
You set up the instance variables and then you can just use them
that's the reason to do it. It makes life simpler for the
programmer, and Rails and Ruby are all about simplifying your
programming. The controller can set instance variables that
become visible to the views and where does it find the views? As
we'll see, if you have a controller action called, for example,
show, which shows a movie, it'll just look in the Views
subdirectory for movies and look for show. html. haml, because
that's reasonable. We're going to talk a lot more about
convention over configuration. Here's an example of what our
controller action might look like. We get the ID of the movie
that we wanted to look up, this comes from the URI, the route
subsystem pulls it up for us. As we'll see, this is one of the
ways that we can tell the movie model to do the R and find the
database record whose ID is this, assign it to this instance
variable, MV, and magically, that instance variable become
available to us in the view. The view might have a little piece
of stuff in it that looks like this in Haml, a list item
saying, " The rating of this movie is," and an interpolation
saying, " Mv. rating." Why does this work? Because MV is just a
movie variable, movie has an attribute called rating and we can
de- reference it. The goal is to make the code look like the way
that you had expected to work. It's really to minimize the
number of surprises when you're looking at the code. The Rails
philosophy that under lies a lot of this, and we're going to see
many examples of … a couple of flaws, one of them is convention
over configuration. Basically it says you follow certain rules
and in exchange, there's a lot of things that you won't have to
worry about, and how to find stuff or where stuff is named. An
example would be that if the movie's controller, which is ...
it's a controller we defined, so it's subclass of action
controller, and we wanted to find an action or a method in that
controller called show, Rails will expect that that controller's
subdirectory includes movies_ controller. rb. Basically the rule
is, you take the name of the thing, you pluralize it and you
add _ controller. It will expect that at the end of the show
action, because it's going to want to render a view, that unless
you say otherwise, it should look for the movie subdirectory and
views and show. html. haml in that subdirectory. Again, you can
override all this whenever you want, but if you override it, you
end up doing more work because now you have to tell it where to
actually look for these things. As you might guess, the ability
to introspect on Ruby objects and ask questions about
themselves, like what is my name, what is the name of this
variable, what is the name of me, is how Rails is able to then
look up things with the corresponding name find them in certain
directories. Part of this is the Don't Repeat Yourself
philosophy, or DRY. If you can figure out the names of things
like files and actions and templates just by applying some
simple rules to the names, then there should be no need for you
to explicitly repeat that information somewhere else. That's
just one more place you have to update whenever your app
changes. We'll see many mechanisms not only using convention
over reconfiguration to be DRY, but also to extract common
functionalities that you can reuse it for many places. Both the
mechanisms, the examples that we'll see, rely very heavily on
Ruby Language features. This is why people will often say, "
Rails is just a framework," you can do a framework just like
Rails, but it would be in JAVA instead of Ruby. It's actually
not that simple because a lot of the things that make Rails apps
as concise as they are is the fact that you can get away with a
lot of ... essentially not explicitly put in a lot of
information, because you use introspection to infer the
information, and you can use metaprogramming to create new
objects at Runtime that look the way the way the programmer
expects. If the language doesn't support that, you might think
you have something like Rails, but the parts of Rails that
really buy you simplicity and compactness will be largely absent
from it.