So which statement is not true about testing: With better test
coverage you're more likely to catch faults while difficult to
achieve a hundred percent test coverage insurance design
reliability, each higher level test delegates more detailed
testing to lower levels or unit test work within a single class
in module testing or works cross classes. So which of these four
is not true just false. Me. So C. K. why don't you think a
second ready, set, vote. Alright, okay, that's I think that's
okay. Why don't you talk that over a little bit and I'll do
something. Okay let's let's try and vote again ready set vote!
Well... it's... okay so let's let's go over these things. With
better test coverage you're more likely catch faults: yes. Each
higher level test delegates more detailed lower levels, that's
true. while difficult to achieve a hundred precent test coverage
ensures design reliability. The problem with that statement is
just because you tested everything doesn't you tested it well.
So it just says you've exercised the path you may have done some
stupid test on it but you'd exercised it. So it's a good goal to
get a hundred percent test coverage but doesn't tell you how
good a test you really have. So you could still have major
easy... easy to have major bugs in your software even if you
have a hundred percent test coverage in the unit testing and
module testing recognition. Okay we're doing good. So good that
I can do another segment was great because I was worried I
wasn't gonna get too optimistic. So one of things that's uh
happens is you know in our field is we have, we deal with change
all the time. And because we deal with change all the time we
have to get more productive. And we're going to talk about doing
that. Basically it's More's law. We're this field that expect
things to double every couple years. No other, no other
technology does something like that. It's been going on for
decades. So what that means is the hardware designs get bigger,
faster processors and bigger memories which means software gets
bigger because it's faster and you have a bigger footprint. And
so what we've had to do is improve software productivity. So how
much bigger is it that uses you know it's it's a million times
more cost effective, a billion times... So giant numbers right?
So suppose we're still writing software the way we did fifty
years ago it would take infinity to write a big you know a
hundred million line piece of the software but we have tools
let's do that today. So there's really four techniques just four
techniques that people are using. First of all is making it
concise by writing in a short amount of information they get
transformed as big amounts of information that's a good way to
be more productive. Code synthesis: you don't even write it. t
gets generated for you reusing stuff that's already been built
that's a big way to improve productivity. And finally automation
and tools. So let's just go through those. So the first one is
conciseness. So this line here that you see that's one way to
write that, right? That that there's some languages that with
the way you write it. But a much more compact version is this
and this is legal ruby right? A should be greater than or equal
to seven is gonna read it and understand it. That's shorter,
fewer characters and it's easier to understand. So that's an
example thirty sizes. in general it's an example of raising the
level of abstraction. That that's why high level languages were
invented. other ideas like automatic memory management... You
know thirty years ago my friends would argue you know that you
know that it's automatic management didn't save you that much
there weren't that many bugs. Now we know that languages like C
there's lots of bugs if you manually remote management. Any
scripting languages like ruby have these ideas reflection
programming slated raise the level of abstraction. software
synthesis is like this idea that you generate the code that
you're gonna use rather than write it yourself. An example is
BitBit which generated code fit to the situation so rather have
an a loop in there to do bit movements a little if statement in
it it would generate situation so that if statement didn't have
to be in as a first example of that and right now in the
research and even in products right now there's programming by
example so you got the latest work version of Microsoft excel
you can give it an example of what you want it to do and it will
create a a macro to do that for you. So we're starting to see
it's code synthesis really happening in products. Re-use is of
course people from the very first computers have all been trying
to do that. Why do we have to write everything yourselves? Why
can't we reuse the code that we already have? So first we're
procedures and functions almost from the dawn of computing we
had that, standardized libraries, once we had a functions than
there we create libraries so lots of people could use them
object oriented programming came along twenty or so years later
that we can put together collections of tasks. And then design
patterns and we'll talk about this whole chapter on design
patterns in the book and we'll talk about in this class is that
as a strategy that can we use even if the implementation varies.
The final topic as automation tools I think of tools as kind of
what computer scientists do: is to see a problem it's tedious
let's build a tool to make it easier to use. In fact that's a
lot of what you'll be doing in this class a lot of what we've
been doing is exactly that some rails programmer found something
that was tedious to do and built a tool because it's kind of
easy to build tools in this environment and suddenly it's a tool
we use. I think this is the fifth time we've taught the class in
the last five years. Every time we've taught the class there's
been some new tool that we had to use that wasn't available last
year that we can't imagine how to use it without it. So what are
the problems is lots of programs are coming up with tools all
rights programs are coming up the tools. So are they dependable
is it have a good user interface? How do you pick from them?
Well we're gonna help you in this classes as Armando and I and
the staff are gonna pick the tools you have to learn. There's a
half a dozen of them but, you know, they work and they're
dependable and you'll have to figure that out on your own after
this class. But as I said earlier software engineering because
we're in this rapidly growing field is something to... that
demands lifetime learning in you'll get an example of that lots
of examples of learning tools here that you'll come to love
would