Here, let's wrap up BDD here and there's BDD seems like a pretty
simple set of ideas, common sense once you explain them. We'll
have to see if you follow them but there's a lot of pitfalls
here. The first one is because we're talking about this is the
user interfaces as well as how you helped the code. You've
started meeting with customers and the reason that their ...
when you see a three by five card, show it to the customer they
don't think it's been implemented, right? Tell them a piece of
paper. If you do a mock up of you using interface with just,
it's easier for you to use [ Hamel 00:00:36] to make up a screen
image and flash it up there. The customers are liable to think
that you already built and be kind of reticent to make changes
to it. That is until late in the project when they say, " No, I
don't like to use interface," and make you start over, then, "
Why didn't you tell me that earlier, while they were little
intimidated by the code." Stick to that paper and pencil, crayon
based mock up so they won't be afraid to change it. A relate
thing is to just doing the sketches but not doing the story
boards. The user interface involves the interaction of all these
pages and you want the customer to agree that how this are
related together before you spend the time building the things,
and again the storyboards. If you actually, if go to YouTube and
you look up user stories somebody even took the time to make a
little stop action movie with it and said a while which you
could do as well. I don't think they'll be ... they won't think
to stop action with paste, colors, color crayons and pasty
paper. They're going to think that's a real user interface but
they animated then I push this and the changes around. Do
something and show them to make sure you get it in advance. Now,
the more traditional software delinquent pitfalls that Agile was
invented to try and prevent which is a thing to do is that the
programmer, developers come up with some feature that they think
would be cool. Right? Oh man. They see that it's cool because it
would be fun to program or they think the customer's going to
really like this but then it gets rejected when the customer,
they were at wrong. The customer didn't really want that. You're
BDD is all about going to the customer and figuring out what you
want to write before you'd write the code. What you write stick
around. We want to try and avoid that waste of effort. Trying to
predict what you need or things that you think will be cool,
don't do that, listen to your customer and don't waste your
time. Another issue or pitfall and these are pitfalls because
there they can easy to happen even though if their coming, is to
think their done when you done the happy path, right? You got a
happy path for each of the features and so it seems to work that
you done. You really need a sad path as well as a happy path.
From a customer's perspective it's just as important as the [
feature 00:02:56] when I had works but when a user makes a
mistake that it doesn't blow up, right? That it will record an
air message. Studies of humans that we just have an error right.
You'll hear a mondo and I say the wrong word, we know the right
word in the lectures but we just use the wrong word. Humans have
an error right, so the error is human. At part of building an
app successfully is to make sure you have both sad path and a
happy path working. On the other hand, dunk over board on the
sad paths. How many ways can my app go wrong? There's millions
of bugs, unlimited number of bugs you could have. If you start
seeing user stories then I should not see this, and then I
should not see that. You got a lot of steps of what you should
not see. Be aware because there's an incredible number of them.
You need to have some sad paths but you can't anticipate all
possible bugs. Then the flip side to is you have to be careful
on the happy path when you're looking for positive expectations,
like in a movie page, you have to be careful so then I should
see the movie Emma. Depending on your user interface that name
of a movie might show up many places on page and so you could
pass even the pictures not working, it's not where you want.
What do you do about that? Capybara has some, if you see the
restricts, the documentation about Capybara, it has some helpers
to help you narrow the focus to the sections of the page where
you can look at. In this example, then I should see Emma within
this shopping cart area. We hope by going over this pitfalls
you're less likely to fall into the pits. With that let's go
over another pure instructions. Which statement is false about
Lo- FI UI and BDD? The purpose of Lo- Fi UI approach is to debug
the UI before you program it. A BDD downside is requiring
continuous contact with customers, which may not be possible. A
BDD downside is that it may lead to poor software architecture
since this focus on behavior. None are false, all three above
are true. Think I met there.