Alright, with that, which expression is true regarding pair
programing? Pair programming is quicker, better quality, cheaper
and less effort than solo programming. The driver works on tasks
at hand, the observer thinks strategically about future tasks. A
pair will eventually figure out who is the best driver and who
is the best observer, and then stick to these roles. My
favourite answer, promiscuous pairing is one long- term solution
to the problem of shortage of programmers. I thought it was
goodness. Ready, set, vote. There's a mix of orange and green.
Talk it over and then we'll have the [ technology 00:00:47].
Talk it over and we'll vote. Let's try and vote again, ready,
set, vote. Mix of green and ... it is much greener. Pair
programming is quicker, better quality, cheaper and less effort.
There's a study that may not be less efforts. That's why that
one isn't true. The driver works on tasks at hand, the observer
thinks strategically about future tasks. Second one, that's what
I thought was true. It's not promiscuous pairing doesn't
increase the number of programmers. Thankfully I guess. That's
human nature for one person to try and drive and a person to
observe. That's not how this system works. You're really
supposed to go back and forth. It will be better for you and
better for the [ person 00:01:31].