We are going to start talking about the architecture of SaaS
applications in general and about some of the mechanisms in
Rails specifically. We're going to start with a architectural
pattern, a way of structuring software called Model View
Controller. Since we're trying to motivate all of these material
with a question of why would you care to learn about this stuff,
the question for this segment is, we've been talking about
frameworks and that fact that they allow you to capture some of
the commonality and different kinds of apps. Specifically for
this SaaS apps we're building in this course, the question is,
what is the common application, if there is any, in these
interactive and user- facing apps that we're building, that if
we could capture them in a framework, would somehow simplify app
development. That's what we're trying to capture here. In order
to do that, we're going to go back to our diagram. We already
started up here. We looked at the client's server nature of web
apps. We also looked at the fact that there's three tiers on the
server side of the web app. Now we're going to dive into one of
those tiers into the app server, and we're going to see that
Rails structures the app server as being structured according to
design pattern called Model View and Controller. What is that?
The idea is if you have an application that is manipulating some
data and interacts with users, that you can separate the
organization and storage of the data, we call that part the
Model, from the user interface and the way the data is
presented, and we call that part the View. What mediates the
interaction between them is this intermediate thing called the
Controller. When the user requests access to data, the
Controller is where the logic lives that mediates that access,
and when the Model wants to present that data that the user
asked for, the Controller mediates getting the data from the
Model and making it available for the user to see. In our case,
what we're going to see is that the Model can read and update
data that's maintained by the application. There's ...
indirectly that data is provided to the View, but it all happens
through the Controller, and the Controller also have the users
who are looking at the View can interact with it. For example,
in the case of the web, the View is a page you're viewing in a
browser and there's affordances on that page, like clicking on
things and submitting forms and stuff like that. Now if you
think about this, it seems like this would be an obvious way
that you would structure web applications, but in fact, other
alternatives are possible and most web frame works don't
necessarily follow this pattern. We'll come back to those in a
minute, but very briefly, to show how Model View Controller apps
work, each entity has a model, a controller and a set of views.
For example, in our hypothetical Rotten Potatoes app, which
we're going to be using to illustrate some of the things about
how Rails works, there's a notion of movies, that's a kind of
thing that the app manipulates. There is movie goers, we have
information about people who watch movies. We might even have
information about reviews that people write about movies. Each
one of those types of entities has its own model, its own
controller, and its own set views associated with it. Of course
there might in inter- relationships between them, for example,
it doesn't really make sense to talk about a review unless you
connect it to the moviegoer who wrote it and to the movie that
it's about. One of the things that you have to be able to do is
make these association among different kinds of models and
reflect those associations when you're trying to collect and
present data. We'll show you how that gets done as well. When
the user's interoperating or interacting with an app like Rotten
Potatoes, they will send requests for different kinds of data,
depending what the data is, the request will ultimately get
handled by one of the several different controllers. What we're
going to show in the next few segments is what machinery a
framework like Rails gives you to help you create those
mappings. I said if you don't do Mode View Controller, are there
other ways to organize a web app? One possibility is you can do
a page controller. Page controller means pretty much every page
the user could view has a controller associated with it. If
you've got an app that just does a few simple fixed actions,
this might actually be an easier design. There's the front
controller, which is actually the way that J2EE servlets work.
There's basically one master dispatcher that everything comes
through, and that gets ... there's logic that might talk to a
bunch of different classes beyond that point, but really there's
one central bottleneck that makes these decisions and that makes
data available for presentation through views. If you've used
PHP before, PHP is an example of a pure template view
application, where there are different models. There's PHP code
that manipulates data and talks to a database, but there's
really just a collection of views that gets interspersed with
that model data. The relationship is really between a bunch of
models and a bunch of views as opposed to Model View Controller,
where each entity has each type of ... each entity in the
application has its own Model, has its own sets of Views, and
has its own Controller that really just deals with that kind of
thing. The message here is that their architecture is all about
making choices, and Rails chooses to support SaaS applications
with Model View Controller, because it turns out that's a really
useful way to structure a large variety of SaaS applications,
but it doesn't mean it's the only choice and other architectures
might be a better fit for other apps. Anytime that we're making
a choice in this course, we choose to use a particular
framework, a particular set of tools. Almost always, that means
that we're giving up on some other choice and although we're not
going to cover all of the choices in detail, it's important for
you to understand that choices that are being made and why these
choices are being made the way they are.