Okay, false about Lo- Fi UI. Like 3x5 cards, sketches and
storyboards are more likely to involve all stakeholders versus
just coding it. The purpose of Lo- Fi UI is to debug the UI
before you program it. SaaS apps usually have user interfaces
associated with user stories. While it takes more time than
building a prototype in CSS Haml, the Lo- Fi UI are more likely
to lead a UI that customers like. This is a really hard one
here, okay? If you were listening. If you weren't on your
phones. Okay, ready, set, vote. Wow, okay. This is false, right?
Which one's false? You should talk about this. Which one of
these is false about Lo- Fi UI. All right, let's vote as pairs.
Ready, set, vote to see how this turns out. Okay, well that
actually worked, it largely converged to blue here. Let's go
over the answers. Instead of code, 3x5 cards and sketches and
storyboards are more likely to involve everyone. That's
important because you want to make ... that'll help us make it
something that the people, that the customer wants at the end.
We want to debug it before we program it by throwing away sheets
of paper or scratching up sheets of paper. That's going to be a
lot less work. SaaS apps usually have user interfaces, stories
and then ... maybe you guys can whip something up little pretty
quickly, but probably we think it'll take you less time than
doing it in Haml. So the false answer was number four.