We talked about User Stories and how much work the hour but how
do you know whether you've got a good one or a bad one? Like is
it too big or is it too hard, and is actually useful as it have
business value. Another acronym that we came up with as part of
this is SMART. A good User Story is specific, Measurable,
Achievable in a single iteration, Relevant and we'll talk about
what the Five Why's are and Timeboxed you know when to give up
so let's go over those, what make a SMART User Story. Specific
and measurable are kind of related that each scenario is
testable. It implies known that for every good input, you what
the results going to be, so you can tell whether it does it or
not. The anti- example here is the User Interface should be
friendly. All right. Let's see how are we going to test and
measure that ... who knows, that is not something he measure so
it's got to be something like, response time has to be 90% of
the time in less than three seconds. In typical, we'll do this [
inaudible 00:01:08] format of of given some specific conditions
when I do X then what's the consequences of that? That will be
when it has that format, it tends to be more specific and more
measurable. How about achievable? Achievable in this case
means [ inaudible 00:01:23] is completing it in the single
iteration because if you can't do it in one [ inaudible
00:01:28] and go do a subset of the stories but you're always
aiming have, remember the agile premises, the prototype is
always working at the end of iteration so you can show them to
the customer. If you're getting less than one story for
iteration, you got to get better at making your estimates to
points to be able to do that so you break it down. Relevant part
of SMART is it has business values, so for those of us who
aren't business majors, what are we talking about here, it makes
an economic difference to companies, that was one interesting
feature. What does it do to help the company be successful?
Protect revenue, increase revenue, manage your expenses,
increase the visibility the brand, making the product standout
from the competition and generally, finding more customers.
Here's an example, the talks on this web page, talks about
deciding whether the thing has business value or what, but we
found this thing ... trick, the five Why's is to find relevance
is works pretty well and basically, this is a very easy thing to
implement. it's like your three- year- old nephew can implement
this for you so let’ s start off with that box office manager.
It’ s a box office manager so they induce patron to buy a
ticket. I want to show her Facebook friends. Why? Okay, that’ s
the first Why. I think more people will go and enjoy the show
more if we do this so why is that important. Okay, I think we’
ll sold more tickets. Why is it important to sell more tickets?
Because the theater makes more money. Why is it important to [
Frantino 00:03:03] make money and we want to make more money so
we don’ t go out of business. Why is it matter if we go out of
business? Then, you won’ t have a job, so it kind of surprising
but this simple mechanism asking why a bunch of times kind of
forces you to drop down in exactly what the issue is that you’
re talking about. Okay It’ s really helping us to the bottom
line so, yes, it’ s a good one. If you ask a bunch of Why’ s and
it stays vague then maybe this doesn’ t have a lot of relevance.
The last part of SMART is Timeboxed. What we’ re worried about
in software is, given the statistics, is that you’ re going to
exceed the time budget. You’ re going to put something together
and it takes a lot longer than you think so what we want to do
is break it up in a smaller pieces so you avoid overestimating …
not … Avoid underestimating. I guess on it, yeah, you’ re
avoiding underestimating the length of the project that can take
longer than you want. As we said, Tracker helps you with
calculating net velocity.