Now you have a basic sense of what I'll call the mechanics of
test writing. This is really good stuff to have, the concept of
a unit test, of testing just one behavior, of grouping those
tests according to functionality and by context, of using mocks
and stubs to really isolate the behavior under test from the
collaborating classes, these are fundamental concepts and ideas
about testing that you're going to use over and over. I don't
care what language and framework you use, this is the same
vocabulary, all of the same concepts apply. Here's another
concept that applies, which is the concept of, " When are you
done testing?" One way you know when you're done testing is the
release date comes. That's not my favorite way of determining
when testing is done. A very crude measure, which is completely
static, is you could look at the number of lines of tests
divided by the number of lines of code. It might surprise some
of you to learn that that ratio is often greater than one, or it
should be greater than one. There are more lines of test than
there are lines of code. It shouldn't be that surprising right,
because a given chunk of code ... first of all there's many
behaviors about that chunk that you would want to test. Each
behavior has its own test. Second, there is usually one way that
a chunk of code can be correct, and many ways in which it can
fail. You want to be testing the ways in which it can fail. You
start putting these together and you realize, actually it
wouldn't be surprising if there were more lines of test than
lines of code. We need to exercise the code in a lot of
different ways. For production systems, this number is ... it
may be a factor of 10. An extreme example is a SQLite has 1000
more lines of test than it does lines of code. Admittedly, a lot
of that is because it has to test all these cross platform
special cases. A better question instead of saying, " When are
we done?" is you could say, " How thorough is my testing?"
There's a few different ways that we can look at it. We won't
talk about formal methods today, we're going to talk about them
a little bit later. We will talk about coverage measurement
which is, again, pervasive no matter which tools you use. Like
all the tools in a discipline like this, we could either use it
tastefully, or we could misuse it. Let's talk about measuring
coverage. What does it mean to measure the test coverage of this
very simple class? I've got two methods here called " foo" and "
bar". As you can see, the foo method sometimes calls the bar
method with different arguments. What are different statements
we could make about the test coverage of this class? The most
simple one you can think of is we've called every method. We
called the foo method at least once, I don't know which branch of
the if statement we took, but at least we called it. The code in
the foo method is not totally dead code. The next level up from
that is we call it from every call site. That means, for
example, because we're calling bar ... whoops, the highlight is
not quite right here. We need to call the bar method from both
possible places, and the foo method from which it could have been
called. That would be S1 level of coverage. Now we start to get
more interesting with ... we execute every statement. Executing
every statement is a little bit tricky, because a conditional
may count as a single statement, regardless of which branch you
took. C0 coverage at least starts to give you an idea of what
percentage of the lines of my application were actually
exercised at all by my test suite? There's a simple cov gem in
Ruby that gives you this, which we are going to have you use in
one of the upcoming home works. C1 is the next level up from
that. That means that you took every branch in both directions.
If there's an if statement, then you've got at least one test
that follows each of the two paths of every if statement. You
can see this is one of the reasons why we don't like it when if
statements are nested, because then you quadratically multiply
the number of paths. There's a modified version of that which
adds decision coverage, which means that if you have a
conditional that depends on more than one expression, like in
this conditional, we have if Y and Z are true, C1 means that
we've taken the if, once because of ... basically, we've tweaked
both Y and Z and make sure that they actually both affect the
outcome of the condition. It's a more granular form of condition
coverage, because we're also looking at the way that the
condition is evaluated and making sure that all the different
ways it could be evaluated, that could lead to a difference in
behavior, have all been checked. Then C2 is every code path. C2
is extremely difficult to get in practice because it means that
you essentially have to do enough analysis to figure out what
combination of inputs and conditions would cause every possible
path through the code to be touched. There is generally not
agreement on how much better that is than some of the other
levels like C1, especially when you combine the unit level
coverage testing with other kinds of coverage. What kinds of
tests can you apply this to? Pretty much you can apply it to
anything. We've seen that there's a spectrum. On the one end we
have model specs, where we're basically stubbing the hell out of
everything. We're just testing little bits of code in isolation
and trying to get down to individual behaviors for those pieces.
At the other extreme, we've got things like Cucumber scenarios,
which exercise the whole app but they only touch a few possible
code paths. Any one cucumber scenario is going to touch a very
small fraction of the total code, and exercise that fraction of
code in the smallest number of possible ways. Then in between we
have things like controller specs which, even though we're
triggering the controller method, we know it's going to interact
with the model, we know it's going to make some stuff available
to view. There's some testing around whether those very simple
boundaries work as well. In general, what happens at each end of
the spectrum? Unit tests tend to run really fast. Cucumber
scenarios, as you may have noticed, are not quite as fast. Unit
tests can have very fine resolution, because you have so much
control over mocking and stubbing, you can exercise paths
through your code that require an unusual set of conditions to
all be the case. You can set all those things up using mocks and
stubs, whereas the resolution of the integration level test is
pretty coarse. You're making high level statements about how the
app is stimulated. That means that anything that you will want
to set up in the test that would control how the test goes,
you've got to be able to set that up essentially from almost a
black box point of view, which is much harder to do.
Consequently that means that it's easier to boost your coverage
with these low level tests. If you find lines or methods that
are not being exercised, because you can use mocks and stubs so
carefully, you can essentially handcraft test cases that will go
ahead and hit those corners, which is much harder to get right
when you're doing integration- level tests. As a general rule,
that means that when you're up here, you're mocking a lot.
You're often mocking out the very interfaces that are between
the classes. We mocked out the interface between the controller
and the model class. We mocked out the interface between the
controller and the view by just asking, " Did you assign this
variable?" Conversely when you're down here, you're using very
few mocks, so the interfaces are very important. What this
really takes you to is you need to have a holistic way of
thinking about tests. I don't even know if they use those words
in software engineering courses back East. This is California,
so we can say words like " holistic" when it comes to software.
One extreme is, " I coded it, I tried a couple of requests with
the browser, it works." Sadly, this is not that far from how a
lot of people do their integration testing today. The other
extreme is just as bad. " Until I have 100% C0 coverage and all
green, then we're not ready to ship." The truth is, somewhere in
between is a level where you'll feel comfortable, because the
coverage has told you what parts of your code are severely
under-tested or untested. Similarly, some people obsessively
focus on unit tests, because you can get more detail, they're
more thorough. Some people obsessively focus on integration
tests because they're more like what the customer will actually
do. After all, you're building this for the customer. The real
opportunity is that each will find bugs that the other misses.
Integration tests are more likely to find bugs across interfaces
or gaps in the UI that you hadn't thought about. Unit tests are
more likely to find bugs with special code passes that may be
very hard to get to be exercised from the customer's point of
view. When they happen, you would want to make sure that you
know how your app is going to react. Given that, we can ask the
question, " Which of these is poor advice for a TDD developer?"
Mock and stub early and often when you're doing unit tests. Aim
for high unit test coverage. Sometimes it's okay to use stubs
and mocks, even in your integration tests. Unit tests give you
higher confidence of overall system correctness than integration
tests do.