Let's go on to team. What are the questions here? First of all,
earlier in my youth in getting into software many years ago. It
was kind of this superhero programmer. We are now in the post-
superhero programmer. It was just the state of software,
whatever it was 30 years ago was such that one smart person
could build this brilliant thing better than anything that was
out there. Why isn't that happening today? Why don't we have the
single superhero anymore that we had 30 years ago? I think it's
just that software is a lot better. It's raised the level of
functionality and quality that you really can't do it by
yourself. Now, to have a successful software engineering career,
you have to be good at programming which a lot of you already
are. You have to get along with others and you have to help make
the team win. Quoting [ Fred Brooks 00:00:48] for the third time
today, " There are no winners on a losing team, and no losers on
a winning team." He said this about basketball at the University
of North Carolina where he was, but no winners on a losing team.
If the team loses you're not going to be bragging about that. If
you're on that infamy hall of fame, hey, I was the best
programmer on the FBI file case abandonment project, that's not
a good thing as a resume. No losers on the winning team, hey, I
help found Google. I only did this minor role, but I help found
Google. Man, if you help found Google, you're going to need that
on your resume. It'd be pretty good. It turns out I've got a lot
of experience in sports, in teams. I think one of my strengths
is building teams. Ironically, I wasn't on a sport like football
or any of the sports that involve a lot of teams. I did
wrestling which is highly individual. This was high school. This
is me. This is me and this is me, and this is 50 years later a
coach and this is Rich Burn whose standing there and we were
best men at each other's wedding and we're still good friends
today. One of the things that these ... I had really good
wrestling coaches. To talk the importance of working as a team
even in an individual sport like wrestling and that's kind
of ... That carries over today and I think that's one of my
strengths as a faculty member. I can get all these independent
faculty members to work together as a team, but basically
you ... If you're in a winning team, there's no losers and
that's what you need to be able to figure out what to do. All
right, so what's an alternative? The Plan and Document has this
program manager style and it's in hierarchical, depends on the
manager, how should we organize an Agile team? It's probably not
going to have this manager model. Is there some alternative to
this hierarchical model? That's what's called Scrum. Scrum is an
example of a way to organize an Agile team. They come up with
this two pizza size team which is four to nine people which is a
good size so you don't spend too much time communicating.
Scrums, the name comes from rugby which I played also. That's
not why. Scrum is inspired by these short daily meetings.
Fifteen minutes every day at the same place, you show up, like
9:07 in the morning, you get there and you have a short meeting
and you just go around the circle and answer three questions.
The three questions are: what have you done since yesterday,
what are you planning to do today, and are there any impediments
or stumbling blocks there? You're going around in a circle and
what the idea is is you try and help individuals on your team,
in the Scrum and see if they have some obstacle and maybe you
can do something to change what you're doing to help them
overcome their obstacle or maybe you have some experience you
can share. Hey, I've had that problem before and you do that.
Every day, 15 minutes, what are you going to do each day?
There's a couple of roles. There's the team which develops it,
but then this person called the Scrum Master and that's the team
member who does these followings things. He acts as a buffer or
he or she acts as a buffer between the team and any kind of
external distraction to try to keep the team focused, working on
the things at hand rather than getting distracted and working on
things besides the user stories you're supposed to. He or she
enforces the team rules, like if you have a coding standard,
make sure every body is sticking to the coding standard and if
there's impediments in making progress, like access to data or
software, the Scrum Master takes that on. The one other role is
called the Product Owner. This is a team member whose not the
Scrum Master, somebody else who represents the voice of the
customer and helps prioritize user stories. We've got the Scrum
Master to help keep the people in the right direction, the
Product Owner. They're going to say, hey I don't know ... As the
Product Owner, I don't think that's a good way to do this or I
think this is more important than trying to push them to do
this. We'll say it again, it's a good idea to rotate these
roles. In this informal organization, certainly the Product
Owner and quite possibly the Scrum Master. Now, one of the
things that happened in teams is resolving conflicts. You know,
there are different opinions on what's the right way to go on a
particular technical issue. Let's talk about some ways to
resolve these conflicts. One way is instead of starting with a
disagreement, it's starting where you agree. Let's start off
with listing all of the things where you agree and then maybe
you're going to realize, well gee, we're not far apart. On these
seven or eight things is one thing to differ, maybe it's not
that big. Another way to do this is to articulate each other's
arguments. Being in arguments, you swap roles. Even if you don't
agree with it, you give the other argument of the other person
and then, that other person switches roles and gives your
argument back. What this does is it avoids confusion about the
terms or assumptions. Maybe the reason of the argument is just
you have different assumptions and once you understand each
other's assumptions, that's the real cause of the conflict.
Intel actually embraces conflicts. They have what they call
constructive confrontation. If you have an Intel blue badger, an
Intel employee, you are told in the first day that if you have a
strong opinion that the person is proposing the wrong thing
technically, not business, but technically. You are obligated to
bring it up by your badge or I'll bring it up. Even if it's the
President of the company. That's constructive confrontation.
That sounds good. That causes lots of people to examine ideas.
That could lead to problems. They also have another part of the
culture is disagree and commit. Once decision is made, so
there's two people. One is probably right, one is wrong, you
need to go with that one, embrace it and go ahead and basically,
what we say I still disagree. Basically, you're still wrong, but
I disagree but I'm going to help even if I don't agree. I don't
have to agree to help, but I have to help because I want to be a
team member. As I think about these things, my wife and I
celebrated our 46th wedding anniversary like Wednesday and
there's a chance that this conflict stuff could be useful in a
future career. There's a chance that when you get married, you
may not always see eye to eye and if you could be good at
resolving conflicts ... This is ... Software engineering
improving your personal lives. Boy, you handle these conflicts
so well. How did you do that? Well, I'm a software engineer so.
Of course. Summarizing Scrum is basically a kind of a guidelines
to self- organize the team, the big part of it is the stand- up
15 minutes questions, 15 minute meetings where you answer these
three questions, what did you do yesterday, what are you going
to do today, and are there any obstacles and you've got these
two roles, the Product Owner and Scrum Master that you rotate
around, so everybody has as chance to do it.