Okay, let's try the [ inaudible 00:01]. Ready. Set. Vote. Let's
see what colors we get. Lots of blues and oranges, so why don't
you talk it over. Ready. Set, let's vote as teams and see if the
colors change and vote. it's a lot bluer than it was last time
so let's see what it was. Explicit scenarios, starting with the
second one, it's explicit scenarios usually capture integration
tests. No, they're usually the acceptance test. This is the
thing. The customer you talk about, you got it on a 3x5 card,
that's probably an acceptance test. Declarative scenarios aim to
capture implementation as well as behavior, their aiming at
behavior, so people didn't vote for that one. The first one,
explicit requirements are usually defined with imperative
scenarios and implicit requirements. No, that was just like
Armando last time, just put all the words together. There's no
relationship between ... explicit/ implicit is orthogonal from
declarative and imperative, so that's the other thing. The right
answer was blue. All these are false. Any questions about that?
Good.