Let's go through the answers to this matching question. The
terms I'm trying to match are presentation, logic and
persistence here. We basically have the names and number of open
source and proprietary products here but what's the presentation
tier? The presentation tier is the first thing the client sees
when it ask a question. It's their first point of contact with a
server. That means that the presentation tier is going to be a
web server of some kind. Apache is a plausible answer to that.
Internet information server from Microsoft is an answer but
Firefox clearly is not because the presentation tier is some
part of the server and Firefox is a client. That rules out the
green answer and it rules out the blue answer over here. What
about the logic tier? Well, we said that's where your
application runs so rack and rails are certainly an example of a
logic tier that means that the red answer is still on the
running here. Then, the last one is the persistence tier. What
happens there, that's where stuff gets stored that survives a
cross invitations of HTTP request so a relational database,
certainly a plausible choice for that but the Apache web server,
well, web servers tend to be stateless. They're part of the
presentation tier that we scale out and one of the reasons they
can do that is because they don't manage persistent data where
the problem of multiple copies could arise. In this case, the
correct answer is the first one.