After our brief detour, remember what we’ ve done so far is we
talked about models and how they connect to the database. We
showed how you actually create the table in the database. By the
way, now you see how these two pieces go together, a migration
will create the table and the table will have certain columns
for the different attributes. That’ s how ActiveRecord knows at
runtime what attributes you can do reference on a model. It’ s
basically the column names. It essentially asks the database, “
Tell me what columns are available in this table,” and those
become the getters and the setters that are available on your
Ruby models. We’ ll talk a little bit more now about
ActiveRecord and some of the facilities for doing the other
operations. We saw the four CRUD operations. We saw C for
creating. Now we’ re going to do reading, updating and deleting.
How do you find things on the database? There’ s a class method
that inherits from ActiveRecord base called where. Not
surprisingly. It’ s meant to mimic the fact that the where
keyword existence sequel. It lets you select things based on
attributes. I can select a movie where its rating matches a
string. I can also more effectively write more complex
conditions where I substitute symbols of my choosing. These
could be any symbols I want. Then I provide a hash that maps
those symbols to the values that I want to match. Sometimes it’
s more clear to write a more complex query in this way because
it makes clear what the intent of the query is. I have some
cutoff in mind. I have some rating in mind. I’ m going to
separately specify what the values of those are. This is another
option for how to do it. This is a really bad idea. It’ s got
security implications that we’ re going to see later in the
course. In general, anytime that you’ re embedding a string into
a query, you had better trust that string. If that string in any
way was ever touched by a user, you must immediately assume the
user is evil or at best possibly incompetent and that just
jamming the string into a query like this could result in a
query that is either malformed or evilly formed which is
actually much worse. The reason to use things like this symbol
interpolation is as you might expect, there’ s extra machinery
in Rails that will go out of its way after the substitution is
done to make sure that you either end up with a legal statement
or at least end up with a statement that is not malicious. There
are a lot of standard tricks that evil users try that is exactly
aimed to people who write code like this. Rails has mechanisms
that will circumvent most of those if only you choose to use
them. A non- obvious thing about this though is that you can
chain these things together. For example, I can initially say, “
I’ m going to define kiddie to be movies where the rating is G.”
You might ask, “ When this is executed in Rails, what is the
result of doing this?” What you would think is that the result
is something like a collection of movies that have been
extracted from the database. That’ s actually not quite true.
The result is an object that if you ever do reference that will
cause the database query to happen, it gets evaluated lazily.
That means that I can now say there’ s also kids films and those
are kiddie films where the release date is let’ s say earlier
than 30 years ago. What’ s the impact of these two statements?
If query evaluation were eager or if it were immediate, in other
words, if the act of doing movie where actually made the
database query happen, then the code that I’ ve shown here would
result in two queries; one for each of the wheres. In fact, the
code that I’ ve shown here doesn’ t do any queries at all. At
some point, the semantics of where is that it’ s supposed to
return something that quacks like a collection. Remember the
Ruby concept of quacking like something. It means, it doesn’ t
really matter if your collection, you just need to do the things
that collections do. What do we know that collections do? One
thing collections do is they respond to each. They can enumerate
themselves. What’ s actually happening here, so that you
understand what’ s going on under the hood is at some point,
later on in the code, presumably we’ re going to say something
like old_ kid_ films dot each do something. We’ re going to go
through the collection and do something with each element. That’
s the time the query happens. Only the time we actually try to
get the result is the time the query happens. A consequence of
that is you can actually build up extremely sophisticated
queries by chaining together a lot of different conditions and
Rails has a fairly sophisticated optimizer that will generate
good sequel. At the end of the day, only when you try to
actually ask for the value of one of those objects, that’ s when
the query happens and not before. It’ s a very nice feature and
it’ s a part of ActiveRecord called active relation. It’ s
basically a relational algebra engine that’ s built in. What are
the ways can you read stuff? There’ s a collection of methods
that begin with find. The simplest version is if you happen to
know the primary key of something. When we talk about
controllers shortly, we’ ll show some examples where you
actually do know the primary key. You can just look up something
by its primary key as long as you’ re willing to risk an
exception if you got it wrong and it’ s not found. You could
also just say find_ by_ id, remembering that ID happens to be
the column name that Rails uses for the primary key which is
more friendly and that it just returns nil rather than throwing
an exception if that ID doesn’ t exist in the movies table. The
more interesting one is attribute based finders. Remembering
that we set up our movies table to have title and rating for
example. We could say, find all movies by rating or find by
rating a single or the first movie that matches this condition.
Find_ by_ rating! which as you’ ve know dot figure out by now.
We’ ll fit on exception. You’ re probably already a step ahead
of me and thinking, “ Aha, I know just how that works. That code
doesn’ t exist in any file. If you want to look for find_ by_
rating across all of the source code in your app, you would
never find it because of course, this is being handled by method
missing. You already saw an example of this, right? What’ s the
rule here? You could probably write this yourself. If you’ re
trying to call a method find by something and if that something
happens to match the attribute name of one of the columns in
your table then it gets converted into a sequel query basically
isn’ t something like the where conditions. In fact, in case you
are wondering, you can in fact say find by rating and title,
find by release date and something. Then the rule is if it’ s
find by X and Y and Z and they’ re all separated by ands and
underscores and they all match attributes names, then method
missing will do its thing. Again, a nice example of allowing you
to do a bunch of common cases, you get them for free. It’ s not
like this code exist somewhere and it’ s not being used because
it’ s method missing, this only happens if you actually try to
use this feature. It’ s not like you’ ve got a bunch of
functions sitting around that you’ re not using. How about
updating stuff? There are two ways to do it. Suppose we have
already used one of the finders to grab an instance of a movie
from the database. One thing we could do is we could modify the
attributes in place and then we can save the object. Remember,
the big difference here is between we have an in- memory copy
and we have a database copy. Those copies are distinct. What
ActiveRecord does is give us mechanisms to keep them in synced
to tie them together. Just because we’ ve changed the release
date in our in- memory copy, to update the database’ s copy, we
have to explicitly save the object out again. We could also
combine. There’ s a call update attributes that lets you
essentially pass a hash of attributes and their new values. It
operates atomically. If you try to update a bunch of attributes
at once, either they all get updated correctly or none of them
do. You could think of it as being transactional in that way. By
the way, a nice structural thing about ActiveRecord that we’ ll
see is there’ s many different ActiveRecord calls that can
modify the database. At the end of the day, they all end up
funneling through a single point called save. There’ s a way
that Rails allows you to do extra validation checks before
writing something in the database to make sure that you never
write invalid data for some reason. You only have to put that
check in one place because all of the other calls that modify
the database eventually funnel through there. We’ ll talk about
that when we talk about the more advanced Rails topics. Deleting
is straightforward. What might be interesting if you haven’ t
seen it before in Rails is that it’ s an instance method. You
first have to be able to name the object and then you tell it to
destroy itself. You could also write row sequel queries to do
this but there’ s actually a very good reason why you do this.
There is in fact a method called delete which really just maps
to what you would do in row sequel. The reason to call destroy
and the reason to call it as an instance method is again,
suppose again we’ ve got the Ruby world and we got the database
world. In the database world, deleting is simple. You vaporize
the row. The database is done with it like it never existed. It
may very well be the case in the world of your application life
is more complicated. For example, suppose I have movies in
reviews and suppose I delete a movie. At that point, any reviews
that depended on that movie have nothing to connect to anymore.
In terms of my app logic, there may be consequences to
destroying an object and I want to make sure that whenever the
object is destroyed, I have the chance to clean up other state.
As we’ ll see, destroy allows you to type other callbacks so
that when an object is destroyed, you can do various other
things. It’ s a little bit like finalizing Java if you want to
think of it that way. This is the reason that perhaps counter
intuitively destroys an instance method. You find the thing you
want to destroy and then you tell it to destroy itself. Ruby
helpfully gives us the technology so that once we’ ve actually
called destroy on an object, so now again, the database world,
the Ruby world Now the database is working that the object is
gone but we still got M. We’ ve got this data structure in Ruby.
What would prevent us from trying to modify the attributes even
though we know we’ ll never be able to save it again because we
deleted it from the database. As it turns out, this will fail
because once you’ ve destroyed an object from the database,
Rails will change the way that the titles that are works to
basically say, “ No, sorry you can’ t do that.” Once you’ ve
destroyed an object, you might think that the setters still work
but they’ ll actually raise exceptions. The object will have
been frozen. Again, this works because all access to the
internal state of an object is through these getters and setters
and we can modify it runtime how they behave. It’ s another
example of how a language feature is used in support of an
obstruction. Here’ s what we’ ve learned so far about
ActiveRecord which is by far the most interesting and important
part of Rails. This is sort of just getting your feet wet. If
you subclass from ActiveRecord Base, that’ s how you create a
model. That means that you can connect a model to the database
and get built- in behaviors for doing the four base of CRUD
operations. Because of convention over configuration, you can
deduce the name of the model, the name of the database table and
the name of the code file for your model are all related by a
simple set of rules. By default, ActiveRecord will give you free
getters and setters that are named after the table columns. They
all work the way you expect. In fact, they work a little better
than the way you expect. For example, different databases like
my sequel versus Postgres have different internal
representations for certain types like date times. Ruby has a
date time type. It has a bunch of different date time types.
When you assign something to a model attribute that has a date
time value in the database, one of the nice things Rails does is
convert back and forth between the representations. If the
database has a store as a date time, it will pars whatever the
database’ s representation of date time is. What you get handed
back is a Ruby date time object which has all the great date
time behaviors. Conversely, when you set a new value for it, you
can set the value to anything that Ruby thinks as a reasonable
representation of a date and a time and Rails will make sure
that it gets serialized correctly for whichever flavor of
database you’ re using. The getters and setters actually do
quite a bit. The thing that ties all these together is you’ ve
got an object in a memory. You’ ve got a row in the database
where you’ re persisting that object. Those two things are
distinct. ActiveRecord is an obstruction that tries to keep them
close together but it is not a perfect obstruction. There’ s
going to be times when you see it leak. One of them is like we
said, when you try to destroy an object, you still have the in
memory copy. You can’ t make the in memory copy just go away.
The best that you can do in a leaky obstruction is it will
prevent you from trying to make changes to the in memory copy.
It’ s kind of a rude reminder that, “ Hey, you’ ve deleted the
object.”