We're voting. We're voting. Okay, let me read the question one
more time because never so many have been so wrong for the same
reason. The method that contacts TMDb to search for a movie?
Take a little bit to think about that, in case you voted, say
red, before. Now that I'm trying to give it away. Let's try
another vote with my very big hint. What's going on here? I want
to see if people are on their toes. I see that the booth has
voted blue. Let's look at the possibilities here. I threw a
little bit of a curve ball at you, but it worked apparently. It
is true, we are about to embark on coding a controller method.
However, I also wanted people to remember in the model to
controller paradigm, where does the action occur that has to do
with any interesting computation around the data model? It
occurs in the model. Okay? The controller method is going to
receive the form submission and it is going to be responsible
for making the right thing happen with the model, but the
action, ultimately, of figuring out how to get data from
somewhere else and transform that into data that we can use to
populate our movie model, that is clearly model related logic.
At the end of the day, it's going to be something in the movie
model that does that and from then on, it should be easier to
figure out, you can't call find_in_TMDb on any ... you can't
have a specific movie be the recipient of that message because
you haven't found the movie yet. You have to go generally find
the movie and then use the information, so it's going to be a
class method of movie. I understand that you all have the
keyword controller in your brains, but the lesson here is
sometimes the keyword is not the answer.