We're going to launch right in today and talk about Ruby as a
modern object- oriented language. If you've come from the Java
world, which many of you have, there's all these concepts that
you have to assimilate when you do object- oriented programming.
You have to learn about objects, you have to learn about the
attributes of objects, and you talk about getters and setters on
attributes. You talk about the methods that objects support.
Maybe if you've done C++, you know about operator overloading.
There's things like interfaces which allow you to add other
behaviors to a class. Java also has these primitive types like
integers. You have to box and unbox them in order to do certain
things to them. At some point, you probably found yourself
asking whether there isn't a smaller set of mechanisms that
supports the things you're trying to do when you're using all
these different mechanisms in a language like Java or C++.
Ruby's dramatic simplification of how to deal with this is to
say everything is an object, everything. The only way you get
stuff done is by calling methods on objects. What does this mean
concretely? First of all, even the lowly integer is a true
object. That means that you can do things like call methods,
like days, on actual integers; three days ago will tell you how
many seconds it's been since three days ago. Now, in raw Ruby,
this won't work. It will work in Rails. I'll get back to why
that happens. To give you a sense, I can also say 50 dot
methods. I’ m asking the integer 50, " What methods do you
respond to? What things do you know how to do?" In fact I can,
explicitly in Ruby, talk about responding to, I can ask an
object directly, “ What methods do you respond to?” by using
this built- in respond to method. See how good I am at drawing?
I'm pretty good, huh? Yeah. In fact, all of these really can be
thought of as syntactic sugar around a single construct which is
the send method. It's a language primitive. That's the one that
says, “ Take the following method call and send it to the
object.” We say that the object is the receiver in that case.
The only thing Ruby cares about is whether the object you're
sending a message to knows how to respond to that message. For
example, if I say one plus two, what I'm really doing is saying
shorthand for sending to the receiver the object one, the plus
message, with an additional argument of two. That's really
what's going on internally at the language level. Plus is really
just another method and it's another that takes one argument
which is the thing to add to its receiver. Similarly, if I
dereference an array with square brackets, really I'm sending
the square bracket dereference method to the target array, and
I'm passing another argument which is what the sub- script is
that I want to get. We can do other examples like when we do
array assignment, " What's going on here?" Believe it or not,
this is a method call. There's a method call that means assign
to an array and, this time, we need two arguments – which sub-
script to assign and what the new value ought to be at that
place. The important thing here is that there's actually a
method to find on arrays, called bracket equals, and, when you
say, my array sub three equals foo, it's really just a
shorthand. Syntactic sugar for calling the bracket equals method
with those two arguments. This is a dramatically simplifying
thing that you … it takes a little bit of getting used to but
bear with me, for just a bit , as I work through a few more
examples. When I do a comparison, again, what am I doing? I'm
sending the target a message of double equals with another
argument of the thing to compare it to and, when I call up
regular old function, I'm sending to self which is the implicit
receiver. Right, if you don't see anything before the dot, it
means whatever the value of self is, and we'll have a lot more
to say about that when we talk about object orientation. We're
sending self the name of a method , my func, and one argument
that's expected by that method. The hope is that self has an
instance method called my func, in this case, and that my func
is prepared to accept an argument. That's what's going on there.
Remember, when we do this, okay, save yourself a lot of grief.
When you see the notation a dot b, it means we're calling the
method b on the object a. Okay, what does it not mean? It does
not mean that b is an instance variable of a. It doesn't mean
that a is some kind of a data structure, and b is one of the
fields of that data structure – it's nothing like that, right?
Keeping this in mind will help you parse Ruby expressions that
look a little confusing until you get more accustomed to the
language, at which point it'll seem very natural. Understanding
this distinction, keeping this one simple rule in mind, will
save you a lot of grief and confusion. When you say every
operation is a method call, go a little more deeply into that.
What does it mean? Here's three different uses of plus. Somebody
unfamiliar with a modern extremely object- oriented language
like Ruby might look at those three lines and say, " Wow, if
those are all legal calls, it must be the case that Ruby has
some pretty sophisticated type inference and type conversion in
place so that plus knows what to do depending on what the types
of its two arguments are." Now that you understand that
everything is an object and plus is just a method, it should be
clear that what's going on here is these are three different
methods. These three uses of plus are three different methods.
One of them is the class numeric definition of plus, another one
is the array class's definition of plus, and another one is the
string class's definition of plus. How does Ruby know which one
to use? To take the third example here, when I say y equals
quote hello plus quote world, what's the receiver of plus? The
receiver is this first argument hello and it's a string. The
string class is going to be the one where the plus method gets
looked up, the plus method is going to get past a second
argument, in this case world, and it had better know how to do
something sensible with that argument. The answer to the
question, " What if I say foo plus bar, and foo plus bar maybe
are of different classes or of different types, what happens
then?" In foo plus bar, foo is the receiver, plus gets sent to
it, and it will get past the argument bar, and it has to decide
whether it can do something sensible based on what kind of a
thing bar is. One last thing before we get off of this quick
intro topic. Poetry mode. I mentioned in a previous lecture that
I'm a really big fan of the minimum number of marks on the page
that make it easy and clear to write the code and for other
people to read the code. One of the ways that Ruby supports this
is through poetry mode. Here's an example of a legal Ruby
statement that came from one of my apps using poetry mode. You
can almost read it aloud and figure out what the code does.
Redirect to login page and return unless logged in. Code does
not get much more transparent than that. The reason this is
legal is because when parentheses around function call arguments
are optional, in other words when the parser would not be
confused by omitting them, Ruby lets you omit them, and also
because braces around hashes can often be omitted if the context
is unambiguous. For example, if we rewrote this with fully
parenthesized syntax, we could see that – redirect to login
page, this redirect to is a method that expects one argument –
and is a standard Boolean connector which you've seen before –
return, in this case return isn't returning any explicit value
so it's like a function call but there's no argument – and
logged in happens to be another function; I didn't add the empty
parens around it. Again, as you get used to the language, it'll
become very natural and very clear to you when it's okay to
leave stuff out. Here's another example. Dave alluded, in one of
the earlier lectures, about the ability to write things like, a
should be greater than or equal to seven when you're expressing
test cases. How can that possibly work? Again, if we
parenthesize defensively, should is really just a function that
takes one argument. The argument that it takes is the
expression " be greater than or equal to seven." In this case, I
happen to know that b isn't a variable. It's actually another
function call. It's a method call. In the poetry mode example,
I've been able to omit both the empty parent around b, which
tell us it's a function call with no arguments, and the parent
around should which capture its argument. One last example, and
this is an example of omitting braces when it's obvious from
context that something is a hash. This is an example of a call
that was very common in Rails applications saying to create a
URL that links to a particular procedure in your program that
handles some user interaction with the web app. What we've done
here is there's actually two things we've omitted. This is a
function of one argument and the argument is a hash. Because
it's unambiguous in parsing, not only can we leave out the
parens around the function argument, we can leave out the braces
that normally would go around the hash literal. Now again, the
first time you see this, it's a little confusing, you might not
always realize when it's acceptable to do it and when it's not.
When in doubt, you can always parenthesize defensively. In
general, you'll very quickly get used to when this makes sense
to do and you're going to find that it makes your code much more
readable.