Let's do initial vote. Initial vote sold majority for red with
some yellow and orange. Take about 30 seconds, there's enough
descent. Okay, let's do the second vote. Red has gained a few
concretes but not unanimous. Before we discuss the answer let's
look back in what's going in the code here. Remember I said, my
claim is that this test could be easily made the pass. We're
going to do that in just a moment. What we're actually doing in
this test is by setting up this expectation what we're saying is
all we really care about is that as a result, by the end of this
test case. By the time we reach the word end and the execution
here, as a result of whatever we did in this test case. At some
point somebody should have tried to call the find in TMDB class
method of movie and should have tried to pass with the argument
hardware. Now if you've been sort of putting the pieces together
about the discussion we had about method missing and meta-
programming and so forth. You might realize that there's a very
natural way to implement this in Ruby right? We basically can
say, " Oh if you're expecting that some method or rather is
going to get called, I know what we can do." We could just open
up the class that is supposed to define that method. Redefine
that method ourselves so that we can watch whether anybody ever
calls it. Let your test case run, and then when your test case
is over we can actually list that anybody actually try to call
it or not. With that background in mind, it provides us stand-
in for a real method that doesn't exist. Clearly it's doing
that, so the first choice is true. It would override the real
method, even if it did exist. This is also a true, and it's
extremely important. We're going to come back to another soft
check question that hammers on why that is. It can be issued
either before or after the code that should make the call.
That's the one we had fall down. If we want to be able to spy on
a method, we have to indicate our desire to do that before
someone actually tries to call it. If we didn't do that,
there'll be no way to sort of after the fact to ask who called
what method. If redefine the method so that we can spy on it,
then we actually have the ability to check whether the method
called correctly. It absolutely exploits open classes because
the way they were doing this we're essentially redefine,
surgically redefining that method in place. There's a really
good elaboration in the book, I think it's a good elaboration.
That's probably because I wrote it, but it's about how you would
do this in languages that are statically complied or languages
where you have to re- link whenever you want to override the
definition with particular method in a particular class. The
bottom line, that the TLDR version is dynamic languages with
open classes are your friend for this. Does everybody understand
why the only false statement is the third statement, the red
statement? Okay, this gets better.