All right. Now what we're going to do is go back, we went
through Ruby and part way through rails here and ready to go
back back to good old [ inaudible 00:00:08] design now. [
inaudible 00:00:10] driven design User Stories which we've
talked a lot about. So why do software projects fail? Well, they
don't do what customers want or the projects are late or they're
over budget or their hard to maintain [ 'above' 00:00:22] or
they're all of these, all of the above right? So what is it
about Agile that tries to avoid these failures that are so
famous? So let's do a little review of Agile. So Agile is
working closely with customer to develop requirements and work
with everybody involved in the project, you do these iterations
that are pretty quick every week or 2 so you don't [ 'sink'
00:00:43] with the customer and instead of these longer phase of
the plan and development methods. And before you do the next
thing, you check with the customers to make sure they're happy
with what you've done so far. So you're validating, building the
right thing in building this thing right. The actual iteration
that corresponds to chapters of our textbook is what we're doing
now and what's highlighted in yellow is what we're talking about
today. So talking to the customer, behavior driven different
design and then measuring velocity, we'll do all that today. So
what is Behavior Driven Design? That is the idea that you ask
questions about what the app is supposed to do before you start
writing it and during development, so this is a different idea.
Rather than you'll build it and then show it to the customer. So
and it's focusing on validation versus verification. How are you
going to get requirements in cooperating with the customer?
We're going to use User Stories. Stories, that sounds like fun,
let's write up some stories. These are these very lightweight
short descriptions of what how the app's going to be used and
you're going to be doing this very soon. And the BDD part of it
Behavior Driven Design as opposed to implementation as you're
trying to capture the behavior. You can think of it as
acceptance test level or integration test level. Armando will
talk about test driven design in the future segments about ...
and that's more about the implementation. So what are these User
Stories? What do they look like? Well they look like this, this
3 by 5 card. So it's 1 to 3 sentences in just plain old English.
It has to be shorten to fit in a 3 by 5 card and it's not
something you write yourself, you write in conjunction with the
customer. It comes from a start up company called [ inaudible
00:02:30], they came up with this format which is the feature
name which is at the top and then this 3 part sequence, the
essay and the type of stakeholder, like our ... in this case
it's I'm a movie fan but it could have been the box office
operator. So essay kind of a stakeholder so that I can achieve
some goal in this case so that I can share the movie with other
fans. I want to do some test so I wanted to add a movie to
Rotten Potatoes database. So the 3 phases can be there and they
can be in any order according to [ inaudible 00:03:02] company.
And basically what you're meeting with a customer and agreeing
with these 3 by 5 cards is coming up with the acceptant test
before you write any code. So where did these 3 by 5 cards come
from? They came from the user inter- phase community and the
user inter- phase community does a lot of work with dealing with
people and what they found was these 3 by 5 card, how can 3 by 5
card be threatening? Anybody can deal with 3 by 5 cards. When
you start building code and you show that they kind of feel
constrained by the code you build because they don't want you to
have to throw it away, so you ... but because we want to get to
what the customer really wants rather what they think they want,
we want to have them involved in the brainstorming and 3 by 5
cards are really easy way to do it. It's also takes almost no
time to fill these out and once you get a bunch of cards, you
can rearrange then, re- prioritize them, decide what you want
and you can ... obviously easily threw cards away if you decide
you don't like the User Stories. And then over the developments,
it's easy to create these new 3 by 5 cards. Now what you write
depending on which kind of stakeholder you are. So this is 2
descriptions of the same feature in which we will talk about a
lot which is a theater going application which is Armando worked
on is community theater group. So see which of my phones are
going to a show. So as a theater goer so that I can enjoy the
show with my friends, I want to see which of my Facebook friends
are [ 'given' 00:04:28] the show. So from the patron's
perspective, as a box office manager so that I can induce the
patron to buy a ticket, I want to assure which of her Facebook
friend are [ 'going for show' 00:04:36]. So there's 2 different
perspectives with 2 different goals. Okay, so that User Stories,
now really User Stories have hundreds of these stories, so
many ... it's easy to fill up 3 by 5 cards to come up with
potential things that you want to do, a lot easier to do that
than to build these things. So there's something that's call the
backlog which those the ones I'm working on and typically even
when a project will be done the first of the week she still have
a bunch of 3 by 5 cards left and that's what the backlog is and
we'll see that with tools to track these things. You put these
things in order in the backlog as well so that when you get some
time you'll take them out of the backlog and work with them. So
as you do an iteration, you'll be picking things out of the
backlog in priority order and you can even organize these User
Stories together so you can say this is going to be next
release, these stories. Now, another thing related to User
Stories that's been useful to these programmer teams is what's
called the Spike and what a Spike is is not a user story, not
something that the customer wanted you to do, but something you
need to do for projects. So Spike is this quick investigation
into something that's a problem for the project, it's not a
feature exactly that the customer asked for. So what we're going
to do recommendation algorithms like Amazon has recommendation
algorithms, if you like this book you'll like that one. Someone
has to go learn more about recommendation algorithms, so you put
that Spike there on the list of to do things and even if you
build some code to try and figure out the algorithms that you're
not part of the code development process you're just doing some
exploratory investigation and just throw these stuff away when
it's ready to go ahead. Okay. So that's User Stories