Seams are such an important concept that I'm giving them a
little section all to themselves. Basically, this definition,
which is my favorite one, is from Michael Feathers who wrote a
book called Dealing Effectively With Legacy Code. A lot of what
we have in our book about legacy code is really inspired by his
framing of the problem. His definition of a seam is it's a place
where you can change the behavior of your application without
changing the source code. It's useful for testing because one of
the things we need to do in unit test is isolate the behavior of
the code that we're testing with these particular tests from the
behavior of other things that it depends on. Even in the example
we just saw, suppose we actually had already coded our find_ in_
tmdb method in the movie model, one possible reaction be, in
that case, you no longer need to have a seam where you're
essentially faking out the behavior of code that doesn't exist
because, hey, the code exists now. The real reason to use the
seam is not just because the code doesn't exist immediately.
It's because if the code existed but was broken, or somebody
else had made a change to the code, that might have caused your
test to fail, the idea's you can still test in isolation the
other things that depend on that code. You can break that
dependency by a tastefully inserted seam. Should_ receive is an
example, it uses Ruby's open classes to create a seam for
isolating method calls from each other. Happily, after every
single test case, Rspec basically resets all of the seams. If
there's a seam that I'm temporarily creating, like I did in our
example, because I wanted to spy on a method that didn't even
exist yet in the movie class. If that method had existed and I
chose to spy on it, after my test case finishes running for the
very next test case, that stunt double or that spy is torn down.
That means that in every test that I want to spy on, I have to
reestablish that condition which is not a big deal. We'll see
that there are ways to do it for a group of tests at a time. The
important issue is I can keep tests very independent this way,
right? For a very specific test, I can say, " I need to stub out
these places where the test depends on other things. I need to
have a controllable [ canned 00:02:04] behavior of the things
that it depends on because that makes my tests execute
predictably. That's what gives some independence and
repeatability and the other things that are nice about tests. We
already know that we could write ... we have a spec that's going
to fail because we wrote the spec but the controller method, we
emptied the body out. There's nothing in there so what's the
minimum amount of code? Remember, the goal here is what's the
least amount of code we can write that would make our failing
test pass? That would make it go from red to green? The
expectation, the should_ receive said,  " We believe that the
controller method should call movie find_ in_ tmdb." A logical
thing for us to do to pass the test would be let's actually make
that happen. Here it is. Here is my modified controller method.
All I have done is add a line that does exactly what the test
says. It calls find_ in_ tmdb. It passes params from the search
terms. Now, you could say, " Is there actually anything being
tested here?" There is, right? As a programmer, I just made the
assumption that if I look at params search terms that that's
where the title of the movie would have come in from. If my
simulated post in my test case doesn't match that, or if I was
wrong about the name of the foreign fields or anything like
that, even this trivial test would help find that level of
stupid error. It's still the case that we don't have the find_
in_ tmdb method in movie. We have yet to write it. The important
thing is, we have actually verified about something that's going
on here, right? In fact, we've done a couple of things. We've
done a couple of things. We know that the spec, we could say
that it drove the creation of the code that goes into the
control reaction. It made us think about what the control
reaction has to do. It made us think about what external
entities the controller has to depend on to do its work. In this
case, it depends on the method and the model. It made us realize
that even if that method and the model happen to already exist,
for the purposes of testing, there's an articulation point
between the controller and the model. That's a good place to put
a seam so that we can keep separate the behavior of this test
from the behavior of the things that that code depends on. Now,
one thing that we haven't really addressed is, we haven't
written find_ in_ tmdb but shouldn't that return something? At
this point, all we had done ... all we've done is call it. We
haven't actually said what it should return, right? All we ...
we did the minimum necessary to make this spec pass but it's not
clear that this is going to lead us to the code we actually
need. We're going to return to this in just a moment. In fact,
I'm making the example almost pedagogically a little bit
oversimplified because I'm trying to drive home an important
point which is that one test maps to one behavior. The one
behavior we should care about in this test is the controller
action calls find_ in_ tmdb. The question, should find_ in_ tmdb
actually return something? If so, what happens to that data? We
just haven't addressed that yet. It doesn't mean we don't care
about it but what find_ in_ tmdb should return, that's going to
be something that's tested by the code the test find_ in_ tmdb.
What should happen to the stuff that it does return? That's a
question of what is going to happen when we try to generate the
view? The whole point of calling the model is to get information
for the view. We'll answer those questions in just a moment but
let's take stock for a moment of where we are. We're going to
start a list of things we know how to do in a test. We can setup
this expectation that says, " Certain objects should receive a
certain method call and we can optionally specify what argument
is supposed to be passed to it." In this case, we cared, right?
We cared because one of the things we're testing is, the
controller has to get data from the user and make sure that the
correct aspects of that data make it all the way into the model
method. In our case, we cared both about the fact that find_ in_
tmdb gets called. Also, about what argument is going to get
passed to it. Both of those things are relevant to the behavior
of it should call a model method that is going to actually query
the database. There are some cases where you care only about one
or the other. For example, if I just care about whether a method
is called and it takes no arguments, or for whatever reason,
this test case is only concerned about control flow and not
about what data is getting passed, I can leave out the whiff.
That means that as long as the method is called at all, no
matter what argument, the expectation will be correctly
fulfilled. This is one of a set of things that we're going to
learn how to do that allow us to specify in a test, what is the
thing that should happen and then how to go back and backfill
the code to make that thing actually happen. Let's make sure we
all agree about being on the same page about this. Eventually,
we'll have to write a real find_ in_ tmdb method. When that
happens, what are we going to do? We can replace the call to
should_ receive with the call to the real method. We can ensure
the API to the real method that we wrote matches the API that we
thought we wanted when we originally did the test with should_
receive. We should keep the seam exactly as it is but we might
have to change the way the seam looks because when we actually
wrote the method, the API turned out to be different than the
one we had on our original test. Or we can just remove the
entire test case, that we wrote. Now that find_ in_ tmdb exists,
the test case isn't testing anything interesting anymore.
Thinking ...