With that in mind, we can do a question. Cards out. Every blank
in Ruby accepts a blank but not vice versa. Let's see if you
followed all the terminology. Let's do our initial vote. Initial
vote. Initial. I like the holding up smart phones. Initial vote.
Okay, we have a lot ... Lot of votes for blue. Majority of votes
for blue, I would say. Let's talk through why blue is actually
the correct answer. Congratulations those of you voted blue.
What is an iterator? Remember, an iterator is something that is
responsible for knowing how to reach into a collection and get
elements out of it. What it's going to do with those elements?
Well, that's why you have to pass a block to a iterator. An
iterator is really just one special case of a yield statement.
That might have made you think that orange is the right answer,
but if you put the sentence together, every yield statement
accepts an iterator, no, that doesn't make any sense. An
iterator is actually just one usage of a yield statement.
Similarly, closures are certainly involved here. Closures is
really just the name of the concept by which the procedural
environment carries around its variables with it. That's not
correct. Every block accepts an iterator. Well, that's just ...
It happens to be backwards. Those are the correct two words. I
tried every combination of words that I thought might be
confusing and for people who aimed to just pick the answer that
has keywords in it, it wouldn't work. Okay, but you all are
smarter than that. To summarize what we've learned about Ruby.
We saw duck typing before. It's a way to encourage reuse by not
caring about the classes of things but only caring about what
method something responds to. We saw a particular interesting
example of that right now which is that if you create a class
that responds to the each method and if your implementation of
each uses yield to yield control back to a block, you can make
things like iterators. You can assume that the blocks that get
called will have the variables and scope that they had when they
started out. This is an extremely, extremely common Ruby you're
going to see all over the place. You'll become very familiar
with it and the good news is that when we talk about Java script
later on in the course, you're going to feel right at home
because it's really exactly the same idea. The last thing I'm
going to say is like any programming language, you learn it more
by doing it. It'll become easier as you go. That's why we have
an all new homework assignment called The Oracle of Bacon which
you're going to learn about pretty soon that will give you even
better Ruby ops.