With that in mind, suppose we've done a simple where, and we've
looked at this 'movie'. No, there's no trickery here, okay? The
'movie' exists. It doesn't throw an exception. Now, right after
we do this another application writes into the database
directly, perhaps it's another legacy app that's running
alongside ours, and in the database table it makes a change to
some attribute of 'movie'. Let's say it changes the title. So
just after that instance, what is the value of 'movie'? Does it
get updated automatically because of the way ActiveRecord
connects you in- memory data objects to the database? Does it
get updated automatically because ActiveRecord is able to use
metaprogramming to do some of this magic? Is it not updated
automatically, but if you re- executed a where, to sort of
reload it, then you would get the updated value. Or does this
behavior depend in some way on the underlying database? Is it
undefined, and just one of these things you shouldn't do?
Initial vote ... Initial vote says ... Initial vote ... Initial
vote. We have a majority of you for red, with a minority view, I
would say, for orange, and a couple of others. Okay, let's see
if anybody has changed their minds. Second vote. Second vote.
Second vote. Second vote. Second vote ... I would say the margin
for red has increased, but it is far from unanimous. Let's go
through these. Updated automatically because an ActiveRecord
model connects your app to the database. Well it tries to do
that, right? But they're still separate things. There's no ...
If somebody goes around our app and directly into the database,
which is what the question is assuming, there's no way for our
app to sort of magically know about this fact, right? The
database is really more like a passive repository that we're
talking to, so if our app is using ActiveRecord to talk to the
database, but there is some other app that is talking to the
database separately, our app has no real way of understanding
what's going on there, right? The moment after the database
table is directly updated, we have no idea about that fact. As
far as we know, nothing has happened. What about updated
automatically because ActiveRecord uses metaprogramming? It
certainly does use metaprogramming. It does it to make a lot of
the connections easier, but again, there is no magical way for
the database to notify us, generally speaking, that, " Hey, this
has changed." If another app went in behind our backs
essentially and did it, but of course, if we reload it, and
there's more than one way to reload a record, but 'movie.
reload' would also have worked, but in this example this
actually will get us the new value, and woe- be- unto us if we
have made local changes to that value without reflecting those
changes back to the database, right? Our local values would be
stomped on if we did this, but the lesson here is that the
database is a separate piece of machinery from the application.
We're trying to bring them as close together as we can, but if
another app goes in behind our back and makes changes directly
in the database, unless we take special external steps to get
notified of that somehow, we have no way of knowing. Lets have a
little bit of a discussion about this because I see that people
have questions about it. Let's start ... Yes, let's just go from
the back. Speaker 2: I thought that this 'movie. where' thing
didn't return the database object, or any information actually,
from the database, but it was actually pointed to a SQL query
that would eventually, once you dereference 'movie', then it
would go and access the database. Speaker 1: Actually you're
right. You're right. Technically I would ... Yes. Are there
people who did not vote red, but it was for that reason? Group:
Yes. Speaker 1: Okay, you're all actually way smarter than me.
Yes, and ironically, by the way, in rails 2- point- something
and earlier, this wasn't the case. Rails 2. X actually had eager
queries. So all the benefits of chaining lazy things would not
have worked, but yes, that's ... Technically what I should have
done ... You get a free thing from the [ Schreid- bag 00:03:34].
Remind me. What I should have done is, you know, put 's- movie',
or something that would have forced the evaluation to take
place. But yes, that's very well observed, but technically no
query is happening here. The query doesn't actually happen until
I try to consume the value in some way. Very well pointed out.
All of you who were going to point out the same thing, likewise,
very well pointed out.