So let's try another one of these poles here. So which
statements are which statement is not true about service
oriented architecture. Service oriented architecture does not
affect performance. Silo'd systems are likely completely down on
a failure so service oriented architecture must handle partial
failures. Service oriented architecture improves developer
productivity primary through use. And no service oriented
architecture service can name or access another service's data;
it can only make requests for data through an external A.P.I.
Alright. So look for couple seconds and then vote.   Okay now.
Alright, everybody's orange yeah yeah that's right that's the
downside of service oriented architecture effects performance.
Two down side effects performance some but computers are so
fast, software productivity can't be slowed. But, the fact that
they could have partial failures probably a bigger problem that
mounting system if it crashes, it's often air. This one pieces
of it cannot work so customers might complain that this isn't
even working right you can't and tell because some service works
and some of it best