What happens just to recap if you use printf to print debugging
messages in your production application? Cards out. Raise an
exception, grind to a halt, continue messages lost forever,
continue messages go into the log file, you'll be stricken down
in a fit of rage by the powers that be, or you've already lost
your card. Yeah and since most people have voted correctly,
let's just go through the answers. Raising an exception? Nope.
Rails is nice enough not to raise exceptions for things that are
not really exceptional. You trying to print a message is not
exceptional. Your app will continue, but the messages go into
the log file. No. You can do that but you have to explicitly use
the logger. Printf does not automatically do that for you. If
there were SaaS gods, they might well strike you down, but there
aren't, so you don't need to worry about that option. Indeed
your app will continue, but the messages will get lost forever,
which is almost never the thing you want. Just get used to
thinking about debugging in a different way,. This is no longer
about you and the terminal. There's too many moving parts to
help that work out.