Moving on with our tour, we have a very quick introduction to
models. Next we're going to get a quick introduction to
controllers and views, the other two pieces of the MVC equation,
and let's go back to our 'cookbook approach'. We already know
how to add a new model, or change things about an existing
model. Now we want to add a new action. A new thing that you can
do to a model. To add a new action, remember, what do you need
in a model view controller system? Well, in order for the
controller to do its work, you've got to be able to get from a
URI, to which method in the controller is going to actually
handle that, and we saw that the routing subsystem is where that
gets done, and there's a [ fall 00:00:32] called 'routed. rb'
that you can set up, although the default setup essentially
gives you the routes for all of the 'CRUD actions' on your
models. You also need to add the actual code that does the thing
you want to do. Remember that when we say, " Add controller
code," most of the time, really where the action happens is in
the model, right? The controller code is really just there to
mediate between the views and what's in the model, so the code
that you are adding in the controller tends to be pretty small.
You've probably already added the code in the model that does
the actual work. All you need to do now is basically connect
that to the rest of you app. Make sure that there is something
there for it to render. Remember, the 'http' is a request reply
protocol. That means that whenever you do a request to the
server something has got to come back. Usually that something is
a view, so you've got to make sure that there is some view
associated with the action. One possibility is that each view,
or each action, has its own separate view associated with it,
but as we'll see, another possibility is to essentially re- use
the same view for different actions. As long as there is
something to be rendered you're okay. We're going to use the
'show action', and the view that goes along with it, as our
walk- through example here. The book walks through the 'index
action', which is a little bit different, so this way you get
two different types. Remember, the responsibilities in model
view controller. The model is where all the action happens. The
model manipulates the data, talks to the database. The
controller gets stuff out of the model and makes it available to
the view. So what method are we going to write? We're going to
write the method, or the 'controller action', I would guess,
that given ... You want to see information about a particular
movie, is going to get that information from the model, or from
the database via the model I guess, and create a view that
displays that information, kind of a detail view. The reason
that we can expect to create a method that can consume the
primary key ID of something is when we create the index, which
is the listing of all movies, next to each one there is a link
that takes you to the detail page for that movie, and those
links are basically constructed so that their route already
includes the ID of the movie. The end- user would never be
expected to know this, but if the end- user is just picking
something off of a list, and if we get to generate that list, we
could just make sure that the links already all point to the
right place. That's what the index example walk- through in the
book sets up. It sets up a view where all of the links have the
ID embedded in them. We're going to show where all this comes
from, but remember, the overall template here is, when we set an
instance variable like '@ movie' in a controller method, it's
going to magically become available in the view. The view is
going to display the data, maybe allow the user to do something
with it. In this case it's going to be showing some description
of the movie text and rating, and some other stuff, and we'll
show the view in a moment. Then we'll see what other things we
might want to put on that page, and how does the user get to
that page to begin with? Let's go to 'Pastebin'. Okay. What's
our view going to look like? Well we're going to assume that we
can set up that '@ movie' variable so that in the view we can
just have details about, we can use the '@ movie' variable and
de- reference its title. We can de- reference its release date
and pretty- print it in a nice way. We can de- reference its
rating. This is Haml. How do we get to this point? How do we
actually figure out the controller methods, the routes and so
forth, that we need to use to do this? One of the nice things
that Rails gives you is basically built- in helpers that will
generate URLs that have the right thing in them. So we said when
we generate that list of movies in the 'index view', that the
links that could be generated automatically have the right
information in them to include things like the primary key of
the movie. This is a table that's actually reproduced from the
book, and it shows that the default route- set that you get when
you create a new app is that for each model you get routes that
will allow you to generate RESTful URIs for the 'index action',
which is list all of the instances you have, the 'CRUD actions',
create re- update, delete, and actions called 'new' and 'edit',
which are only necessary in a web browser, because they're sort
of half of doing an operation. When you think about ... When you
create a new movie, from your point of view as a human being,
there's actually two steps involved, right? You have to get a
blank form that you fill in, and then you submit the form, and
the data in the form is what's used to create the movie. The
reason that it looks like, even though we're only doing the
'CRUD actions', that there is seven things here, well one of
them is the 'index action', which is not really a 'CRUD action',
but it lists all the elements of the collection, and the other
two, 'new' and 'edit, are sort of the first half of an
interaction that takes two steps to do. We're going to start
from that index view that the book develops, and in the code
that's in the view, you'll see things like, " Link to movie
path," with a primary key in it. 'Movie path' is what's going to
generate this URL helper, so give a 'movie path' an argument,
it's going to turn it into a URL that looks like this, and then
it encodes the ID of the movie we want to see. In the view
that's going to end up looking like just a plain old link that
you can click on. The URL is already constructed, and when it
gets matched against the different routes, it's going to match
the movies' ID route with the 'GET method'. That means that the
ID is a stand- in, it's a wild card, for this part of the route,
the digit ' 3 ',  so that's going to be available in the
array that our 'controller action' sees. So
we're starting the moving parts one by one. The first moving
part is figure out, " What route does this URI match?," and if
there's any wild cards embedded in that route, pull the wild
card parameters out. Make them available as part of the
hash, and now we also know, from rake routes, what
'controller action' that's going to call. How do we know that?
Well, I'm going to look ... in my application here, which I'm
going to temporarily stop. If I run 'rake routes', it will look
into my routes file and show me all of the mappings that have
already been set up for me. So this is saying that, for example,
when I'm doing 'GET' of a single movie, when I 'GET' with a URL
that matches 'movies/ ID', wit 'ID' as a wild card, that's going
to try to call the 'show action' in the movies' controller. So
that's where my code logically has to go in order to handle that
request. Let's get the app started again. Ouch. Okay, so we've
seen that. The URI matches. Wild cards get pulled out. We know
which 'controller action' we're going to call, and in that
'controller action', which in our case is really short, the one
and only thing it needs to do is get information from the model,
and it does that by calling 'movie. find'. We know the primary
key of the movie the user wants to look at, so we can just look
it up directly. We're going to assign that to the instance
variable movie, and then that variable becomes available in the
view. What is the view? Well, remember we said, " By convention
over configuration, you don't have to worry about the names of
things, as long as you follow some rules." The rule here is that
when you finish executing a 'controller action', unless you say
otherwise, Rails will look for a view that has the same name,
but with HTML. erb or HTML. haml attached to it. In that case
we'll look for 'show. html. haml' in the movies' subdirectory of
views. We'll render it, and if there's any variables that are
used in the view, like '@ movie', we'll substitute the values
that the controller computed. That's basically the round trip
through the app. We could also let the user return to the 'movie
list'. We could, for example, what's the RESTful URI that names
the collection? The list of all movies? Well, there's a helper
called 'movies path' that will return a route that maps to the
'index action', and 'rake routes' would show that. So 'movies
path' with no arguments links to the 'index action', so we could
put something in our view that says, " Here's some text to show,
and here's the hyperlink." The URL will be generated by calling
this method, and again, the reason that this is all segregated
in the routing subsystem is if you change the names of routes,
the way some of the routes work, you don't have to manually
propagate those changes through all of your HTML templates,
because you're generating the routes at run- time based on the
information out of that file.