Last time we started our high level introduction to the Ruby
language and some of the cooler things about it that you might
have been unfamiliar with if you're coming from a language like
Java. We briefly saw one of the interesting things about Ruby is
how you can handle iterating through elements of a collection. I
want to spend a little more time on that because the iterators
we saw using each and when I mentioned that you actually
shouldn't be doing iteration in an imperative for loop kind of
style, but you should be letting the data structures manage
their own traversal that's really just one example of a much
more general mechanism in Ruby called, yield, which is what
we're going to talk about next. I'm going to start by looking at
the way that iterators are typically handled in imperative
languages like Java. If you've seen this kind of Java code
before, typically, you have some kind of collection. In this
case a list and if you want to iterate over the collection, you
hope that it implements the interface for iteration and you have
to setup a new iterator you periodically ask the iterator if
there's any more elements in the collection. If so, you ask it
give you the next element and then you do some stuff with that
element. The reason I'm calling this inelegant is that it mixes
up two things. In red, there's code that is concerned with doing
stuff with elements of the list. In blue, is stuff that's really
just the mechanics of getting those elements out. It would be
nice if those things could be better separated. For those of you
who are Berkeley students and took 61A when it was still taught
in Scheme, one of my personal favorite languages, you actually
have already seen this mechanism. If you remember things like
map and filter, the idea is that you would say, “ map,” you
would give it a function and you would give it a list. In
Scheme, a list is the only type, so you don't have to worry
about what types of things are able to be mapped because the
list was your only choice. In Ruby, this more or less becomes
the same thing. Remember that the braces can be used in some
cases as substitute for the do and end that would go around a
block. Map takes a block of one argument and it just applies the
block to each element in the collection. If you remember filter
from the days of Scheme. We have select which does pretty much
the same thing in Ruby. This time I've actually written it out
using " do" and " end" instead of the brackets. In fact, you can
combine things. I can take a map of a lambda expression that
operates over a filter and similarly in Ruby. I can take a list.
I can call select to filter out some elements of it. That will
return a new copy of the list containing only the filtered
elements and then I can call a map on the result of that. This
is one of the ways that Ruby inherits spiritually from
functional languages of which Scheme is an example. I think of
it as turning iterators inside out compared to what you would do
in a language like C+ plus or Java. Java you say, you hand me
every element of the collection, I'll do some of the element and
then I'll ask you if there's any more elements left. Whereas in
Ruby you go the other way around, you say, “ Here's the thing
that I want to do to each element of the collection.” You, the
data structure, you go ahead and manage the collection so that
you can give me each element as needed and I'm not worried about
that part. Let's do a real example of this to show how it would
work. Here, I've defined. What I said before, was in Ruby, the
only thing we care about is what methods do you respond to?
Here, I'm creating a class called, random sequence. What this
class is going to do is give me back an object that will
generate a list of random numbers between one and some limit and
it will generate up to num numbers in that list. For example. I
can call it with “ 10,4,” meaning I want a new sequence of four
random numbers between 1 and 10. How does this actually work?
First of all, I'm going to prove to you that it does work by
just pasting this into a Ruby Interpreter window. Of course, I
have to actually start the Ruby Interpreter, and now I can grab,
here's just a little chunk of code that … There we go. This
little chunk of code actually created a new random sequence
object and it called each on it. Remember, we said, as long as
it responds to each. Each is a promise that I can manage a
traversal of my own data structure. In this case, we generated a
new random sequence object and we returned each element one at a
time. What is that actually mean? How’ d we do that? Look at our
definition of each. We already saw it times before. It just
says, “ Repeat this block some number of times.” However may
that second argument was and what's going on in the block? This
is the first exposure many of you have had to this. This is
yield. Yield says, “ Transfer control back to the thing that
called me because it has a block waiting for me.” Down here,
when we called random sequence and the argument to each is this
block right here. This block is what's going to get called with
the argument of Yield. You can see Yield is yielding one value
and this block is setup to take one value. It's one value
between the vertical bars. What happens is each is actually
called and each time we hit yield, yield essentially transfers
control back to this point. This is turning the iterator inside
out. All we had to do was define some way that each would be
able to use yield to give back objects one at a time. It is a
pretty nifty construct. Iterators are actually just one nifty
use of Yield that it used to we've already seen and that's why I
wanted to start with them. Let me show another interesting thing
you can do. This is when you start to see how Yield can help you
clean up and dry out your code a lot better. On the left is a
very typical idiom and languages that provide a way to
manipulate files. There's a library called to open a file.
There's a library called to close the file. Typically what you
have to do is you call, file open. You do some stuff on the file
and then you close the file. That's probably the way that you're
used to thinking about things but we don't believe in doing
things just because we've always done in that way. What would be
a more Rubyistic way to do this? It would be to realize that the
pattern of open a file, do some stuff and close a file is a very
common pattern. The open and close parts are the same for
everybody. The only part that's different is what happens in
between the two. We can actually use yield to extract them and
this is actually how Ruby's file call works. Instead, we define
an open filename method, which does whatever it has to do to
open the file to get a file descriptor and then it yields that
file descriptor back to a block. How does that look like when
you use it? In your code, you could say, “ file open with a
filename” and then present it was a block. Inside the block, you
can do stuff with the file. What's going to happen here? I'm
going to call file open. That's going to transfer control up to
the open call. The open call will actually open the file. It
will yield the descriptor back to me. Now I'm here and I can do
stuff with the file. When my block is over, where am I? I'm back
in this function after the yield. In here, I can close my file
and do any other clean up. I've extracted out the common parts
and I've essentially used, yield to put something around as
opposed to having two separate function calls. I've exposed one
call instead of two. Blocks are closures. This is another
concept, although it's taught in 61A and in Scheme, it's not
present or at least not present in an obvious way in a lot of
modern language. A closure is basically the set of all the
variable bindings, all the variables with their values that you
can see at a given point in time. If you remember in 61A, they
called this an environment and you drew diagrams about them.
That's what this is. What does this mean in terms of yield and
why do we care about it? If we go back to our random sequence
example and what was happening here, when we call random
sequence new and then recall each on it, what's this variable, “
i?” This is just a random local variable. Here it is, “ i” as in
scope, but remember what the flow of control is. We're going to
call, each. Now we're in this function. Each calls numtimes. The
first time we hit yield, we're back down here. If you think
about where in time is this block getting executed? It's getting
executed at the time that yield is called, but despite that
fact, it has access to the variable, “ i” which was in scope at
the place where the block was defined. This is actually a pretty
deep concept. It means that when you create a do block, all of
the variables visible inside that do block are going to be
visible and have those values, even if the block is being
executed at a place in time far away from where you defined it,
and a place later in the course or in the case of the online
courses in part two where we're going to see this again is in
JavaScript. JavaScript makes extensive use of closures, and it's
one of the reasons the beginners in JavaScript tend to write
horrible, horrible code because they don't understand this very
powerful concept that you can define a procedural environment
that always carries its variables around with it.