Welcome to software engineering this is a really it's I'm
excited to be talking about this when I was a student what was
called software engineering just didn't make any sense you know
what other people trying to figure out how to build software and
advice they had you couldn't possibly take advantage of this
course what's exciting is now we can the software has been
changed so it 's easier to do. So why are you all here maybe not
why are you all here but what a great taste you have in courses
I think that so so last year somebody get a ranking of all the
jobs in the united states by job title this company. So I I
thought I'd go through it in reverse order here like a top ten
list you know so somebody you are a kid growing up I think this
is a cool job and so let me go go backwards looks like maybe you
want to be a lumberjack that's absolutely the worst job so how
it is how do they picked it was based on salary stress levels
hiring outlook physical demands of work environments a
lumberjack work environment not so great but lumberjack is only
four things worse than newspaper reporter yeah so so for your
friends in journalism you might you know check. Maybe they'd
like lumberjack and and then you're growing up you know I wanna
be a firefighter or maybe a flight attendant or a police officer
or high school teacher fashion designer pilot those are all on
the bottom half of the one hundred list okay now maybe a little
bit later in school you thought you know I'd like to have a
challenge job you know all good lifestyle today suppose you said
attorney well that's a little better that's in the top half but
towards the bottom now we 're in the ECS department how's how
many of you are electrical engineers right that's next Yeah it
seems like engineering seems pretty good so mechanical still the
but you know if you're not the top quarter yet accountants you
know that's in the top quarter finally how about a doctor you
can lots of kids wanna be a doctor right that's barely there or
a nurse in terms of the kind the best engineering position is
civil engineering at least on the Berkeley campus is actually
another one we don't have petroleum engineering that's a pretty
good job right now. But the number one job in the united states
is software engineer right sorry. So that's very it's cool that
we are teaching things you know that people can have the best
job in the united states but if it's such the best job why do we
screw up at it so much okay that's the thing that's fascinating
or yeah yeah are frustrating to having been in the field a long
time and you can you can follow this on wikipedia. but there's a
few of them if you are in a software engineering community you
know the cliche all you have to do is mention the word video
yeah I I know about that one So you need to know if you don't
know about that so one of the first scary ones is the Therac
lethal radiation overdose So this is nineteen eighty five and
the predecessor machine had hard[unclear] inner locks to make
sure you didn't give somebody too much radiation that machine
the Thrac twenty five took away the hard? locks the software was
already working under And its predecessor that uses the same
software made some changes to it you moved the software forward
there was a bug that rarely occurred six people would burn to
creation and three of those died So a software for bug kill
people that was eye opening the Mars climate orbiter
disintegration. So the ground computer used imperial units and
the satellite computer used metric units they use different
units and so when the orbiter came its time went the wrong angle
and burned up so psht three hundred million dollars the thing
that amazes me is that the F. B. I. partial file case. So what
happened that for five years they tried to build a virtual file
case to give F. B. I. agents the ability to have things at their
fingertips they gave it was so bad they they didn't like fix it
they said just okay we'll just throw it all away a hundred 70
million dollars. But the most spectacular software bug the Arian
five so the aryan five annals of history that one momentarily
yeah so the Aryan four again it worked fine but the Aryan five
ran faster than the aryan four so they they take the aryan four
software for five to save space they stored numbers in sixteen
bit integers but they calculated sixty four bit floating point
numbers the Aryan five can fly faster than the Aryan four so the
number was bigger and so what happens is what it's going oh you
can't hear it right okay software there goes three hundred
twenty five million dollars of satellites right there okay so
this you know there's this IEEE software or ItripleE spectrum
has a whole a wall of shame that I think it's seventeen billion
dollars so why it is such a great job you know why is it why's
it so bad so there's this wall of shame how do you avoid that
right so that we've been developing software for sixty years.
And what we're gonna do in this classes is go over all the
things that you can oh there's been a lot of [unclear] try but
we're gonna go over them in this class but there's one we're
going emphasize really we're going to emphasize the one that's
got the software why we're saying ten thousand students around
the world have got certificates from the course last year
enrollments have grown you know before before computing was
popular computing was popular teaching evaluations last time was
really good so what you're gonna do is how do you not end up on
wikipedia pages something you want to take off your resume right
you're gonna learn how to do it the right way