We're going to start talking about RSpec and Rails. We got a
brief introduction to RSpec recently, and I don't know how many
of you have actually taken to heart our advice that as you do
these homeworks, even though right now we're providing test
cases for you, we wanted you to start reading the test cases,
just to understand what they look like, and start getting by
osmosis a sense of what our spec code looks like. Because now
we're going to start talking about it in a lot more detail.
Interestingly, as Dave said, the previous cohort of students,
when we introduce BDD to them, I was afraid that BDD and
Cucumber would be where the cognitive sticking point was,
because it's a new tool, it's a new kind of language, it's not
actually code, it's somewhere between code and natural language.
In fact, students, once they had gotten used to doing it, they
really embraced it, and I think they absorbed the fact that it
was a natural way to communicate with a customer, and also
express integration test. That was great. What we didn't expect
was that people had more difficulty than we anticipated grasping
the unit and functional testing at the level that you would do
with RSpec. Hopefully this time around, we'll do even better. We
already got introduced to the idea that RSPec is this domain-
specific language for testing. We already know, because we have
be following along looking at the homeworks, that there is a
spec directory, and what we haven't told you yet is, just like
we have a generator that we used, for example when we created
migrations, it creates some empty code for you in the right
places, there is a generator that you can run on your Rails
app, " rails generate rspec: install", that will generate all
the directories so that tests will be placed in the right
locations that it expects to find them. Now in the homeworks
you've had so far, we really just had two subdirectories of
interest. There is a lib subdirectory, where your code goes, and
there is a spec subdirectory, where the tests go. In fact, in
order to keep the tests a little bit better organized for Rails
apps, there's actually three different kinds of tests we're
going to write. There's the unit tests, which mostly test the
models, sometimes test the helpers. There's functional tests,
which mostly test controller methods. What about integration
tests? Could we write RSpec tests around views? Some people do,
some people don't. There's mixed opinion about it. Our view is
that integration testing is really part of the process of coming
to agreement with the customer. Our view is that it's fine to
use Cucumber as the way of expressing your integration test,
because you can express things like what should appear, or
should not appear in the views. Having said that, be aware that
even though we're not going to talk about it much in this class,
you can, in fact, write specs for your views. We'll give some
examples of the kind of things you might put into a spec for a
view if you were to write one. In terms of a Rails application,
just like we have subdirectories for models, controllers and
views, there's a parallel hierarchy under spec where our, model
specs, controller specs, and if we wrote view specs, there would
be a place for them, but we're fine having everybody just use
Cucumber for that. The example we are going to pick up on is
going back to the BDD example, where we're adding this method
where we're hypothetically going to call out to the TMDb
service, and be able to populate our movie database using
information from that. Remember that the setup for this was in
the sad path for the Cucumber test, there was a step, and I
pressed " Search TMDb", and the idea is that in a fully working
app, that would invoke a controller method that would actually
cause the external service to be queried, return the data, and
then put that data into our model. What would we do to actually
fill out that example? Remember we said that there's this BDD/
TDD interaction. You start with a step of a Cucumber scenario,
and because there's no code, that step will fail, and now we're
going to get to the point where, " Okay, time to write the code
for that step to pass." We're recursively going to take the same
idea. We're going to first think about what we would like that
code to do, how we wish it would behave if we had it. We're
going to write tests that capture those behaviors, and then
piecemeal, we're going to backfill the code, so that it does
what the tests say that it should do. Conceptually not very
difficult, feels totally unnatural the first time you do it, so
you're going to have to stick with us. Recall when we said
you're adding new functionality to a Rails app, there's these
things you always have to do. You have to add a new route, new
controller method, and new view. We're now going to focus on the
controller method, and we're going to ask, " What should the
controller method do when it receives the search form?" What we
said before, when we were planning out this feature, is that it
should call a method that will search TMDb for the specified
movie, and if it finds a match for that movie, it should select
the " Search Results" view, display the match, etc. Let's just
start with that much. When it says, " The controller method
should do these things", we can actually capture this in normal
code, and ... okay, here is the RSpec centric version of what I
just said. I said that when we have a controller method that's
going to search TMDb, it should call the model method that
performs the search, it should select the search results
template for rendering, assuming that that worked out, and it
should make the search results available to that template, so
that the template has something to display. All I've really done
is translate ... think of this as like a user story, but for the
programmer. Just as we were able to take the customer specified
behavior and write a Cucumber story, we're now talking about at
the level of code we want to write, what does that code have to
be able to do? This is all actually legal RSpec. These are three
test cases beginning with " It" that we haven't written yet. If
you've been looking through some of the test cases that come
with the homeworks, you would know that if we put a Do ... End
block after each one of these, that's where the code would go
that actually does each of those tests. Let's see what that
would take. Let's do a sanity check on this first. Remember that
we're about to add new functionality to our app, and we're going
to have this method at some point that actually has to contact
TMDb and search for a movie. Just so we're all on the same page
about what we need to do, is that method going to be a class
method in Movie, an instance method in Movie, a method in the
controller, or a helper method?