Okay. Now that we understand where we're going, and yes, we are
going to have to implement a controller method that is the first
place that external user input touches our code. So yeah, that's
we're going to code next, and this gives us an opportunity to
sort of do the cycle that so far has been provided for you in
the homeworks which is the Red, Green, Refactor cycle. So here's
the basic approach, we're going to think about one thing the
code should do. In fact, in the last little segment there, we
just came up with three things the code should do. We're going
to capture that thought in a test, which fails because we have
no code, and then we're going to write the simplest thing we can
think of in the code that makes that test pass. Before
continuing on to the next behavior, we'll just see whether
there's any opportunity to sort of clean up or refactor or
beautify the code that we are already wrote. Then we're going to
have a lot to say about refactoring later on in the course, but
it's kind of like it's always refactoring time. Right? You
should never miss an opportunity to do a little bit of code
cleanup. The cycle's called Red, Green, Refactor because you go
from Red, which if failing; to Green, which is passing; to
Refactoring, which is still passing but with an improved code
structure and you keep doing that sort of until the code passes
all the test that you have thought of. So you're goal is to
always have working code. Whenever you write a new test, it's
going to fail. That's like unstable situation that you want to
get away from. You want to get back to green. So that's why the
simplest possible code that makes sense it pass, that's that
path of least resistance. Right? You have a separate opportunity
to beautify or refactor the code, but the most important thing
is ... don't get too far away from stuff that works. If it's not
broke, don't fix it. The question is ... if we're going to start
doing unit level testing, we have to test things in isolation,
right? We said that there's this spectrum of testing from
testing one method or one class at a time all the way up to the
integration test, which exercise big chunks of the app many code
paths. So the basic question we're going to look at next is, how
do you test something in isolation? Given that sort of any non-
trivial piece of code has dependencies on other things that
would affect how you would test it. So the powerful tool that
we're going to use here is the code you wish you have. Maybe
it's the code we wish we have, I don't know. But we already
said, " What should the controller method do that receives the
search form [ molds 00:02:06]?" Let's just start with our own
answer to that question was it should call a method that will
search TMDb for the specified movie for the specified movie.
Now, we have no clue under the sun of what that method is going
to look like. In fact, all we really know about that method
based on the last self- check question is that that method is
actually going to live in the model. So really, the only thing
controller has to do ... is kind of pass the buck to the model,
right? We have to make sure that whatever user data comes from
the app, that what's going to arrive in the controller, so
somehow that data has to successfully get to whatever method in
the model is going to do the actual work. Right? I think we're
in agreement about that after the last question. The question is
how do we test this controller method if we've already admitted
to ourselves that it depends on this other code in the model,
which we haven't even thought about yet. So this is where the
powerful idea of the code we wish we had comes in. Let's
remember we have to add a route to config/ routes. rb. That's
not a problem, we can do a simple route that just posts a form
to the search_ tmdb [ inaudible 00:03:00], not a problem there.
We already know that because of convention over configuration
rails will map that and it will look for an action called
search_ tmdb in our movies controller, that's while I'm good.
Again, we get that kind of for free. Well, the view has to have
something to render, so for now, we'll just create an empty
view. That's perfectly legal. Not useful, but it will allow our
test to pass. So, we just create an empty Haml file that has the
correct name and is in the correct place. Right? This is just
all scaffolding, so that the world doesn't blow up when we start
doing our test. And now, we're going to get to the actual. We're
going to look at that " hardwired" fake method that Dave used in
his example and we're going to replace it with an empty method.
Okay? So now, we're pulling out the safety net. The method is
now officially going to have to fail. Since I just said ... we'd
agreed that the controller has to hand off some data to the
model and the model is going to have a method that does the
actual work, but what method is that? I mean, we haven't written
that method yet. So, how could we possibly test the controller
action if the thing that it's supposed to call doesn't exist
yet. This is the magic part. Okay? So, the way we resolve this
is we'll say, " No problem. Let's develop an idea for the code
we wish we had." In other words, we know that code doesn't exist
but suppose it did exist. How would we like it to work? We will
use a seam, a seam is a really important concept. It's basically
a place where we can change the behavior of our app without
changing source code. When we come back to this and talk and
separately about it. But we're going to insert a seam that
allows us to test the code we wish we had even though that code
isn't there yet. So, here's the code that I would say we wish we
had. We know that it's going to be a class [ method 00:04:34] of
movie, so I postulate that it be nice if we had a method called
find_ in_ tmdb that it's a class method of movie and that it can
take some arguments representing the mood that it's going to try
to look up in the TMDB database. So, here is our game plan,
we're going to simulate in our test what happened when the user
post that search form. We're going to check that when the
controller action gets invoked, it tries to call find_ in_ tmdb
and that it correctly includes the data that it had pulled out
of the submitted form. Now, these are useful things to test.
Right? We are not testing the find_ in_ tmdb function itself.
We're not testing that it can talk to the external database. The
only thing we're testing is that controller is doing it's job
which is separate from the model doing its job. Okay? So, of
course, the test will fail because we just made the controller
method be empty, and then we'll backfill the controller method
so that it makes the test pass. We could do all of that without
ever actually writing the model method. So, how would we do
this? So, let's walk through, this is our ... controller spec,
and as we've already seen, we have a describe block for the
overall class whose behavior we're describing and then within
that describe block, we can nest other describe blocks that are
sort of testing different chunks of behavior within that class.
Here's our test case that says the controller action should call
the model method that performs the actual search, does the real
work. We're saying ... first of all, we're going to set up this
expectation. The movie class should receive the method call,
find_ in_ tmdb with particular movie title. Right? So remember I
said the game plan is we're going to simulate posting the form
with some data, make sure the controller action can correctly
get that data and hand it off. Well, here is our simulated post.
Post is one of the methods that's included like the rails plug
ins for our specs, so that there convenient ways to simulate
things in the model of new controllers. So, post is a method
that says take code ... what controller are we testing? It's the
movies controller. So to that controller, post this action and
it can lookup in the routes. rb what [ inaudible 00:06:28.]
require to simulate that post and here's what's going to be
passed in [ params 00:06:32]. So, this is the one place that we
have to sort of synthesize something is we have to know what [
params 00:06:38] would look like when the user actually submits
that form. There's many ways you can do that. I showed one
example is you can put a debugger statement in your controller
method and sort of take a look at the [ params 00:06:48.] object
and see what the form actually looks like when it arrives. Any
of those methods is good. Right? So, what are we doing here? Our
two steps is we're setting up an expectation of something that
should happen, and then, we're executing some code that should
trigger that thing to happen. Right? So, why is this work?
Here's a self- check [ inaudible 00:07:08] let's see how far we
get without me sort of revealing all the details here of what's
going on. Just to test your intuition about what that example is
trying to show. So, should receive is one of our specs methods
and see if you can use your intuition to answer the following.
Which of these statements is false regarding should_ receive?
One of the statement is should receive provide a stand- in for
real method that doesn't exist yet, so that we can do our test?
Another statement is ... even if we did have that real method,
should receive would override it for the purpose of our test? A
third possibility is should receive could be either issued
before or after the code that should trigger the behavior that
should receive [ sets up 00:07:51]. Or fourth, that it exploits
Ruby's open classes and metaprogramming to create that should
receive seam. To create the place where we're going to try to
sort of change and spy on the behavior or our application
without changing the application's actual source code. So, I
guarantee that one of these four statements actually is false.
It is not a trick question.