In the self- check question, we ask which types of tests could
be ran repeatably and independently, because we know that those
are two of the attributes from the FIRST acronym that make for a
good test suite. One of them was, " What if you have a code that
relies on randomness like shuffling a deck of cards?" You would
think that because randomness is part of what the code does, you
can't test it repeatably, but in fact there's a couple of
different ways to do it. One possibility in the case of
something like shuffling a deck of cards is to keep track of the
random number generator seed that was used when you ran the
code, and to capture a particular execution order associated
with that seed. The way random number generators work is if
there are software or pseudo- number generator once you've
established the seed value, the sequence of random numbers that
comes out of the generator is deterministic. That would be one
way that test of type A could in fact be ran in repeatable and
independent manner. What about tests of type B, code that relies
on the time of the day? Well, as we will learn when we talk more
about testing, a key concept in testing is the ability to fake
out the behavior of collaborator classes that are separate from
the class you're testing. In example B, an example of a
collaborator class would be the library that provides the time
of day. What we could do is fake out that library with the so
called stub that returns a known time of day. We could basically
return a canned value for the time of day, and then we could
test that our code does the right thing depending on what canned
value is returned. Another strategy is worth mentioning for
cases of type A where there's randomness involved looks at the
spectral properties of the result, so if you were testing for
example code to flip a fair coin, we know that a fair coin
should come up heads about 50% of the time, so you could write a
test suite where one of the tests flips a coin or a virtual coin
a large number of times, and checks to see whether the
proportion of heads and tails is within some relatively modest
value of 50/ 50. The moral of the story is even if something
seems none- deterministic or seems to depend on external
conditions, there is usually some way you can think of to either
control the conditions it depends on, or establish repeatable
conditions for the purposed of testing. We'll keep coming back
to this over and over again so that every time you think of a
new feature you want to add to your code, you're automatically
asking yourself the question, " How could I test this?"