I said an instance method in a controller method for how long as
its value going to be retained? Read, think. Initial vote. I've
ever surely decided you have long enough to think. Was I right?
Take 30 seconds to discuss it. I was only partially right. All
right, let's vote second time. Second vote, hold them up. Okay,
wide convergence on red. Let's go through this one at a time. If
I said an instance variable in a controller method, all right
that's key phrase in there, instance variable to controller
method. Your tip off here is the controller is really just the
receiving end of an HTTP request. HTTP is stateless. You keep
coming back to this over and over. Once the controller method
has done its work ... What is the controller? The controller is
an instance of object. It's an instance of the controller object
that handles an incoming HTTP request. As soon as that
controller object has finished doing its job, that instance of
the controller evaporates along with all of the instance
variables. Instance variables used ones, they're gone. Once
you've consumed them to view, you can say goodbye to them
forever. Now, there are special cases like the flash and the
session. There's a reason to persist some information from one
request to another, which is why those things have a separate
obstruction like the flash and session. Only this request and
the next request that will be to review put something into the
flash. Which again looks like a hash, quacks like hash, but it
persist one request after the current one. If you put it into
the session it would indeed stick around for all subsequent
requests. As long as you didn't make your session so bloated,
that it doesn't fit in a cookie. Red is correct, and for the
blue one, if you voted blue it say you're on 169 now and no more
Java. In fact I'm not even sure the statement makes sense in
Java. There's no declaration, there's no static and if there
were, they'll be class variables and not instance variables. I
just tried to see how many different key words I could put in
there to make it not makes sense. Every time you hit your
application with a new HTTP request, each incoming new request
causes a new instance of the controller object to be created.
Just as with any type of object, whenever an instance of an
object is blown away, all of the instance variables associated
with that instance are also blown away. That is exactly the
explanation.