Next thing you need to do when you meet with a customer besides
coming up with the user’ s stories, is work on the user
interface. Why? Because most SaaS applications have a user
interface. There’ s a piece in the cloud. There’ s a piece on
the browser typically. What can we do to get the customer to
participate, like the 3 x 5 cards? We want to avoid the WISBNWIW
user interface. Everybody knows what that is. The WISBNWIW
interface, that’ s the, what I said but not what I want user
interface. You don’ t want to build the user interface as far as
you can tell just what the customer asked for, and then once the
customer sees this, “ No, no, no. That’ s not what I want.” We
want to avoid that thing. So what’ s the user interface
equivalent of that? Then that’ s kind of you could imagine some
kind of picture that you create, like Photo Shop user interface
that way, but a user interface is active. It’ s animated. Many
things are going on. How do we reflect that into what make it
easy to change? The answer is you’ ve already learned this in
kindergarten. We do user interface sketches with pen and paper
or with crayons. You could do it with the crayons, and you make
what’ s called the Lo- Fi, low fidelity user interface. Here’ s
one that I did, so you can see at the top of this page is rotten
potatoes, and we’ re creating a new movie. I left some blanks,
some forms to fill in for the title, rating, release date, and
here’ s a button at the bottom where they save the changes.
That’ s my sketch. That took me very little time to sketch, and
we could show it, and because it’ s not threatening like 3 x 5
cards, “ No, no, no, that’ s not what I want”, we could just
throw the pieces away or do it on a white board and take
pictures of it. It’ s really low tech, but we can get an idea of
what’ s going on. That’ s like a statistic one. What about this
animated when you click on it? Well, once again the user
interface community came up with another good idea, which is
storyboards, which they borrowed from the movie industries. You’
ve probably all seen movies about movies where you see these
storyboards, like for Disney, and here’ s how the scene is put
together. It’ s like the scenes of a movie, but instead of
linear, like pieces of a movie, we can go to anyone. So let’ s
go look at the storyboard version of this examples. This one is
a mock up of a page that when I click on add a new movie, this
arrow says, this page is supposed to pop up. That was the one I
showed you before. What happens after I save changes, it’ s
supposed to go to this page, which shows the movie being added,
and then I can click back to the movies and go over there. It’ s
multiple of these Lo- Fi sketches and with some arrows to show
how it works. That’ s storyboards. Believe it or not, with
pieces of paper and storyboards and dealing with the customer
that you can help evolve, at very little effort, figure out what
the customer wants and likes and be happy before you build it.
It seemed kind of a lot of work, but it’ s a lot less work than
producing html, and again, not threatening, engage the customer
more. After this, we talked a little bit about Haml, and Armando
did talk about Cascade Style Sheet, CSS, so it’ s important to
make it pretty, but after you figure out what they want. You
don’ t want to make it pretty and then we throw it away. That’ s
the idea of Lo- FI UI, and as you meet with the customers and 3
x 5 cards, as soon as you get tired of talking about that, you
could start talking about the user interface and the storyboards
and how they would work.