Now we get to wrap up. Fallacies, pitfalls, perspectives ...
We've spent some time looking at the machinery, lines of code,
and I think the thing about this class that works well. We make
you go frequently between looking at details and lines of code
and then also try to back up a little bit and look at the big
picture. Let me just start with a couple of pitfalls, fat
controllers and fat views. When I say fat controllers, I'm not
talking about human beings in a particular occupation. I'm
talking about controllers whose methods start getting really,
really long. In a simple example that I showed, the controller
method was like four lines. In practice that'll be a little
longer than that, but they shouldn't be a lot longer. The reason
that it gets that way is because when you start thinking about I
want to code the following new action in my map. What's the
first place in your app that's a point of contact with the user?
It's the controller right? That's how model view controller
works. The first code you write that can touch what the user is
doing is code that goes into the controller. That's where you
start coding inevitably that's where you keep coding. It's just
one more thing, it's just a couple of more lines, and pretty
soon you've got like a page long controller method. You realize
that the controller is doing work that really belongs somewhere
else usually in the model. If it is interesting work, the model
should do it. It's a huge temptation that you should avoid to
start, just throwing code into your controller methods because
that's the first place you happen to look when you're writing
new app code. Fav use is a similar problem and Hamel does some
social engineering to try to make it really awkward to put code
into your views. People managed to circumvent it nonetheless. It
starts innocently enough it's like, " Well I have a collection
of items so I just need a simple for- loop to loop over the
collection and print out one table rope or item. Okay, well
that's kind of reasonable. Oh but it's not sort of the way I
want, so I'll just add a couple of lines to sort it before I
display the table. What if the user is not logged in and they
shouldn't see some of the choices?" Again you're on the slippery
slope, the decisions that really ought to be made somewhere
else. The view is just for presenting stuff and if you need some
code to prettify what the view is trying to present, that's what
helpers are for. You can put help methods in the first stuff
like that. I mentioned that it's really easy because of this
philosophy that you're really deciding a restful service first.
The user facing service second that it's actually quite easy to
use the same controller code to match both purposing. I'm going
to show an example of how to do that. Typically if you're being
called as a service in a service- oriented architecture. The
color will probably expect that you will deliver results to them
in XML or JSON. XML, we sort of have seen by Osmosis. JSON we'll
talk about more when we talk about JavaScript further down the
line. Basically what I'm going to show you is a trivial
controller change. Let's see re- purpose it to either way. We're
going to look at, here's a version of the create action that
will work correctly either in a service- oriented architecture
or in a human face the one that we just built. What did I change
here? This first two lines are the same, update attribute. This
is all neither ... What's changed here is what we do in a
rendering step. What I've done is I've put the render step
inside of this block with this method respond to. Respond to
yields to a block something that Ruby calls a collector or the
Rails calls a collector. Basically a collector is responsible
for figuring out what format the client probably wanted and what
it should do for that format. In our example here, we're going
to worry about two formats. If the client wants HTML, that was a
user phasing request. That means we have to generate something
that is a reasonable HTML page to present to a human being. On
the other hand, if the client wants XML that means that we were
called as a service and a service- oriented architecture. What
we need to generate is an XML representation of the result of
this operation. The respond to is baked in the Rails. There's
logic in the routing sub- system that already allows you to with
one line changing your routes file say these action should be
valid in service- oriented architecture mode. They should be
callable as the client wants an XML version of the same action.
That's how this part works. You don't have to worry about this,
this is going to be setup for you. All you have to do is provide
a block that says what's the right thing to do in each case. In
the HTML case, this is the same thing we had before. We're just
going to do a redirect back to a different action. In the XML
case, we're going to render ... Render colon XML means deliver
the output in such a way that the client on the other end will
see it as an XML encoded document. What's the thing that we're
going to render? Conveniently, Rails defines a default or I
should say active record, defines a default to XML method for
you. The simplest thing it does is if your model contains basic
types like strings and ends as it attributes, it will correctly
XMLify that. You're free to override it so that you can do
custom fields or whatever you want. For the most part this will
just work. If I added a third line here for JSON it will work
the same way. Again the message here is what's the controller
doing. It's the first point of contact from the outside world.
It can figure out what kind of entities making the request. The
model is where the real work happens but once the work has been
done, the controller can also decide what's the most appropriate
way to present it. If you want it to do like your custom special
stall sheets for a mobile app or something like that, this is
another place that you could have that logic, completely
orthogonal and very cool.