So we take an initial vote. Initial vote? Initial vote? For
those of you in the middle of the room, when I put my hands over
my head it's not because I'm stretching. It means initial vote,
although I am also stretching. I see at least one of almost
every color, so this is a good one to spend a few seconds on.
Let's try an updated vote. Updated vote says? Updated vote says?
Blue and orange seem to have the most votes and it's a split.
Let's go through one at a time here. We'd probably just go
through it in an order. If we try to just read each sentence,
should_ receive combines a mock and an expectation where stub is
only a mock. One reason that this doesn't make a lot of sense is
because a stub isn't a mock. A mock is an actual object. It does
stand in for something. A stub is more like, " Don't call this
procedure. I'll just give you the answer." You can stub
individual methods on a mock object absolutely, but the term "
mock" refers to identity. You mock the whole object or even the
whole class. Stubs usually refer to individual method calls. A
stub isn't really a mock. That leaves us with, from the other
three choices, we could say stub as an expectation or we could
say stub as a seam, but stub absolutely isn't an expectation. In
fact the main difference between stub and should_ receive, they
both deal with a concept of a method getting called on an
object, but should_ receive says, " It's an error for the method
not to get called." Stub just says, " If the method gets called,
here is the can response that you should return." It doesn't
actually check that the method got called. In fact, you could
perfectly well set up stubs and some of them don't get use,
although if that happens, you should ask yourself why you set
them up. So that leaves us with number two to number three. What
is it that should_ receive and stub certainly have in common?
Should_ receive and stub are basically both ... oh sorry, not
number and number three; number four. What do should_ receive
and stub actually have in common? They're both places that when
you're writing tests, allow you to surgically alter the behavior
of the program without changing the source code of the program.
So both of them are kinds of seams. The seam is the overriding
concept here, but should_ receive in addition makes it an error
if the seam isn't use so to speak. The right answer in this case
is that should_ receive is both the seam and an expectation, and
stub is only a seam. That makes sense, people?