Today's the day for, " Which statement is NOT true about." So, "
Which statement is NOT true about RESTful routes and the
resources that they refer to?" " A resource could be existing
content, or it could be a request to modify something." " In a
Model- View- Controller app, every route must eventually trigger
some controller action." " One common set of RESTful actions
that you might want to support is, CRUD actions on your models,
whether they're ActiveRecord or not." And, " The route always
contains one or more wildcards, like ": id", because it needs to
identify the particular resource involved in that operation." So
think about that for a moment. Okay, so the initial vote. Okay,
initial vote. Wow, okay, the initial vote is almost
overwhelmingly for blue. You guys are so smart that we're going
to just review why blue is the right answer. So, why is blue the
correct answer is this case? Well, we can look at the first
three, and basically rule out all the other ones. A resource
could be existing content, or a request to make a change to
content. We've seen examples of both, so that's true. Every
route must eventually trigger a controller action, that, yes, in
a properly- designed Model- View- Controller app, that's the
description, the job description of the controller is, " Handle
the incoming requests from users." So, yes, sensibly enough,
controllers must eventually be triggered when the user asks to
do something. One common set of RESTful actions are, the CRUD
actions on models. Absolutely. In fact, as we just showed, those
are the ones for which Rails provides you, for free, routes that
will already do the correct things. Which leaves only the last
one, that the route always contains one or more wildcard
parameters. That's only true if the action is one that could
operate on a particular element of a large collection. So, one
action is, " Show me information about a specific movie." In a
route like that, you would need to have a parameter to say which
movie it was, but, as we say, another resource could be, " Show
me the whole list of movies." You don't need a particular
identifier for that, you just need a constant string. So, the
last choice is the one that is false, and you're all really
smart, because you got it right.