Big ideas about how to develop software and ways to build
software and your jumped into ruby,  this new exciting programming
language or not you but you need a lot of us well traditionally
the first thing that we had developing software we call it plan and
document process and so remember from the last couple of
segments that there was this if that you thinking by building
software is the greatest job in the world except you know you could
be made fun by your friends and neighbours. So about you know twenty
years building software did he ask the question can we make it as
predictable as building a bridge, a civil engineering facility why can't software
development as dependable as  civil engineering cost and schedule
. And so what to do. So with its software is only like six
years old so somebody had to invente how to do that. And this idea
bring engineering discipline to to software was coined in
nineteen sixty nine and yeah it was frustrating to people to start
having disasters. So we call plan and document collectively will be
three examples of those is before anybody starts writing code make
a plan that's the way you build a bridge so that's way you should do software.
You write detailed documentation for all phases of the plan
a and then you measure progress against the plan is so you start
building software and then if you gonna have to make changes in
the project should be making changes in the plan and the
documentation. So the first example of this has become known as
the waterfall process which came out right in software
engineering was first going. And the idea was to have five
explicit phases and so rather than calling it a software
development process also called a lifecycle. So this waterfall
software development processor life cycle. First is to write
requirements down in into a specification, do the analysis and
write specification second faces architectural design the third
phase is building integrating the pieces together, then you
verify it, remember verification is making sure it does spec says and
finally you move into operations and maintenance phase. So this is the
classic phase. And you complete one phase before you go the next
one and the idea was that they found is that the earlier you found a bug
you find a bug in architecture phase it's a lot cheaper than you find it
in the verification phase. And because the last of long time, years
for building software projects the extensive documentation they're
apart so when you employees come the end they can get up to speed so
it is that's story. So that was first software development process
of life cycle how well doesn't work. Well here's the something
that somebody posted anonymously and the uses exclaimed with a
laugh and a taunt. It's just what we ask for but not what we
want. Alright? So typically what happens when you dealing with customers
they don't quite know what they want. And when you build
something it starts to work they realise that's not what
we want, I don't know what we want but that's not it. That's idea right. So that happen in the waterfall
you take years you get there you show it to the customer they change their
mind. Another one is from Fred brooks. And his phrase is a throw
the first implementation away you will anyhow. So Fread Brooks one my
personal heroes and we'll call him a couple of times but he won
the Nobel prize computer science. And is author of the famous
book in software engineering called mythical manmonth and basically what happens
is developers mostly of the first one then I get an idea has
been implemented and if you had the way they do begin better so
so kind of this is what the problem soft whatever life cycle is
they would build software customers didn't like and then after they
build it they realise the right way to do it that inspire the next of
life cycle called spiral. And what's trying to combine is the
features of waterfall is a lot of planning and documentation
with building prototypes and iterations and prototypes. So what
you do is evolve a document over time
every time you do a iteration so here let's look at this drawing
out these so these four quadrants as what you go around building
startup down here with the determine the objectives and
constraints then the next step is you evaluate a bunch of
alternatives and identify any risk to the project and figure out
result then the next phase is you developing verified prototype
do the verification of the prototype. You know this is a portion of what you do and
you show it to the customers. And then you get feedback and then next
iteration so we met fan right here and then you again again
again in this final prototype then is is the product which so
we'll see if this works. So what's the good the bad parts are
the the good iterations of a customer it's less likely when you
build this thing that the customers are gonna change the mind.
So they'll see it as ball that's a good thing reduce the cancer
misunderstanding risk management that kinda come from the
business school you identify the recent dance to try and avoid
them that's part of this life cycle. It's pretty easy to
monitor or it's easier to monitor the project. The waterfall was supposed to be
separate phases you're going around to see where you are in the
second or third and your schedule and cost projections get more
realistic overtime you're more familiar with the customers
seated get idea because if yeah but that things are these
iterations a pretty long they could be half a year to two years
long which is plenty of time for customers change your mind if
it takes a year between iterations lots of documentation for
every iteration every iteration gotta right set of documentation
that these rules that you following abilities those four phases
where you're not supposed to do one of the other faces until you
get to the next phase the temptation is gonna skip steps. So
it's part product stick to it because of all the documentation
in the building of prototypes it's pretty expensive. And it's it
it proved to be hard to me budget schedule purpose. So that was so
waterfall spiral. The third example in this is another fifteen
years later fifteen years after a spiral and thirty years after waterfall
is what's called the rational unified process. It's not rational
cause it's the others rational rationals name that company
came up with some rational unified process. So what you can see
in this design here these faces across the top. And then they
have what they called engineering requirements you'll unique
across the bottom so I'll come back to the slide show you again
and you can have multiple iterations within one of these phases. So there're two
elaboration for construction and sort of these days too the
first phase call section you come up the business case for the
software this RUP models more closely tied to business processes.
So what's the business case for building it why should we make this investment because that's
what would be return in this investment. This is the time you set the
schedule and the budget for the project and you do this risk
assessment of things so that white either cost budget or
schedules that restraint try and evaluate the second phase
collaboration word you develop use cases will talk about these
pieces are later it's kind of ways the software you use you
develop the architecture of the software and later we'll talk
about the importance of architectural building software works.
And you build the first basic prototype that's phase two. Phase three
construction were you the coding and you testing for the
product and you actually the first product release in the last
phase call transition was where you move to the real environment
where the software running and you get customers sign off on
customer acceptance. So that's the four phases of right the
engineering disciplines that you'll need in varies over the
lifetime of it is business modelling this is make the business
case doing requirements analysis design implementation just
fine. So let's go back to see how this all together in the
slides. So here the requirements we see the business modelling
plays a bigger role in the business in inception phase in the
beginning collaborations can advise off deployment is kind of the opposite
profile what happens at the end very last construction
iterations in the beginning of in the transition phase you can
actually planet testing happens periodically releases a lot of
more different implementations so that yours team has these
skills you need more of them different skills later. So what's
the what's the good and the bad of the RUP model? okay a the
drilling the business processes because you have you building
software the active business case for them that's more closely
tied in others lots of tools rational was a company that was
making tools for sales call computer aided software engineering
case tools these are very expensive tens of thousands of
dollars. And idea but also to get an idea the tools support
rationally improvement project over time a there this is you
know it's tens of thousands of dollars tools is open source
version so unless you pay rational idea more money you can't use
the tools. There's a lot of ways to tailor it you know how many
phasesbut also you may not result tools intensity get
only for big projects causes you know expensive one that it's
automatically decide how one iteration within of the phases the
so it's the manager's experience in fact what's true about all of these
projects is they expect a strong project manager that this
person writes the contract to that's going to win the project
from a customer here she recruits people new hires are people
from within the company this is the boss of your she's
evaluating the performance of all programmers limiting it that
which affect the sorry. And here she's responsible for
estimating the cost maintaining the schedule again one of the we have
and how to over come risks that's all managers. And they have to
document all this in the management plan and pretty much the
boss gets credited if it's success gets blamed if it's a over budget what
these teams plan and document methods tend to get bigger primarily
through expansion in another famous thing this thing Fred Brooks is
from the mythical man month is adding manpower to late project
makes later. So this is something he observed right over behind
what really we're gonna people that's gonna make words what said
as we bring the people or it takes time for you people learn the
project also the other. So it takes awhile useful and and
communication goes up as number people in the project. So the
bigger the project of the more times than communicating less
time there is work. So you can scale up to bigger groups at the
{Kennedy not too big so that it have not	 to miss time mutation
and then you still higher. }