Alright what statement is true about productivity copying and
pasting code is another good way for use. I suppose I suppose
laughter maybe a hint. Ha. Meta programming helps productivity
via program synthesis of the four productivity reasons the
primary one for high level languages reuse a concise syntax is
more likely to have your bugs and easy maintain. So what you
think about maybe this one's a a little harder. So which one is
true you're not getting the false one the true right. Ready.
Set. Ready. Set Okay Vote. WOW, this is a, I think this class a
smarter another classes that we've taught. Alright, wow all you
got, well about 90% of you have blue. So, yes meta programming
helps productivity probably reuse isn't the main reason for high
level languages probably the main reason is that it's concise
and concise is more likely fewer bugs. Fortunately, all of a
laughed about copying pasting. But that actually is a part of
the reuse culture about copying pasting is that there's this
thing that that's called don't repeat yourself. Or dry is what
we'll use. This schemes from these guys Hunt and Thomas, every
piece of knowledge must have a single unambiguous authoratative
representation of the system. So, you wanna refactor the code so
there's only one place by copy and pasting. So, now here's our
test. So, in conclusion of good work in conclusion so we cover
today so this class gonna learns the best job in world by
deploying it and really getting a for real customers on the on
the real same software. Software services less hassle for
developers and users the servers are in architecture, which
makes it it easy to reuse the current code. It's warehouse
computing this scale is much cheaper so you could resell it as
utility computing and testing issues, software quality and
software quality means it's good for the customer and for the
developer. Product testing is how ay we keep up with okay with
that