So far, I just assumed the existence of a table in order to do a
simple example. I didn't say anything about where that table
came from, why it has the columns it has. The next thing we're
going to talk about is how do you get that to happen. Our
discussion of database is going to be around migrations which is
something that in other programming frameworks is maybe not as
popular. I think Rails has put this on the map in a way that
made it accessible to a lot of programmers. The problem we’ re
trying to solve here is that once your appropriate is actually
up and running, if it’ s an app that anybody cares about, the
people who use it, they think of their data in that app as being
pretty important. You don’ t want to mess it up when you’ re
experimenting or developing a new feature that might require a
change to the database schema. When you do change the database
schema, you want to track those changes. Obviously, you’ d be a
fool if you’ re developing your code files with no version
control, no ability to roll back to an earlier version of your
code. Why wouldn’ t we think the same thing as true about the
database schema? The answer to managing both of these things is
automation as evidenced by the friendly dancing robot. In
general, if you can automate something, it means that you can do
it consistently. We’ re going to come back to this theme again
and again and again. Almost every successful thing that you do
in software engineering, at some point relies on automation to
take some of the stupid mistakes out of it. In fact, when we
talk later about deployment, I came back from a conference
literally 15 minutes before class today. There was a really,
really great talk from somebody who runs the back ends of one of
these games servers. He actually used the phrase deployment
should be a non- event. Releases should be an non- event.
Database schema changes, a little bit harder but we’ re going to
try to make them a non- event by automating them. The way Rails
addresses this is there actually isn’ t just one database;
there’ s multiple ones. The one you use depends on the
environment. What’ s an environment? Development, that’ s your
environment of when you’ re pounding a code on your laptop.
Production, that’ s the golden environment that you must not
touch because if you break it, people will be mad. Test is an
environment that only exist for the purpose of running automated
tests. Don’ t confuse this with an environment where you get to
do your own manual poking and testing; that’ s development. The
testing environment exists and is managed entirely by the
testing tools. By the way, you can define more environments
beyond these three. For example, a lot of companies define a
staging environment which is service that are in the productions
environment but they’ re not visible to real users. If it’ s
live in every way, except that it’ s not live because the end
users can’ t see but it’ s the closest thing there is to really
running on a system with all of the same conditions in place as
if it were a live deployment. How do we make changes to the
database? One problem is as soon as you say we have multiple
databases then we got to make sure they stay in sync. Any schema
changes, any structure changes that I make in development
eventually have to make it to production and maybe also have to
be tested in a staging server and my testing tools have to know
about them. We do this with migrations. A migration really is
just a script describing the changes you’ re going to make.
Rather than using your favorite sequel database gooey to add
columns and move columns around, we will write code the
describing changes we want to make. We can version that code
because it’ s actually ruby. Once we’ ve satisfied ourselves
that the changes are legit, all we have to do to apply the same
changes to the production environment is run the same script
over there. That’ s the basic idea. Why would you do this? First
of all, you can identify each migration. You know at what point
in time each schema change was made. Unlike code, you can
annotate why that migration was done. Why do we have to add this
column? Why do we choose to delete that column? Some migrations
can be created to be reversible which means, here’ s a set of
changes I want to make but actually all of these changes are
undoable. One thing that you can as in development if you apply
your migration, it turns out to be a mess, you can say, “ Oh,
undo all of that.” You’ re doing it in a principled manner not
in a sort of manual way where you have to remember what are the
eight things I clicked on in trying to make this change? You can
manage them with version control and because you can automate
them, it’ s reliable. You can repeat it. You can run the
migration multiple times on multiple machines and it will have
the same effect. The theme here that we’ re seeing with the
happy dancing robot is don’ t do it, automate it. If you’ re
thinking about doing it, stop and start thinking about what kind
of a tool might I be able to use to automate the task I’ m about
to do so that I can do it repeatedly and track each time I do a
change, why I did that change and what it is. Let’ s take a look
at migration. Remember we said that the idea of generating code
is pervasive throughout Rails. Here’ s another kind of code
generator. This kind doesn’ t write new code at runtime. This
kind generates code in files that become part of your
development environment. What happens when we issue the command
rails generate migration and we give the migration a symbolic
name that hopefully represents what it wants to do. We’ re going
to create a migration that creates the movies table that I used
as an example, a really simple version of it. Let’ s see what
that code would look like. When you say rails generate
migration, what you get is basically empty methods up and down.
You’ ve got to fill in what goes into those methods. What are we
doing in this method? We’ re going to create a table called
Movies. In that table, we’ re going to have a string for the
movie title, a string for the rating, a longer text field for
the description, a date time field for when it was released, et
cetera, et cetera and timestamps as we’ ll soon see is a field
that if you add it Rails will automatically manage it for you to
indicate when was the last time each record was updated or when
that record was added. This is the up migration. The up
migration is I’ m making a change to go from version end to
version end plus one of my database schema. Right now, for us
version end is there’ s nothing on the database. Couldn’ t be
simpler, right? At the end of this migration, there’ ll be a
table that has these columns of these associated types. What
would be the opposite? How would we reverse that migration?
Since the migration is consistent of creating a table, dropping
the table, meaning deleting the entire table would be the
opposite. That’ s nuclear. You’ ll drop table. Sequel gives you
enough rope to hang yourself and this will become a drop table
and sequel. The table will be incinerated. Of course, you backed
up your apps and you back up your databases nightly as we’ ll
talk about later in the class. If that happens, you’ re still
not totally host. Now, this is what the code looks like. I’ ve
created the migration. I’ ve filled in my up and down method
saying how am I going to change the database, how I would undo
that change? We haven’ t actually done anything yet. We have to
run this code in order for the database to be updated. We’ ve
just created the migration but what we say is we haven’ t
applied the migration yet. We’ re on our development box. We say
rake db: migrate. That will run the script and ideally, in an
error- free way make those changes to the database. We showed a
really simple migration but as the course goes on, we’ re going
to show a much more complicated migrations involving adding new
columns, creating columns based on the values of existing
columns and many, many other things. Remember, we’ re still in
our development environment. We’ ve tested our code. We know
that yes, the migration works, does what it’ s supposed to do.
Now, what do we do? We got to push it to production. No problem.
You just run the same command but you run it against your remote
heroku instance. That’ s it. You’ ve debugged the process by
which it’ s done and then you push a button and automation takes
over. A nice thing about the way Rails manages migrations is
that when a migration runs successfully, it also records in a
special database table which migrations have already been
applied. In fact, you can run rake db: migrate over and over
again and its item potent. Running it many times is the same as
running it once. When you run it, it actually means apply all
pending migrations of this copy of the database hasn’ t seen
yet. The database itself knows which ones that already has seen.
It’ s a really nice way of not having to keep track of, “ Oh, I
have a staging environment and I have production. Did I already
applied the migration in staging? I’ m not really sure.” It
doesn’ t matter. Just run rake db: migrate and if you had
already applied it before then it will do nothing. Save times.
We’ re starting to develop a cookbook of how you do various
things in a Rails SaaS app and the first one is how do you add a
new model? To add functionality to your app, you have to add
models, views and or controllers and models are the thing that
we’ re discussing first. When you want to add a new model or if
you want to change or add attributes to a model that you already
have meaning that it already has a corresponding database table
but you want to make some changes to it. Either way, you first
create a migration that describes the changes you want to make.
Give it a semi meaning full name if you can. Apply the migration
with rake db: migrate. Make sure that all is well, all of your
test passed and so forth. If it’ s a new model, meaning you
haven’ t used this type of model before, you also need to create
a folder that contains the actual code for the model. We showed
a really simple example. What is the simplest active record
model you can have? It’ s one that inherits everything from
active record and it has not logic of its own. Now, if your app
contains models like that, you probably shouldn’ t be using
Rails. It’ s too heavyweight for what you want to do. Generally
speaking, you should at least have somewhere in your models
directory a model that are B file whose name is the singular
version of the database table. There’ s the correspondence. The
singular name is used for the class uppercase. Singular name is
used for the filename lowercase and then the pluralized version
lowercase is used for the database table. One thing that people
often forget to do and they’ re very confused when they just
successfully applied a migration and now they try to rerun their
test and the test starts failing all of a sudden. Remember I
said there are actually at least three environments that come
standard. One of them is the test environment. Testing gets its
own copy of the database that is totally separate from
development, totally separate from production. The reason for
that is by their nature, test can be destructive. You need a
database where the test cannot have to worry about screwing up
important data. You have to separately make sure whenever you
change the schema. DB test prepare is essentially the equivalent
of saying, “ Hey, test environment. I’ ve applied new migrations
to my database so just clone the schema that I have and make
sure that all the tests see that new schema and the test
database too.” Again, it’ s a piece of automation that lets you
not have to worry about doing this manually and actually keep
everything in line.