So let's see about DBB and User Stories here. So which of these
questions is false? BDD is designed to help with validation,
build the right things in addition to verification, BDD should
test app implementation. User Stories and BDD play the same role
as design requirements and plan on document methods. And this is
a valid User Story, search TMDB featured name and I want to
search TMDB as a movie fan so that I can easily find
information. So which of these things is false? Ready, set,
vote. The first couple of rows are voting. Yes, there's some
differences here, so talk this over and then ... talk it over
and we'll do it again. All right. Let's vote again, let's vote
again. Ready, set, cards up. Voting as pairs. Okay. It converged
to green. Good. So BDD is designed to help with validation,
that's correct. User Stories play the same role as design
requirements plan [ inaudible 00:01:04] correct. The blue on
which some people voted for the first time around it's just in a
little bit different order but it's got all 3 terms, so it's
okay. But BDD doesn't test the implementation, it tests the
behavior, Behavior Driven Design. Okay. Good. So with that ...