Okay, so that's a quick overview. Let's ... pretty sure you all
follow this, but let's just make sure you were paying attention.
What's not true? What's false about Cucumber and Capybara? The
step definitions are Ruby and are similar to method calls, while
steps are in English and are similar to method definitions. A
feature has one or more Scenarios, which are typically composed
of 3 to 8 Steps. Steps use given for the current state, when for
the actions, and then for the consequences of actions. The
fourth one is Cucumber matches step definitions to scenario
steps using regular expressions, and Capybara pretends to be the
user that interacts with SaaS app accordingly. A lot of words in
this slide. Ready, set, vote. Okay. This is actually is a
mixture of the first two. I want you to talk it over and see
which it is and then we'll come back. All right. Let's try
voting again, see if anything change. Ready, set, vote. Orange
dominates here. So the fourth one is true. Step definitions ...
Cucumber matches step definitions to scenario steps using
regular expressions, and Capybara pretends. The steps are given
for the current, when for action, and then for consequences.  .
A feature has one or more Scenarios, which are typically
composed of 3 to 8 Steps. What's wrong here? What's wrong about
the first one? It's almost right. Just change a couple of words.
Step definitions are Ruby and are similar to method definitions.
It's like here's the step you're going to use a lot and the
steps are like method calls. Steps are in English but they're
similar to method calls and step definitions are Ruby and are
similar to method definitions. Keep that in mind. Keeps the
words ...