So or I'm gonna do the lecture today you're gonna see so much of
Armondo you get tired of seeing him so that Armando you'll see
him more.So, today what we're going to do in class organisation
and then jump in and start lecturing uh you'll find out about
the book for the course we told you some about it but will try
to cover the first six sections of the book today. So first,
what's this course about learning software engineering
principles understanding challenges opportunities the problems
here. And what you're going to do in this class you're going to
take build a real application working with real nontechnical
customers you're gonna on the server side you going to learn
ruby on rails and the client side all these things you've
already heard about the javascript. And deploy using cloud
computing that's a big part class you're gonna be teams probably
six a little bit bigger dealing with non-technical customers and
things in the past we've done the humane society minority firms,
the children's hospital nearby Oakland helping them vacation
planning teams are you get started this weeks ago discussion
section the first to is find a team. Your team needs to be in
your discussion section I'm gonna show you a quick video what we
interviewed the nurses after a little bit example so you think
vacation scheduling would be easy but not with union rules. All
kinds of different rules there we have elaborate pencil and
paper method with note books and Berkeley students the alumni
have this course stepped in and created a wonderful work
interface let me just hold on see if this is really gonna work
Sometimes we met weekly, sometimes it was every two weeks I
never for more twenty minus oh yes It didn't take a lot of time
for us but trying to convey to them the rules that we have to go
by know why vacation show them what we did. And we showed them
the rules and then gave them a copy of the rules they came back
with ideas that we couldn't have put forward and yeah brought
into this institution. you gave a lot of feedback on what they
were doing and then right easily fixed any concerns and it was
amazing.So, now with this prototype in place is there a point to
you person hope things get better? Correct. Yes. So our
vacations are due February first of each year. And so we start
usually in January. yeah I've got it going to try to make this
an issue okay oh right right right screaming we could start
using it in other areas of the hospital as well. That's great,
thank you for working with our students. Hopefully you will have
similarly satisfied customers and we'll interview them and when
used them the future version the class. Um so what happened was
the feedback innocent approach not technical but ninety percent
of them we gave them a multiple choice being disappointed up to
happy thrilled and they check happy with thrilled ninety percent
hal of them wanted to hire the students them happen one of the
hard decisions to keep working on it into thirds assumes
playtime keep working on even after classes over. And we were
really you know enthused,Armondo and I at just how well engaged
people were they with this agile a process to get four
iterations will do it really got into it in the projects varied
in size and code but not in the quality they were all very well
done. So how are we gonna grade this course? There these five
homeworks that's about a third is gonna add up to a little more
than a third homeworks two midterms no final this project about
third grade. And there's some altruism points that's you know
five percent of all that it depends on your participation
helping others lectures are gonna be up to be Mondays and
wednesdays from two thirty to four there's our office Armondo is
right after this mine earlier on Wednesday homework is gonna be
due right before midnight on Sunday and discussion sections of
thursdays and fridays and we're using piazza this this is a four
unit class the homepage tells you how the grade is going to be
broken down. So we're hoping what you do come prepared to
lecture by doing the Reading before the lecture that's the most
efficient use your time we'll put it in context and are we'll be
putting it to work. were big believers in this Confucius saying
is I hear and I forget I see I remember I do and I understand
you're gonna be doing in understanding your be applying these
ideas using real tools.The same tools the professional
programmers using this and we're gonna do it had to pizza teams
that's a nickname for five or six students that you could feed
with two pizzas. These days maybe you know it even if your
appetite growing as americans we still find a two pizza team is
still five or six people and if at the end we're gonna show off
what you've done one fight all the customers there and this will
be on Tuesday December tenth and will even have interested
people from silicon valley including venture capitalists.A lot
of projects continue after this class the homeworks are gonna be
at the doing understanding done on your own or in pairs and
you're gonna do it in the cloud using that extensively in this
class everything to be done and you need to have it for us since
the last time we talked last class Berkeley has adopted an honor
code. And this is the honour code that you as the students have
developed as a member of the community I honesty integrity
respect for others. So basically if you doing something that you
wouldn't like other students your professors or your parents to
know probably should stop doing it if you don't want them find
out about it that's a sign that maybe not doing it and gonna
help you with your pledge one of the big problems of a software
course is getting all the software working that you need to get
the work done. So or Armando a boldly said virtual machines were
invented to fix this technology is this problem we're just gonna
loaded virtual machines got everything you need all the right
versions you just download go and amazingly enough it actually
works. Uh you should follow these instructions being rather than
doing some custom installation yourself we strongly recommend
you don't do that and you're on your own if you do the it
becomes a discussion section you having any problems on the
virtual machine the GSIs will help Uh, the book for this class
is something Armando and I've been slaving away at for more than
maybe a year and a half now, we were we had an alpha edition and
a beta addition we're now to the second beta addition we're
almost done. And we're excited that at maybe in part because of
us a nagging Amazon they announce a couple days ago the ability
to bundle these together so for thirty three dollars this is
gonna be the best deal you ever get well there's two things
about this book it's the best book written by wrestler the music
director but nobody no other pair wrestlers in music directors
have written is nearly as good a book this and you know we're
keeping the price down hopeful so that won't be temptations to
get the book any other way the buying it. And number bundling
together this'll be the first time that's happened with includes
the right way to do that. So Armando came up with this idea of a
how can other faculty other campuses take advantage of this
massive online courses and he came to this idea called the SPOC
or small private online courses and so you're gonna be kind of
gonna spot really use that technology forgrading assignments and
things like that so we want you to sign up on the the the
Berkeley version of this SPOC will have a a special version of
kind of MOOC technology for this course and I think it says on
the homepage how to sign up on that so typically you know if you
need to ask question in the middle lectures okay we'll just try
and repeat it you know at the end of these segments which about
every eight or ten minutes or so a bit opportunity ask questions
as well. Okay I think I said that okay yeah you know there's a
besides what we've written beside the videos there's a lot
information about what we gonna lecture in this class because a
lot of professional people using them. So if you go to this
website you can find out about things you wanna get started on
ruby and rails there's tutorials you can get started on to learn
about C. S. S. get help in all of those things so if you would
if you find some other things to be useful resources use this
class go ahead to Piazza and signed that I think I added you all
everybody's in the class I think I added you all the also if not
you know talk to your GSIs about getting on okay now one of the
things that we've learned over the years is a lot of people
think you can you know time share your brain and learn something
what you do three things multitask. We know now that doesn't
work we actually know the biological reason why it attractive to
do it apparently evolutionary in our ancestry to get people
learn things every time you learn a little thing you candles
squirt dopamine you're in your brain and so you reward for
learning things. So that was great I think we wouldn't be here
today to would be seven billion of us you know we haven't been
encouraged to learn things alas now that we've got a little you
know Tweets and and you know Facebook things. We are addicted to
this so this story that's a few years old in the New York Times
talks about a guy who was constantly multitasking all the time
he wasn't paying attention to his family and he had build a
software company that he'd asked to sell and use multitasking so
much he missed the email with somebody offering to buy company
he missed it for couple of days finally slightly back and
apologise so heavy multitaskers as regular multicast actually
have more trouble focusing and shutting out irrelevant
information scientists say and experience more stress. So all
this technology that we're help you know responsible for having
has made it harder for you to learn new things the classroom. So
we're really hopeful that for the whole eighty minutes in here
eighty whole minutes of your day that you'll refrain from the
dopamine addiction and not text now will we know that's too much
we know eight units is too much so we'll try about thirty
minutes in we start shaking from the from withdraw love dopamine
we'll take a look at two minute break. And you can get your
dopamine shot texting everybody just how brilliant intellectuals
are in this course and other sure they wish they could be in
here but okay but will please just hold off for you know a few
minutes of time early in my career I asked some education expert
well, how should, what is your pace to lectures? What should we
do and he said this is true about human beings that's true today
as it was thirty years ago. So if you want this if you goes see
a talk somewhere you'll see the same kind of behaviour so the
first twenty minutes human beings can just sit there in the
chain attention about twenty minutes and they start figit And
basically their attention drops so early on in the course what I
would do I start off doing now is to all the administrivia stuff
so that everybody knew that administrivia stuff cold and when
actually got the technical lectures then you know then they
didn't pay attention so what we do is classically we get started
jumping on the good stuff and then twenty minutes in we do the
administrivia if a couple minutes and people can you know sh
around talk to each other and then then we get started again a
yeah yeah and then we go another twenty twenty five minutes to
these things are restless we divvy the dopamine break tech
break. And then we do one last thing and then he said there's
one thing that everybody gets a visitation the they can say that
everybody gets excited here in those words are " and in
conclusion" right. So actually if "and in conclusion" means
don't start packing your bag right just hold on for two more
minutes Armondo and I are good at stopping the class on time or
even early. So when I say in conclusion just hold on, listen to
the summary and then back down and go now another thing we could
start doing I can't remember who has the three by five cards
okay could you you get recruit volunteers starting as a how many
of you have done the peer instruction questions like with Dan
Garcia here people okay so we're gonna do that again about half
of you have done that so what the idea is a big lecture like
this. You know it can be pretty you know lack of interaction. So
this person who's a professor in physics at Harvard about
fifteen years ago came up with this idea that what I would do is
you know the physics is the getting lost in forest through the
trees kind of things you know they didn't understand big idea so
you would do is stop the lecture. So a few times during the
eighty minutes and ask a relatively simple question. And get
people to vote on it now of course if you you've ever gonna
classroom people are going to vote on something you watch you
wanna vote the majority so that wasn't gonna work well so he
came up with a clicker system and I think the chemistry
department uses that that means you gotta spend thirty or fifty
bucks and remember to bring stuff. So I came up with flashcards
three by five cards "'cause" that we can do pattern recognition.
So you'll get free cards as part of the bonuses of this class,
wooh! so these cards and I optimised technology there's two
sided parts you only have to hold onto two three by five cards
right that's what we have the of remember that those cards and
its orange on one side and kind of an olive green on the other
another one's red and blue okay let's like we're handing out the
cards right now. So I don't think I can do the poles. Well we
could just pretend we could just pretend on the first one and
you guys could raise your hand this one's pretty. This one's
pretty easy you have you ever use GitHub? so if you have a card
holder the orange one if you used GitHub or just raise your hand
alright about maybe what would you say okay how many have you
know how many have not used GitHub use the green one or have not
alright only a few alright good then the other options ones give
a in the other option is I've already lost my card right seconds
into the semester and you've already lost your card. So let's
try another that was so much fun, which statement is true if
you've been paying attention which statement is true about C. S.
one sixty   I can leave early since the midterm Tuesday evening
right before thanksgiving is optional. I don't have to show up
for the midterm; how many think that true okay I can leave the
Christmas break early since the poster session on Tuesday twelve
ten is optional alright that's another choice. Faculty don't
mind if I text or play on my laptop and finally your project
team needs to be in the same discussion section okay ready set
vote. So Armando, notice this. So that people like the people
who like ten weeks from now I'm sorry I've already booked my
tickets to go home early for thanksgiving I can't your midterm
drop the class right now there's people wanna take your place or
I've already I've already I I can't be there for the poster
session I'm leaving for home on December ninth I can't be there.