Okay. We're going to do a pure learning question here. Okay.
Ready. To test your regular expression chops. Here we go. This
is actually a bunch of things at once, because you need to think
about a race, you need to think about hashes, and you need to
think about regular expressions. Which of these four expressions
will evaluate to not nil? In other words, which one will result
in a successful reg x match of some kind? I'll let you parse it
for a bit. Okay. I think now we should take a vote. Your brain
is going to get used to this. Don't worry. Okay. Ready
everybody, let's vote. Vote. That means card up. Up. Up. Up.
Hand above. If your hand is above your head, your card is up.
That's much better. I se a rainbow of colors. As be fitting our
great city. Talk it over. All right, it's time for the revote.
Ready, recall vote. Okay. Let's go through these one at a time,
shall we? There's till not far from universal agreement. Well,
so what about ... Why could we rule out the first one right
away? We can rule out the first one as a matter of syntax. The
confusingly perhaps, although a braces is how you could setup a
hash literal. It's not how do reference it. You do reference
hash with the square brackets. So, syntactically, the first one
just wont fly. Let's see what's going o in the second one here.
In the second one, what we've got is hash col rx. We're going to
d reference the hash key that is key by the symbol fox, and yes,
indeed, we do have such a key. The value associated with that
key is this regular expression which as you might know from
regular expression review means the string that begins with
lower case ARM, but we're trying to match it against upper case
ARM, so no joy there. Close and open [ inaudible 00:01:50]. What
about this one? Well, this is saying, we're going to dereference
the hash entry that is pointed to by quote fox. Okay. While, we
got that, what is the value of that? That is an array of two
elements. Both elements are regular expressions. Here we're
dereferencing element one, arrays are zero based, so that would
be this element over here. We're going to try to match a regular
expression that is AN the parenthesis group DO, with ignored
case turned on. So we have a winner. Okay. We're trying to match
AMDO with ignoring case against this string, so that one's going
to work. So red is the correct answer for this one. Just quickly
on the last one. Remember we said you can actually do the match
on either sides? That part's okay, but what's going on here?
We're trying to dereference hash with two arguments. What's that
about? Hashes have a key, right? You dereference A particular
hash key. At least in these cases, we're dereferencing a hash
key, which happens to map to an array, and then we dereference
and array element. Did I mention the questions were going to get
harder? Okay. A lot of regular expression parsing.