Okay, the tour continues. So, we talked about Model- View-
Controller, we talked about models, and we're going to talk
about controllers next. And really, the important thing about
controllers is the special concept called REST, that is one of
these things people argue a lot about. But the basics of it are
not difficult to understand, and really, not that difficult to
get right. And the question that REST really answers is, " Given
that we believe Service- Oriented Architecture is a beneficial
way to organize services on the Web, what are some design
decisions that would allow our app to more readily support being
part of a Service- Oriented Architecture?" Or, another way to
look at it is, " What are poor design decisions that would make
it difficult for an app to participate in a Service- Oriented
Architecture?" So, continuing our tour, we're still here in this
middle tier, where the action happens in the app server. And
we're now going to look at controllers, and the relationship
controllers, URIs, and REST. So, REST stands for
Representational State Transfer, another sort of $ 20- dollar
word. Roy Fielding wrote about this in his PhD dissertation in
2000. And the words I'm using here are not the ones he used, but
I'm trying to convey the essence of what it is, because the idea
is relatively simple and straightforward. The idea is, " Don't
think about a URI as naming a page, or naming an action that
you're going to do. Think about it as naming a resource, and a
thing that you want to do to that resource." And the word
resource is very broadly defined here, right. The idea is, that
a resource could be a movie, and all the information about that
movie in Rotten Potatoes. A resource could be the list of all
movies that we know about. A resource could be the list of all
movies that match some criteria, and having a particular string
be part of their name, or having a particular MPAA rating. Those
are all resources. In fact, a resource can even the response of
trying to create a new movie. When I create a new movie, I've
created a new resource, and all I need to know was, " Did
creating that resource succeed or not?" So, start thinking about
the way that your URIs are expressing resources and things that
you want to do to them, in a self- contained manner. And, in
fact, the Wikipedia article for REST, I don't know if it still
contains this phrase, but it once did. " REST is really an
after- the- fact description of the features that made
successful Web services be successful." So, if you have a
service, if the sense of a Service- Oriented Architecture
Service whose operations follow these principles, then we say
it's a RESTful service, and it has a RESTful API. And, in such a
service, RESTful URIs name the operations that you do, and the
resources that you do them on. This is much easier to do if we
show a concrete example. So, to do that, I'll give a very brief
introduction, because we're going to talk about this in more
detail when we go back to exploring Rails, to how Rails allows
you to set up mappings between URIs and the controller. Because
remember, the controller is where all the action originates,
right. When a request comes in from the user, a controller is
where it hits first, and when there's stuff ready to be returned
to the user, the controller, it mediates that interaction. So,
what does Rails give you to help you to do this? A route in RAIL
is basically a mapping from a URI at an HTTP method, like GET or
POST or PUT, to a controller action. Here is a few examples that
are RESTful. If I say something like, " GET / movies/ 3", this
could be a way to represent whichever movie has the ID3 in the
database, I want information about it. Now, don't worry for the
moment about the fact that most end users are not going to know
the IDs of things in some random database behind your app. Think
just in terms of, " Assuming that we know the resource, and it
has a unique name, how do we construct resource requests that
name the thing that we want to operate on, and what we want to
do to that thing." Here's another example. When I submit a form,
and I POST to the URL "/ movies", the interpretation can be, "
I'm creating a new movie, and here is the data that I'm going to
use, the data to populate the attributes of that new movie
object." I could also say," I'm going to define " PUT / movies/
5" to mean, " If there's a movie whose ID is 5, and it exists in
the database, here is some new data to replace the current
attributes of that movie." Now, if you've done some Web
programming before, you've probably already are getting ready to
say, " Web browsers don't support PUT and DELETE, even though
HTTP defines them. Web browsers only support GET and POST." That
is true, but first of all, Rails provides some interesting
machinery to, essentially, simulate doing PUT and DELETEs. And
why would you want to do that? Because the way that we want to
think about our apps is not, " This is a user- facing app that's
a bunch of Web pages." We want to think about it as, " This app
is a collection of services, things that you can do to
resources. One way to interact with those resources is to serve
Web pages with which human beings interact." Or monkeys or
whatever. But another way to interact with that service is, I
could write an application that just makes HTTP calls against my
app. In fact, in an upcoming homework assignment, you're going
to do just that. You're going to make HTTP calls against the
Oracle of Bacon website. More about that in a future lecture.
So, what does the routing subsystem give you? Basically, it
gives you a bunch of machinery to take a URI and a method,
right, collectively, those two things together are a route. And
to map those to the correct controller action, so you know where
in your app the code is going to be called, to handle that URI.
It provides a bunch of helper methods that you can use to
generate the correct URI, given a controller action. So, again,
don't think about, when you're serving a page to the user, it's
going to have some links to allow the user to do other stuff.
You don't want to think in terms of links. You want to think in
terms of, " What new operations on resources am I going to
expose to the user?" And Rails provides a machinery for you to
take that information, and it will generate the correct URI,
based on your stated scheme of how you want to map your routes.
If you include parameters. If you looked at the textbook section
on URIs, you can embed parameters in the URI. There's machinery
to pull all that stuff out, so your controller method can get at
it. And there's built- in shortcuts, because the CRUD actions
are so common, there are built- in shortcuts to generate
automatically all of the CRUD routes for you, so that you don't
have to actually specify those mappings one- by- one. So, for
example, when you create a new app, and you say, " Here's a
thing in my app, movies are a thing. Movies are a resource that
I'm going to manipulate." For free, Rails will define all of
these routes, and create mappings to standardly- named methods
in your controller that are going to handle those actions. Now,
of course, you can create your own routes as well. You're going
to have a lot more things in your app than just basic CRUD on a
remodel. That wouldn't be a terribly interesting app. But, the
idea that you get these for free, and that, the way you get them
is by saying, " Movies are a resource," really is what
exemplifies the thinking that apps are really a collection of
RESTful services. And, oh yeah, a way that you can interact with
it is, you put a Web page in front of it. So, what exactly
happens, according to the scheme, " if I have an HTTP request
like GET / movies/ 3/ edit"? Right, that's one of the automatic
routes that's created for you by Rails, that means, " Invoke the
edit action on the controller associated with that resource."
What goes on behind the scenes when your browser generates that
request, and it hits your Rails app? Well, the first thing is
that, Rails' routing subsystem will match the URL, it will try
to match against one of the routes that's in the route table. In
this case, it matches the route that I've highlighted in yellow,
because the tokens that begin with a colon are like a wild card.
So, what'll actually happen is, the route will match, and the ID
portion of the route will be set to match the number 3 in the
URI. So, it'll parse the wild card parameters. Those actually
end up getting put in a hash that your controller can access for
free. Then, it'll dispatch to the edit method. Why? Because the
route specifies that, if the URI matches this pattern, it should
go to the edit action, or the edit Ruby method in the movies
controller. And, if I wanted then, as part of my controller
action, I want to generate a view that will cause the user to
submit a form to update that movie. So, what does that form have
to contain? It has to contain a submission URI that looks like
the one that's highlighted in yellow here, right. I need a form
that will cause this to happen when submitted. The bad, old-
school way that you would do this is, you would manually embed
in your view, in your HTML view, you would embed a hard- coded
URI to do that. What you do in Rails is, you say, " What I want
to do is, give the user a URI that will cause an update to movie
ID 5." And then it will generate the URI for you. Why would you
do it this way? Because if your route- naming scheme ever
changes, you don't want to have to go through and manually
change all the hard- wired routes that you created, right. You
want to be thinking in terms of resources and operations on
resources. And the mapping really is incidental, that's why that
part is handled for you. We're going to have a lot more to say
about routes and controllers when we do our walkthrough of Rails
apps. But I wanted to give you a flavor of what RESTfulness
looks like when you implement it in practice.