So, we're partway there. We said we need two actions to take
care of dealing with forms. We need to serve the form itself. We
saw how to do that. We also need to get the results when the
user submits the form, having filled it in, and so that's what
we're going to talk about next. When we receive the form, let's
actually take time to kill two birds with one stone here. We're
going to use the debugger to inspect what's coming from the
user. So, I'm going to go into a browser now, and I'm going to
bring up that form that we just saw. I'm going to fill it in
myself. I'm going to submit it, and then we're going to pause
right in the action that receives the form submission and see
what's going on there. Okay, so, here is- I'm going to start my
Rails server with debugging turned on. I've got my Rotten
Potatoes homepage, and I'm going to add a new movie. That was a
great movie, by the way. Now, before I click " save changes,"
which is actually going to submit the form, I want you to notice
that, over here in the movies controller, I have stuck in the
line " debugger," and it's in the create action. The create
action is going to be the one that receives the form submission,
because we already saw, based on Rake Routes, we can tell where
this form is going to go. Let's scroll down and find it here.
Here's the form. There's a bunch of other stuff that you don't
need to worry about just yet, but here's the important part,
right? We're going to the URI/ movies with a post method, and
Rake Routes would tell us that where that's going is this create
action right here. So, let's actually see what happens when we
push the button. And, although nothing happens over in my web
browser, in my terminal window, you can see that we've dropped
into the debugger. So, if you've used any interactive debugger
before, that's kind of where we are. What I really want to take
a look at is, what's going with this params hash, right? Params
is how any parameter is either entered by the user or passed in
the URI are getting captured, and we can see the value of that
hash here. Later in the course, we'll talk about this
authenticity token. It's a way to prevent certain malicious
attacks on your website. But what we're really interested in
here is the value of params[: movie]. Now remember I mentioned,
why would you want to name your form elements with things like "
movie bracket title," " movie bracket rating," and so forth? The
reason is that, if you do that, the value of params[: movie] is
itself a hash. Does that make sense? Because we're actually
gathering together all of the form elements whose names begin
with params[: movie]. The reason it's useful for it to be a hash
is because, you remember, back when we talked about using active
record to create, one way of calling the create action is to
pass it a hash of the attributes of the thing you want to
create. And lo and behold, what is params[: movie]? It is
exactly a hash of movie attributes for a movie that we want to
create. So, this is why the Rails views work the way they do.
Those form- tag helpers that we use, so that we wouldn't have to
generate each element manually, by default, they will generate
nicely named form elements, so that when they arrive in your
controller method, you already are ready to essentially hand it
right off to the create action. So, here's where we are in the
code. As soon as I continue, we're going to fall off the end of
this method, and that's going to leave us with a little bit of a
dilemma, because remember that every controller action
ultimately has to render something, and by convention over
configuration, since we haven't said otherwise, it's going to
look for a view template called create. html. hamel, and we
don't have one. There's nowhere for this action to go. So, I'm
going to keep you in suspense, and I'm not going to continue the
debugger just yet. But don't worry. We will come back to your
debugger friends soon enough. The important thing to notice
there is that params[: movie] is already a hash because of the
way we named the form field. Conveniently, that's exactly what
Movie create! wants to consume. So, now back to this question
of, what happens when we fall off the end of the controller
method? We're expected to render a view. So, let's think about
it from the point of view of the user. If you're about to get
information about a movie, well, it's pretty clear what we
should be rendering there, right? It's the actual information
you asked for. But if you're trying to create a new movie,
what's the appropriate thing that we should render to show you
the result of what you did? We could probably show you a page
that said, " Thanks for creating a new movie," and then you'd
have to click to go somewhere else, or, given that that's mostly
useless, you could just say, once it succeeds, we'll actually
redirect the user to a more useful page. In other words, we'll
finish the http request, we'll create the movie, but we'll
immediately take you to another page that's actually useful and
represents a reasonable user experience. A very common choice
is, if I was looking at the list of movies, I create a new
movie. On success, I'll go back to the list of movies, and look,
I can see the movie that I just created. So, that's the way that
we're going to do it. To keep in mind here, we said before that
http is a stateless protocol. Every request is independent. I've
just told you that we could redirect the user. Well, that's
going to trigger a whole new http request, and that leaves us
with a dilemma, because we would like to tell the user something
like, " Movie creation was successful." We want to give them
some feedback about what happened. If there's a whole new http
request, that means, by definition, we're not carrying over
instance variables from the previous one. So, how do we remember
the fact that we need to tell the user something? Of course,
because this is a common problem in SaaS applications, Rails has
a way to do it. It's called the flash. It quacks like a hash.
That means that you can expect it to do all the things that a
normal hash would do. But, it's special in that it will persist
until the end of the next request, as opposed to just the end of
this one. So, if I finish this request, before I'm done, I put
something into the flash. On the very next request, I can look
into the flash and grab out that piece of information, and it
will automatically be cleared out for me after that. By
convention, typically we use flash notice for information and
flash warning for error messages, but that's purely a
convention. So, putting those pieces together, what we probably
want to put in here is something like this. Notice that I'm
using the dangerous version of create. I'm kind of crossing my
fingers and hoping nothing goes wrong. That's fine for a lecture
example, not so fine for your applications. This is fine for
development. Don't use this in real life. But I'm going to
populate this with a nice little message, and then I'll have to
redirect somewhere. Where can I redirect to? Well, redirect is a
whole new action, right? So, let's just send the user back to
the page that shows the list of all movies. That's easy enough,
and I have a URI helper that I can use for that. Okay, now I'm
going to continue, and am I going to get an error message? Why,
yes, because by the time I made the change to my app, we had
already fallen into that method with the debugger. But rest
assured that if we repeat this- by the way, this is just the
error we expect, right? By default, create was going to fall off
the end of the create action, and it was going to look for a
template called create, and sure enough, it looked everywhere it
could think of, including under the couch, and it couldn't find
it, so we got a compliant. But rest assured that if we were to
do this again- add a new movie, and I have no idea when this
movie was released. We're still in the debugger. There. But this
time, no error message, because we added- what did we add? We
added this flash message, which my template is set to print out,
and we added a redirect that took us back to the list of movies.
This is a pretty standard idiom. When you're doing an operation
that results in changing the database, instead of just
displaying a passive page whose only purpose in life's to say, "
Your change succeeded," we usually acknowledge with a message,
like in the flash, and then send the user back to a page that's
otherwise more useful. So, we talked about the flash. The flash
is really a special case of a more general mechanism. In this
case, the session mechanism, think of it as a hash that persists
more or less forever. Now, there's a lot of qualifiers around "
forever," but basically, if I put something in the session for
this user, I can expect to get it out of the session for this
user during the entire time that they're continuously
interacting with my app. I can reset sessions and nuke the whole
thing. I can delete specific things out of the session that I
put there, and by default, cookies store the entire contents of
the session in the flash. Now, this is an important thing to
realize, because there's actually limits on how large a cookie
is allowed to be, right? Remember, a cookie, this is part of the
http protocol spec. So, if a cookie is only allowed to be a
certain number of characters long, and the session is just like
any other Ruby hash, you can put things of arbitrary size in
there. You could see where this is an accident about to happen,
right? I keep saying that all these frameworks try to give you
abstractions to help you out, but that those abstractions are
leaky. They are not perfect, and this is another example of
where the abstraction leaks. The session quacks like a
persistent hash that's available forever, but if you put
something in the session that's way too big to deserialize,
there might be a problem if it overflows the size of the cookie.
Now, you could be storing your sessions in the database. There's
a way to do that. If you've forgotten how to use the Google, you
take the important words out of the sentence and type them into
Google. Some people with really, really big systems, there's so
many sessions that they use a NoSQL system, like Memcached, to
store the sessions. But really, the thing to ask yourself is,
why are you putting complicated things in the session at all? If
you're putting things in the session that are more than object
IDs, you need to ask yourself what it is that's not restful
about your application. Because if you're putting them in the
session, then that must mean you're somehow relying on that to
survive from one operation to another, and that might be
jeopardizing trying to do a restful app.