Based on what you just heard, assume we have a table called
fortune cookies. It's got the column fortune text, and which of
these instance methods, if fortune cookie inherits from Active
Record, which of these will not return a silly fortune using the
extremely mature trick of adding “ in bed” to the fortune text?
Look those over for a moment. Initial vote? Let's do an initial
vote. Initial vote? Initial vote is showing all four things.
This is good. Shall we do a second vote? Let's do the second
vote? Second vote says? Second vote? Second vote is mostly
converging on red, some yellow, some green and some smart phones
with indeterminate RGB color mappings. Let's go through the
answers here. Let's see what's going on. Which of these will not
correctly retrieve and concatenate “ in bed” until the end of
the fortune text attribute? Let's just do them in textual order
here. What's happening here? We're claiming to dereference an
instance variable, but the whole point of Active Record is that
you're not just talking about instance variables anymore, you're
talking about attributes that have a representation in the
database. In this default case, fortune text will spring into
existence as nil, it will not be the attribute that you thought
it was, because the way Active Record manipulates its internal
attribute state is not just by setting up simple Ruby instance
variables. It actually has quite a bit of logic, so that when
those things get saved after the database, a number of the right
things will happen. The orange choice will not work, it won't do
what you expect. What about the green and the red choices? If we
start with the green one, if we said that these are instance
methods of fortune cookie, that's fine, because that means that
within an instance method of something, what is the value of
self? It's just the object that receives the message. Self.
fortune text is actually just an alias for fortune text all by
itself. Fortune text is a method call, remember all getters are
method calls. We just have to leave out ... we left out the
parens here. Yes it's true, some people have said, " Looking at
the red example, it's not really obvious that fortune text is a
method call as opposed to being a plain old simple variable."
That's true, and can you consider that a weakness of Ruby. Some
people always put empty parens when it's a method call, but the
way Ruby works is that if fortune text were a variable and it
was a local variable that was in scope, that's the value that
would get used. If there is no such local variable, it checks
whether there's a method and what you meant as a method
invocation. That's a potential ambiguity in the language. Some
people conservatively code around it by always having the empty
brackets after the method call. On the other hand, because
fortune text really is ... in real life, it's an attribute of a
model, that argues that you should notate it like an attribute
and attributes don't have parens after them. It's a little bit
of matter of taste, but syntactically, the choice number two in
green and number three in red are actually exactly the same.
Because when you don't have ... when you have a method call and
there's no explicit receiver, the implicit receiver is always
self. Good enough? Questions? Speaker 2: Two and three will both
work? S. Dupont: Three what? Speaker 2: Two and three will both
work? S. Dupont: Two and three will both work. One will not
work, and therefore, the fourth choice is clearly wrong. The
answer is number one.