Okay. Pair programming. The stereotype is the programmer is
this lone wolf working all night drinking Red Bull, right? Don't
bother me [ inaudible 00:00:13]. But is there a more social way
to program and what would be the benefits of multiple people
programming at the same time? How would you prevent this one
person from just doing all the work and the other person goes to
get coffee, right, and checks their mail, right? How do you
prevent that, right? Suppose there was a more social way and how
do you keep one person from dominating? That's what pair
programming is. The goal is to improve software quality or
making it get done faster by doing two people at the same time.
Now, it's not a natural thing to do so we want you to try it in
this class. Some people love it. Some students, they tried it
and they did their projects that way. They met every night and
they worked in pairs. Some companies love it. Pivotal Labs, in
particular, is an example. You should try this. This is a good
thing to do in school to see what you think about it. This is a
picture from Pivotal Labs. These are two employees here, Sarah
and JR. They sit side by side with the screens facing together.
To avoid distractions, this thing can distract you from paying
attention. There's nothing else on these machines. You can't do
Facebook. You can't do Twitter. You can't read email. It's just
workstations. They sit together and they talk and they play two
different roles. There's a role called the Driver, and that's
the person at the keyboard entering code, thinking tactically
about the current thoughts and explaining thoughts while typing.
If you've seen the medical shows with the surgeons, the surgeons
explain, " I'm going to cut here" - that's what the Driver's
doing. At the keyboard explaining what they're doing. The
Observer reviews each line of code, as he types in, and acts as
a safety net for the Driver and is thinking more strategically
in saying things, making suggestions to the Driver [ inaudible
00:01:52]. So that's the interesting roles. If the pair program
is working there should be lots of talking and you're
concentrating on the task at hand, not checking email. It's an
important part of pair programming that you alternate roles. You
don't want to have one person always be the Driver and one
person the Observer. Ten minutes then you swap and you go back
and forth. How well does this work? When it's not very
complicated it's quicker, pair programming. When it's
complicated, it yields higher quality codes and, since
somebody's looking at it, maybe more readable code. But some
studies indicate it's more effort than solo programmers, that
you don't get twice as much productivity from two programmers in
pairs as one. Now when we talked about our friends at - well let
me just mention that we talked to our friends at Pivotal Labs.
They said, " Well, I don't know. In this modern world, with
Facebook and Twitter and stuff, that's not factoring in the
distractions of the modern world. We don't get those
distractions. In fact, at Pivotal Labs, people come in at 9:00
in the morning and go home at 6:00 at night and they don't keep
working. And the people who have been there for three weeks,
they say 'I've never worked so hard in life. '"
They're not
used to just concentrating all the time in the day. People go
home at normal times. It's not the modern Silicon Valley way of
managing people, which is buying dinner, right? That's the
advanced, " Well, if I buy them dinner they'll work longer." I'm
a manager, right? It's hard for me... I don't know what to say
about this. It may not be more effort but that's what some
studies say. It has this added benefit of educational benefit of
transferring knowledge. When two people are sitting there you
can learn some programming idioms from the other one or tricks
or tools that you hadn't heard of. Or, how this company works or
the latest technologies. In fact, because of this, some people
do pair programming... The team will swap where everybody works
with everybody else to form pairs. That's called promiscuous
pairing. The do's and don'ts. Don't, when you're an Observer, be
using your smartphone. It can work for people of different
experience; you'll both learn. A great way to learn things is to
try and teach it. Those of us who... If you want to become a
teaching assistant, that's a great way to learn things is try
and explaining it. Swap frequently. This is... Please swap
frequently. You exercise different skills when you're thinking
tactically versus strategically and it's a good thing to do.