Let's understand the answers to this self- check question.
What's going on here? We want to select only the word " bar" for
styling and the question is which of these is going to do it?
Well, let's look at them each in turn. What about span. myClass?
That means the element tag has to match span and the C is what
the class attribute has to be myClass. That would work. Here's a
span and it has the correct class value. It selects only the
word " bar". Notice that even though the outer paragraph, the P
also has myClass. It doesn't match, because our role
specifically says it has to be a span tag. This one is okay.
What about the second one? This is an example of descended
navigation. We're saying, we want to match a element that has
the class myClass but only if that element is nested inside of a
P element. Again, here is an element that matches class myClass.
It's nested inside of a P element. The fact that the P element
also happens to have class myClass is irrelevant in this case.
The second one also works, because it does not select the outer
element. It selects the innermost one that matches the whole
rule. Whatever the third one. The third one says we're looking
for a span element, but only if it's inside an element that has
the CSS class myClass. Well, here's a span element and it is
indeed inside of a CSS element that has the class myClass and
just as in the previous rule, the fact that the span element
itself also has that class, that's irrelevant for the purposes
of matching this rule, right? The rule just says a span no
matter what as long as it's inside of something that matches
myClass. In this case, all three of these are valid ways to
select only the word " bar" for applying visual styles.