Now that we know how testing works in a modern software
development environment, we're going to take a look at the tool
called RSpec that we're going to be using for most of our
testing in this course. In introducing it, I'm going to
introduce an acronym to help you remember some of the principles
that go along with writing tests. Unit tests should be FIRST.
You can remember by the acronym FIRST these desirable properties
when you're writing unit tests. They should be fast. They should
be independent. They should be repeatable. They should be self-
checking, and they should be timely. Briefly, what does each one
of these mean and why do we care about it? Fast just means that
the test don't take very long to run. As we're going to see, a
typical application even a simple one is going to have hundreds
or thousands of test cases, so if the test took a long time to
run, it would disrupt your flow as you're moving between running
a test, writing a test, and writing the code. Independent means
that you can run any subset of the test, and expect them to work
in isolation. In other words, there is no dependencies on the
order in which different tests run. Again this is because in a
larger application even when the tests are running fast, it may
be too costly to run the entire test suite every time you make a
change. Having independent tests means that you can only run
that subset of tests that might be affected by your most recent
code changes. Repeatable means that the test will do the same
thing every time you run them. Now, this might seem obvious, but
when we do the self- check question for this lecture, we'll look
at some scenarios where it's not so clear if you can make a test
repeatable when they're trying to test a code that is inherently
none- deterministic such as if you're flipping a coin. Self-
checking means that no human being should have to examine the
output of the test in order to figure out whether they passed or
not, so the test should have enough information that after it's
finished executing, it knows whether the right thing happened.
We care about this for the same reason we care about any type of
automation. When we automate our test suites being ran and the
results being collected, it allows us to have a repeatable task
that we can always have running in the background. In fact,
that's what we're going to argue for in this lecture segment, so
repeatable just means that the same thing happens every time you
run them. Self- checking, they know whether they passed or not.
Lastly, timely means that the test were written pretty close in
time to the code that's going to be tested. We've said before
that we're going to do Test- driven development or TDD. That
means in most cases we're going to be writing the test before we
write the code. Later on on the course, we're going to teach you
how to do that, but for the time being, for the first couple of
homeworks, we have provided the test cases for you. We're going
to illustrate now how RSpec works to help us run those cases.
RSpec is a domain- specific language for testing, and a domain-
specific language or DSL means that it's specialized that doing
some narrow set of tasks at the expense of generality or at the
expense of other tasks. You've already seen some examples of
this. For example, regular expressions are a DSL for expressing
patterns that might match different kinds of strengths. If
you're familiar with data- based programming, SQL, the
Structured Query Language is a domain- specific language for
making data- based queries. A difference with RSpec is that it's
a domain- specific language embedded in Ruby. That is to say
that every RSpec program is actually a valid Ruby code, and it
takes advantage of Ruby features like a poetry mode to make it
more readable. What does this look like? Looking at this first
set of tests, we're describing a class called dessert, what
you're going to be asked to create as part of the next homework.
The first blog of tests is about a particular kind of dessert or
a cake, so what we're saying is the subject of our test is a new
dessert which we're specifying to be a cake with 400 calories.
Once we've created that new object instance, these very simple
tests consist of looking at various attributes, and make sure
that their values are what we expect based on the constructor.
We also have an apple which should be delicious and should be
healthy. As we get farther into the class, we'll teach you how
to interpret these specs in more detail, but for now, note that
things like beetle issues and be healthy use method- missing to
actually call method as delicious question mark and healthy
question mark in your class. As you read the homework
assignment, it will become clear that you're supposed to write
these methods to give information as to whether the dessert is
healthy or not. RSpec tests are called specs or examples. Each
spec or example tests one behavior, and one way to run the test
file is to run the RSpec command against the particular
filename, like the file that we just saw. What you'll see is
that you get error messages printed out in red for the test that
fail. The test that passed will be shown in green. Test that
have not yet been implemented or a so called pending test will
be shown in yellow. Now, as I said, a large project could have
thousands of test cases spread across hundreds of files, and
running RSpec on each file or even on the whole suite might not
be very efficient, so instead, we're going to prefer this other
technique of using autotest, which is a nice tool that not only
runs all of your RSpec tests but any time you make a change to
the test code or a change to the app code, autotest will figure
out which tests need to be re- run. It will automatically do
that. It's running in the background all the time. Let's take a
look at a demonstration of how that might work. I'm going to
skip to the ... Okay, this is basically the contents of the
directory that you guys are going to get for homework one.
There's about five or six different files full of tests that
we've created for you guys. I've got one of them up here. It's
called " Fun with Strings spec". As you'll see, there's a
convention that when I follow the name of a filename with
underscore spec, it means this is specs that go with that class.
I'm going to go into this directory, and I'm going to run
autotest. If I scroll up through here, you'll see there's a lot
of yellow messages, all of which are pending. It says, " No
reason given. They're yellow, but I don't know why they're
yellow." Well, the reason is that in the test files that we
supplied to you guys initially, all of the blocks of tests are
marked pending true, which means " don't even try to run these
tests because the code is not there yet." Now, supposed I delete
pending true for one segment of these tests, so you can see
there's three different tests here. It should work for simple
strings. It should be case- insensitive. It should ignore none-
word characters. I'm now going to save this file, and without me
doing anything, here we go, ready? Say file. Oh! It woke up. Now
it says, " Three failing examples," and indeed the three
examples that I just looked at at lines five, nine and 12, it's
now trying to run them, and re- divider should be up [ inaudible
00:06:38] in their own but it's not, so the meat of the homework
assignment id to write the code that does this, but what you
just saw is I changed something in the test file. Autotest
immediately figured out what I changed, and tried to rerun only
those tests. If I had been changing my code file, autotest would
figure out which tests have used that code file in the past so
that it could run the test against my updated code, so it just
run autotest in the background, and as you modify the code in
test files, you'll start to see these lines go green one at a
time as you backfill the code necessary for the test to pass.