Given that, here are three possible ways for generating the
form_ tag that, when submitted, would call the Create New Movie
action. The question is, which of these are valid ways to do it?
By the way, the way these questions are phrased clearly either
exactly one of them is valid or all of three of them are valid,
the way that I wrote the question. Take a look at this for a
moment. You can see that the top one is a call to a method, a
Ruby method in Rails called form_ tag. The other ones are really
just the HAML equivalent of manually creating a form_ tag
ourselves. Are these three all okay or is exactly one of them
okay? I'll remind you, in case it's useful, very briefly of what
you want the result to look like. Remember that from the
browser's point of view, this is the only thing that matters. It
doesn't matter how you got here. Just matters is that I know
what method to use when I submit the movie form and what URI I
have to submit it to. Do a quick initial vote on this one.
Initial voting? Initial voting? People? Cards? If you have no
arm, you don't have to hold up a card but otherwise you do. Most
people who held up a card held to the right color. Next time,
I'm going to have everybody hold the cards. But for this time,
blue is the right answer. I'm just going to walk through it
quickly. What's going on with these three? Taking a look at the
raw versions of these, really here we're just going to do a one-
to- one mapping of a HAML tag to an HTML tag. As you remember,
when you do a HAML tag, any attributes that you pass in this
Ruby hash essentially become the attributes of the HTML. Both
number two and number three would match what we saw that we need
to generate in terms of the HTML. Why is that they would both
match? The only difference between them is in one case, we use
the URI helper movies_ path. In the other case, we hard wire the
URI slash movies. If you did rake routes, you would see that the
movies_ path helper is created to give you this path back. Why
would you use the helper instead of hard wiring the path?
Because as your app gets more complicated, you may include
additional routes and you may change the mapping of logical
action names to the URIs that they connect to, using this level
of indirection, like movies_ path, allows you to redefine this
without then going ahead and changing the 25 different views
without a curse. The only other difference between number two
and number three is the use of a symbol versus a string. As I
mentioned much earlier, this is a Rubyism. In many cases, there
are methods where you can pass either a symbol or a string. It
gets converted to whatever is needed internally. This happens to
be one of those methods. I also mentioned that the reason or a
main reason that you would use a symbol rather than a string is
to connote that the value is not arbitrary. It's one of an
enumerable set. In this case, indeed, the only legitimate values
for method are the different HTTP methods, like get and post and
put and so forth. Its intent revealing to pass a symbol, because
it means this is one of a fix number of possible values as
opposed to this is an arbitrary string. Then as far as the first
choice here, form_ tag really just generates a form whose method
is going to be built in his post and whose URI is based on the
first argument of form_ tag, and again we're using the movies_
path helper here. For all practical purposes, these three are
all the same. My view is the first one is the most intention
revealing, because it says what you're trying to do and it uses
the URI helpers rather than hard wiring the URI in place.