Vote. I want to leave for a minute for the fun thing that didn't
work last time. Okay, you have a minute to talk it over because
that still leaves us two minutes for the fun thing. Revise vote.
Revise vote. We need to leave time for video game. Revise vote.
Revise vote. Wow, surprising amount of disagreement. Let's go
through these. Formal methods, they're expensive but worthwhile
to verify important applications. Well, I hate to tell you if
you think of something like Google Search as being pretty
important, I'm pretty sure Google Search is not formally
verified. Formal methods are great when you can use them but at
the moment people haven't really gotten a handle on how to use
them for very large systems. There are some systems that even if
you'd like them to be formally verified, they're really not.
Same is true of the space shuttle software, by the way. It is
meticulously done according to a P& D strategy but it's not
formally verified. Although you'd like to feel warm and fuzzy
about the top statement being true, it really isn't. P& D
developers tend to code before they write tests. That's
generally true unless the P& D project specifically has adopted
test- driven development. That sometimes happens but it is not
the norm in P& D projects. Agile developers tend to perform
module integration system and acceptance tests themselves.
That's true. It is also true that in most P& D organizations
there are separate teams that take over part of those testing
functions. Sandwich integration tries to sort of get the best of
both worlds by reducing the number of stubs and try to get some
general functionality early. That's also true. In this case,
number one was the false statement: formal methods are
expensive. That part is true but worthwhile for important
applications. There are some big applications that are important
and unfortunately we still can't use formal methods on them
because they're too big.