Okay. That let's do a peer questions to see if you communicate
thing well. Which statement is false about Waterfall, Spiral,
and Rational Unified Process Lifecycles? All rely on careful
planning, and measure progress against the plan. All reply on
thorough documentation. All reply on a manager to be in charge
of the project. All use iteration and prototypes. All right. See
how many people can get this, and how many people haven't lost
their card. Okay. Ready, set ... Okay. Vote. All right. As I
suspected, that's pretty straightforward. Yes. The right answer
is the fourth one. The incorrect answer is the fourth one. All
use iteration and prototypes. That waterfall doesn't use
iteration prototypes, but the others do. All right.