Next in our series of topics, once again, motivating the
question of why would you care about databases and Active
Record, which I'll describe next. Here's the question that this
is trying to solve. So far, when we talked about object
orientation and how classes are organized, we talked about
classes, there's instances, and instances can have attributes.
This is a record- oriented way of looking at the world. We have
instances of things like bank accounts, and each instance has
some attributes associated with it. In our web apps, we're going
to have to be able to store that data somewhere, we're going to
have to be able to retrieve it and search it. That means that we
have to have some relationship between the way we store the data
and the way that we manipulate it in our programming language.
The different ways that people have tried to solve that problem,
create that mapping, lead to different ways of thinking about
how you should organize and store your data. Going back to our
diagram, where are we today? We are still diving down into the
structure of the applications here and we're going to look at
how the model part of Model- View- Controller is handled in the
Rails framework. Again, I'm going to present more than one way
to do it besides the way that Rails does it, to send the message
that just because Rails does it this way, doesn't mean that this
is the appropriate way for all applications. Let's talk about
objects in memory versus objects that you store. We've seen,
when you create new classes and you create new instances of
those classes in Ruby, obviously there's some in- memory
representation of those objects and their attributes. The
question here is, " How do you represent that object in storage
in such a way that later on, you can essentially take that
object back out and reconstitute it?" It's as if you need to
store the object, kill the program that was manipulating the
object and know that later on, you can restart the program, read
the object back and not lose any information. Generally
speaking, the process of doing that is called marshalling. It's
also called serialization. There's a subtle nuance in
distinction and meaning, but not one that we're going to worry
about. The idea is that if I marshal an object, it means I'm
converting it to a new format that makes it amenable to doing
something. Usually, something is storing it or transmitting it
someplace else. I'm doing it in such a way that later, I can un-
marshal or deserialize and get back a representation in my
language that is, in every functional way or every behavioral
way, equivalent to the thing that I started with. In our case,
we're talking, for example, about a movie with attributes like
Name and Rating. How might we take the in- memory representation
of that and store it some place? In particular, the operations
we need to do, whenever we're talking about managing stored
data, we can create a new copy of something. In our case, in the
persistence here, we can read an existing copy of something we
stored before, we can update. For example, we could change the
name of the movie and want to keep that change permanent and of
course, we can delete things from permanent storage.
Collectively, these are the CRUD operations. The way that Rails
organizes its models is according to another design pattern
called Active Record, whose main conceit is that every model,
every type of thing like a movie, knows how to CRUD itself using
a set of common mechanisms that all the different model share.
If you come from, for example, the PHP world, you're accustomed
to there being an object that represents the connection to the
database. You create queries and things like that, which you
hand off to that object. The Active Record view of the world is
quite different. The database doesn't ... isn't really visible
to the programmer as an explicit obstraction. The obstraction
is, here's a collection of operations you can do on this kind of
object. It happens to be the case that the object is going to be
stored in the database. We'll talk more about that separately,
but the Active Record view of the world is there's a common set
of machinery that allows any type of Active Record object to do
these basic operations. In the case of Rails, I think many years
ago, we all agreed that relational databases have won the battle
for being the way that most web apps store their data. Roughly
speaking in a relational database, each kind of model that we
have is going to get its own table in that database. All the
rows in the table have the same structure. That's part and
parcel of what relational databases means. One row in the table
is one instance of a particular model, of a class ... a
particular model class. Since each row is one instance of a
model, it stands to reason that the columns would be the
attributes and each column stores the attribute value. Each row
also has a unique primary key. By convention, in Rails, this is
an integer and it's called ID. Don't let that confuse you. ID is
not really a property of movie, the object in Ruby, but it is
going to have to be a property of movie, the object that's
stored in the database. This is one example of how obstructions
aren't really perfect. We're saying that we want to make a
mapping between objects and memory objects in the database, but
in fact, they're not really going to be identical. There's going
to be a few ways in which they differ. As we'll see, the reason
for those differences is because the way a database wants to
manipulate an object and the things that you have to represent
to allow the database to do so, have some overlap, but not
complete overlap, with how Ruby wants to manipulate an object
and what kinds of things you might want to do an object in the
Ruby world. Collectively, if you look at all of the tables in a
particular database, what columns they have and so forth, what
the types of those columns are, that is collectively called the
schema for that application. What's an alternative? Suppose you
didn't want to do Active Record, what else do people do and why
might they do it? Data Mapper is a different way of thinking
about data that says, " Every time you define a new kind of
model, you also have to come up with a mapper for that model."
The mapper is responsible for figuring out the specifics of how
that type of model is going to be stored in that database. The
reason you might want to do this is that it keeps the mapping
strategy independent of a particular type of data storage. For
example, as we'll see, Rails models, because they're based on
Active Record, because they know they're going to be stored in a
relational database, the Active Record machinery takes advantage
of a lot of things about relational databases. If you've read
about things like the NoSQL movement, people using things like
MongoDB and SimpleDB and a lot of other databases, most of those
are non- relational. They lack a lot of the features for data
manipulation that relational databases have. In those cases, you
can't really use Active Record because of its heavy reliance on
the relational model. You could use something like DataMapper,
but in fact, you don't get anything for free. If you use
DataMapper, then a lot of the work that an Active Record has
done for you, now you have to redo that work yourself and you
have to reinvent it to fit what your database is able to handle.
This will become a lot more clear when we start talking about
more advanced concepts like Associations Between Models. Just as
a data point, Google App Engine uses the DataMapper pattern.
That's the way that they recommend you rate apps against their
storage system, because one of the nice things about DataMapper
is by leaving out some of the complex relational database stuff,
it actually allows their storage system to reach much larger
scale than most relational databases can reach. That's an
example of an architectural trade off. When you get to a certain
scale and using a relational database for some things just is
not in the cards anymore, here's an alternative that you could
use.