Let us start talking about debugging. I reordered some of the
segments because in view of the fact that we have more homeworks
then we’ ve had before in this class, and it is a really fast-
paced introduction to Ruby and Rails. We know that, and we’ re
asking quite a bit of you guys to step up to the plate. Let me
just give some words about debugging, and none of what I’ m
going to say about debugging is specific to this course. This is
all information that I hope will serve you well anytime you move
to a new language or a new system. Compared to debugging command
line programs or other kinds of programs you may have written,
SaaS can be a little bit trickier because for one thing you’ re
probably used to being able to print up some stuff and see it in
the terminal. There is no terminal in the SaaS world. It’ s
running on a server somewhere so the idea that you can have
stuff printed out to the terminal doesn’ t work too well. Also,
remember that there’ s a lot moving parts in these applications.
We start with a URI coming from a browser. There’ s a routing
subsystem. The controller has to get invoked. The model does
stuff so there’ s sort of all these places where things have to
happen, and sometimes an error can occur early in the flow but
not become manifest, not show symptoms until later in the flow.
Sometimes if it’ s an error that only arises under a certain
difficult conditions, it might be hard to reproduce. That’ s
another thing that’ s tricky. We’ ve got external users. You
can’ t control what the inputs are. There’ s a couple of
different things that I’ m going to talk about and how you can
approach debugging. One thing is something you probably all have
done in many other languages, which is printing stuff to the
terminal. Some people call that printf debugging, and in
development mode, that’ s fine. You can certainly do that, and
I’ ll show you a couple of different ways. There’ s log- in.
Even though there’ s no interactive terminal in the production
server, there are certainly log files where you can write stuff.
A colleague of mine that said that log files are actually more
important in some cases then the code and the comments because
the log file, when you write a message of the log file, you’ re
expressing your intent as a programmer of what was supposed to
happen in the app. It doesn’ t mean it actually happened, but
you wrote to the log file that you thought this what’ s supposed
to happen so that can be very valuable. When it’ s time to
really bring out the big guns, Ruby has an interactive
debugging. We’ re going to demonstrate a little bit later on.
However, all debugging has the following four letter acronym in
common. It [ WEEVS 00:02:00] RASP. It could also be SPAR or PARS
or whatever you want, but it’ s the same four things. When you
run into a problem, first of all calm down. Debugging is a fact
of life. You’ re always going to do it, and we were very big on
test- driven development and stuff like that, but I would be an
idiot to say that that’ s going to guarantee you’ ll never
experience bugs during the running of your code. This is just …
we’ re programmers. It’ s a fact of life. First, read the error
message. Let me say that again because it bears repeating.
Really read the error message. Some of the error messages may
look like a lot of spew, but in the scheme of things it’ s not
that many lines of spew, and there’ s valuable information in
there, like usually the file and the line number of where
something went wrong; the backtrace, which is a list of all the
functions that called you all the way up to the top level where
Rails first got invoked. Understanding at least where you should
start looking for the symptom is one thing you can find in
there. Ask a colleague. You’ re surrounded by colleagues in the
class. You’ ve also got the staff of the course, but when you
ask a question, try to ask the most informed question you can. A
bad example of a question is, help, my code doesn’ t work. A
good example of a question, is, look, I got this far. I expected
this variable to have this value, but it seems to have this
other value or it has nils of value, and this is the
circumstances. The more information that you give, the more like
that somebody could say, oh, yeah, I know what that is. Here’ s
what you might’ ve done wrong. If that doesn’ t work, you can
ask more colleagues the internet. You can use StackOverflow,
which is one of my favorites, but there are other sites as well,
and this is especially true if the error involves a particular
version of a library or something like that. Sometimes the bugs
don’ t manifest the same way on different versions, but somebody
out there’ s probably had the same bug you had. For the more
obscure ones where it’ s not just a bug in your logic, but there
might actually be an issue with the framework, things like
StackOverflow are a great resource. If you can’ t find the
answer already on StackOverflow, you can post there. There’ s
also the course forms, [ Piasa 00:03:46] and so forth, but
remember everybody who reads those is as busy as you are. They’
re also trying to debug and get their code to work. To help them
help you, give them the most complete information you can but
also concise. Don’ t confuse complete information with copy and
paste the entire transcript of the error message. That takes a
long time for them to read. You do the work of reading, and it’
s your error message. Once you’ ve narrowed it down to a smaller
set of circumstances, maybe you could even reproduce the bug in
a controlled manner with less code, that’ s what you post. Those
questions tend to get answered within minutes on StackOverflow.
How do you read these error messages? They are long, but you can
parse them. You know, you’ re all very smart. The backtrace
shows you where you came from, so not only where the error
occurred but who called that method and who called that method
and so on all the way up to the top. A very common message,
especially in Ruby, is you’ ll see undefined method, something,
for nil, and 99% of the time here’ s what’ s happening in this
message, and I’ m using this as a specific example because it is
so common. Often it means that you did some sort of a call where
you assigned a variable, but you didn’ t bother to check for an
error condition, and a lot of Ruby methods when an error of some
kind occurs, instead of raising exception, they’ ll return nil
instead of returning the object that you expected. For example,
we’ re going to show later how you talk to the data base in a
Rails app, and you might do a find on the data base expecting to
pull out, let’ s say, a movie from the movie’ s table, and if it
turns out that that movie’ s not there for whatever reason, M
will come back nil. When you try to dereference something on it,
well, this is syntactically legal. You’ re trying to call a
method on the object, but if M is nil, nil is an object that
doesn’ t know how to do that many things. It is not a very
talented object; hence, the somewhat initially confusing method,
undefined method foo for nil. When you think about it, it
actually does make sense. The value of M is nil, and you tried
to call the method title on nil, and that doesn’ t work. Other
things that you can do, instrumentation, which is a fancy word
for printing the values of stuff as you collect the data during
the time your program is running. As we’ ll see, you can put
limited amounts of code in your views. I know I’ ve told you,
you shouldn’ t do it, but sometimes when you’ re debugging you
got to break some eggs, etc. There’ s a couple of methods like
debug, which prints out, I should say generates, a string
representation of an object that’ s nicely pretty printed, and
you can just stick that right into your view. Your view will
look terrible, but given that there’ s no terminal to print to,
this is a good thing to be able to see on the screen. A slightly
lighter- weight version is inspect. Inspect is a method that is
defined on objects. Every Ruby object responds to it, although
the default thing that it prints out to describe itself is not
necessarily that useful. That’ s why most interesting classes
override inspect and print out something more useful about
themselves. They try to print a program or useful representation
of what the object is. You could also write stuff to the log. I
am a big fan of logging. Space is cheap. Write log files. There’
s a logger method that returns the logger object. All controller
methods can have access to it, and there’ s different warning
levels like debug and warn in error, just as you’ ve probably
seen in other logging systems. Remember, if you try to just use
printf or its various equivalents, they nowhere to go. In a
production server, there just going to sort of disappear. When
it comes time to search and using the internet to answer
questions, you’ d be surprised how far you can get by using the
Google, seriously. Suppose your question is how do I format a
date in Ruby? Well, let’ s pick out the elements of that
sentence, shall we, the subject, the verb, and the direct
object; format, date, Ruby. Search for those three things in
Google. I guarantee you’ ll find some results. How do I add
Rails routes beyond the standard CRUD ones that get defined for
you? Again, look at the key words in your question, type those
key words into Google, and rely on the wisdom of the world to
see if you get an initial step. A lot of error messages have
been reported by people other than you, amazingly enough. Read
the documentation. We used to have an abbreviation for this,
RTFM, but since no one reads anymore, the abbreviation has lost,
perhaps, some of its currency. Nonetheless, there’ s complete
searchable, nicely formatted online documentation for both Rails
and the Ruby libraries, both of which are extensive. Read the
source. Rails is source code. Rails is actually just a Ruby
library that’ s part of your app, so if you’ re really curious
you can actually traceback into Rails. The error occurred
somewhere when Rails was trying to do this thing. What is that
part of Rails actually doing? You can go read the documentation
and find out. Of course, StackOverflow, my personal favorite.
Use Rails console. So we’ ve been using irb for simple examples,
but what you really want is you want a Ruby command line
interpreter that actually has the entire environment of your
application loaded into it. It knows what database tables you
have and so forth. Rails console more or less does that. In some
cases, if you need to inspect the state of the program at a
particular point in time, like what happens when I get to this
point in my controller method? In those cases, even Rails
console is a little bit awkward to use so a little bit later I’
ll show you a demo, a real interactive debugger that you can use
in cases like that. That’ s kind of bringing out the big gun.
You don’ t need to do that too often.