Today we're going to start talking about the web as a client-
server system and the architecture that underlies SaaS
applications because the architectural choices that we make are
actually common to any SaaS application. They predate a lot of
the material that is specific to ruby and rails. One of the key
lessons that we're going to talk about through the rest of the
segment is whatever you do an architecture, you're making some
choices about the way that components fit together in that
architecture and we're making some choices around the fact that
our architecture softwares a service that we're using open
standards. In cases where we're making a choice, we'll also
eliminate what's some other possible choices might be. In terms
of this diagram that's reproduced from the book, we're going to
start at this top level right up here where in the simplest
possible manner, we think of a web browser, we think of a series
of tubes in between and we think of a site where you want to end
up and get some content. From 100,000 feet away using height as
an analogy and as we go closer to the ground, we'll see more
detail, you can think of the web as a client, server
architecture which means that it's request and reply oriented. A
client is a thing that asks questions, a server is a thing that
gives answers. Fundamentally, each piece of software, the client
and the server is specialized in some way for that role. Now, in
our case, the client is a web browser like Chrome of Firefox or
Safari or Internet Explorer. The website or the web server is
the server part and in between, we have the internet which
magically routes content from one end to the other which we're
not going to go into a huge amount of detail about but we'll
give you the basics. The simplest possible interaction, the web
browser asks the server for something. That's the client asking
a question of the server. The server response, the response
comes back. How does this all happen? Well, there's a long
history of a set of protocols going back to the 60 's called TCP
IP for transmission controlled protocol and internet protocol.
Starting with the second half of that, here is the one slide
crash course on what you need to know. The internet protocol is
a set of rules that computers agree to follow in order that they
can all interact when we talk to each other. You probably have
seen these internet protocol addresses, IP addresses. They're
four integers separated by dots. They're often called four
octets because each integer can be an eight bit number. There is
a special address, 127.0. 0.1 which always means this computer,
whichever computer I'm running on right now, as opposed to being
a unique address of some machine somewhere else. In general,
every machine in the universe has more or less a unique address
although with routers and network address translation, that's a
little more complicated than it once was. There is also a
special name called local host that in the UNIX world and on any
computers that's derive their ancestry from UNIX, the name local
host means this machine that I'm running on right now and we're
going to use this fact in doing a simple example in a moment to
show how the internet works. Now, IP just says if you give me
the address of a remote machine and a small bit of information,
a packet which is really only a few hundred bytes of
information, I will do my best to get it over to that other
machine but there's no guarantee that it'll get there.
Furthermore, if you send multiple packets, for example, you got
too much information, you got to break it up, there's no
guarantee that they'll arrive in order or that some of them will
arrive at all or that they will arrive completely free from
errors. On top of IP, there's an additional layer of protocol
called transmission control protocol or TCP whose job it is to
make sure that all the right things happen. TCP essentially
monitors the IP packets and make sure that is there is a gap in
the order in which they're delivered, that it re- request the
packets that got lost. If there are errors in transmitting the
packets, it re- request the corrupted packets to make sure that
it gets them all correctly and it reassembles them in a proper
order. The result being that as a programmer, you can have th
luxury of the illusion that you're putting long strings of
characters or bytes into a pipe and at the other end, they're
coming out of the pipe in the same order, reliably and you can
just think of it as printing strings pretty much. Now, one
nuance is if we want to have multiple different programs on the
same computer all using TCP, we need a way to identify which
traffic streams are intended for which programs and the way TCP
does that is by using port numbers. A port number is just a 16
bit number that essentially identifies a particular program
running on a certain machine and says this traffic is intended
for that program to consume. As we'll see in the case of the
World Wide Web, it's been decided by the powers that be that
port number 80 is the standard port on which web servers should
listen for traffic. In a moment, we're going to do a very simple
demonstration of running our own very brain dead web server just
so you can see how simple protocols really are. Of course, any
protocol effort like this is a result of decades of work by a
lot of people but I think the two gentleman who are giving
credit for really making these ideas real and putting them into
practice as TCP IP are Vint Cerf and Bob Kahn who shared the
Turing Award in 2004 for their work on network protocols which
ultimately led to the development of TCP IP which now powers
billions of computers all over the world. How does this work?
The beauty of TCP IP is I can pretend that I've got a pipe into
which I'm going to put a string like get/ bears, at the other
end of that pipe, there's somebody listening who is able to pull
out that same string just how I put it in. The other side will
come up with some reply to my question. For example, here is a
line that says everything is fine and the content is coming your
way and they send that response back to me and I pull it out.
It's really, gives you the illusion of a reliable sequence of
bytes that can go on either directions. It's a bi- directional
or full duplex protocol. Now, I lied when I said that at the
simplest possible level there's just a client and a server. In
fact, there's a third piece of the web that very fundamental to
how it works which is DNS, Domain Name System, and that's the
service that allows us to use meaningful names like Google. com
or Microsoft. com instead of trying to remember those addresses
with four numbers separated by periods. The domain name server
is actually a separate kind of service. The diagram I showed
before, really should have look like this. What I want to talk
to a web server really the first thing I do is I have to go look
up the internet protocol or IP address of that server from a DNS
server and DNS servers are usually configured by whoever your
ISP is. Once I get that information back, now I have the IP
address and I can do what I really wanted to do. The irony here
is that even though DNS is a totally separate service, for all
practical purposes, most of us would think the internet was down
if DNS wasn't working because most web browsers and other
programs no longer rely on being able to just remember the raw
IP addresses, they rely on being able to do this mapping at
runtime. Now that we know how to talk over TCP IP, what do we
say? The way that we exchange content between browsers and web
server is a very simple network protocol called hyper text
transfer protocol or HTTP. It is ASCII- based, that means that
everything that goes back and fourth asking for stuff and
getting the status of whether that stuff can be returned or not,
those are just plane old strings. They're easy to read, human
beings can do site for the protocol. An HTTP request is very
simple. There's a request method, get and post are the most
common ones but there is three or four others that you'll come
to meet during the rest of the course. There is a URI, you've
seen this before. The URI names the thing that you would like to
retrieve and the HTTP protocol version, a very important lesson
from the networking literature is when you deploy a protocol
that many millions of clients and servers are going to use, one
thing you should put in the protocol itself is for each party,
when it speaks, to identify what version of the protocol it's
using. The reason to do this is that if you upgrade the protocol
or add features in the future, you want to make sure that if
somebody asks you for something using an old version of the
protocol, you don't accidentally use these new features that the
older clients maybe haven't been upgraded yet. There's also some
protocol headers in HTTP. They give some extra information both
for the client's point of view and from the service point of
view that a company request or the company that reply. The most
important HTTP request and the replies that we'll see is we'll
get a status code back from the server of all as well. The
resource has moved like redirect or there was some kind of a
problem and I wasn't able to serve your request. Now, this is
all much easier to see in demonstration form than it is to do on
a slide so let's do a very simple demo. What I've got is I've
got an instance of a Google Chrome browser here and I've got a
terminal window where I'm going to run a program that is a
standard part of the index called net cap NC and I'm going to
say listen on port 8000. Remember, I said TCP uses port numbers
to identify different programs that want to receive TCP traffic.
I am now a program that is waiting for somebody to send me some
traffic on port 8000. I'm going to go over to our web browser
and create that traffic. Remember, I said local host is the
magic name that means this machine that I'm running on right
now, I'll make sure that we're using HTTP, and you can follow
the host name with a colon and a port number. Remember, I said
that port 80 is the default port for web traffic. If I didn't
include a port number in the URI, 80 would be assumed but in
this case, I want to make sure that I direct some traffic
specifically to this terminal window that we're listening on.
Let's see what happens if we try to visit this URL. You can see
that the web browser has sent over a request. It's saying, I
want to get the root resource because I didn't put anything
after a slash or anything after the host name part of the URI.
It's identifying the version of the protocol that it knows. I
know protocol version 1.1 so that means that the server is in
its best judgment is going to reply and only use features of the
protocol available in 1.1 and earlier so it's not to confuse the
client. The client gives us some more information about itself
like what kind of a computer I am. I can see that I'm running a
Mozilla browser on a Macintosh and so forth. Now, you can see
our web browser is just sitting here. We've got the little
spinning circle that indicates the browser is waiting for
something to happen and that's because it's waiting for a reply.
We're going to give it the simplest possible reply. Sure enough
there's hello world. Now, you noticed it before anything
appeared. I have to essentially quit out of the net cap program
and close the connection because that's the easiest way to tell
the browser I've finished saying everything I'm going to say. At
that point, the browser pulls the string of characters out of
the TCP pipe and displays it. Now, we broke a few rules here.
Technically, what we should have done is we should have included
some headers like this, telling the browser what's coming your
way. In our case, we're just going to deliver some plain text
and for historical reasons, browsers are very tolerant if you
just return some plain text without any other identifying
information. They tend to do the right thing. The big message
here is you just seen in its simplest form what HTTP does. The
client asked a question, there was a server on the other end
waiting for questions to be asked and we supplied and answer to
that question which then went back to the client, back to the
web browser. Now, one issue that we haven't talked about yet is
early on in the design of HTTP, a decision was made but the
protocol would be stateless which specifically means that
whenever I make a new HTTP request to any particular server,
it's as if that server has never seen me before in its life. The
corollary of that, if there's any information that has to be
maintained across request then there has to be some separate
mechanism for doing that. An easy example of this is even in
early web apps, there's an notion of going through a flow of
pages in the application. For example, you visit a product page,
you add something in your shopping cart, you check out and
somehow the server has to remember which step you're on. How can
it do that if every request from you is independent and as if
every request was like the first time. Cookies were invented to
do this and essentially, the first time that you visit a site,
the site has the option of sending back along with its response,
a little piece of information called the cookie and most of the
time, that's really just a name for some state that the server
is going to maintain about you. The wen browser's job is to
remember that cookie and anytime you make another visit back to
that same server, make sure that that cookie value is supplied
along with it. Cookies essentially provide a way of saying, "
Hey, remember who I am? You served me this cookie value and now
you can look me up." You can remember what I was doing last in
your application. As you might expect, as a framework that's
mature for doing SaaS applications, rails has pretty good
facilities for handling cookies so that you're more or less
don't have to worry about it.