The tour continues. We have done models. We have done
controllers, and that leaves only views, and as with models and
controllers, there is more than one way to deal with views and
as with models and controllers I am going to show the way Rails
does it. I am going to show you at least one other alternative
and we will talk about why you might make different choices for
different situations. So, we are going to talk about template
views, which is a specific way that we can handle views in an
MVC app. So basically what problem are we trying to solve here.
We know that browsers display HTML. That is what they do. So
whenever we return stuff it is going to be user facing. That is
the format that we have to use. The questions is how does the
data that we store in our app become HTML, and again if you have
done any kind of web program in other frameworks you have
probably done a few different variations of what people call
template view which we are going to explore next. In the
template view pattern basically you have a view that consists of
a certain amount of fixed markup, stuff that does not change, no
matter what the request is and then at runtime you interpolate
selective data into that view template. So, for example there
may be a generic template for displaying information about a
movie and then at runtime whichever specific movie is chosen
that information gets substituted in or interpolated in. So one
example is that you have a bunch of variables and the values of
those variables get instantiated into the code or into that
template of runtime. You might have little short bits of code
that are embedded in the template, and back in the olden days,
that was pretty much the whole app, right. If you look at
especially some of the earlier PHP apps, they start out being
HTML, HTML and then the little percent sign and then there is
some code and there is more HTML. Over time, what happened is
that the HTML became tiny and the code that got embedded in them
became huge, so this is not a great way to keep your app easily
manageable. So we are going to do it according to the model view
controller way of doing it. We are going to use a templating
system called HAML, which I will introduce you to momentarily,
and how do these template views really work if you follow MVC.
You take a templating language in which to express your HTML or
whatever templates you want and you take a closure. We have
already talked about closures. Now they are making a
reappearance. Closures are your friends. Why, because a closure
is an environment containing a bunch of state, including things
like variable values which you can then interpolate into your
view. In the case of Rails, there is a module of Rails called
action view module. It contains rendering logic that is able to
do this. It can combine fix markup that you provide with other
data that you interpolate. Basically what you do is you pass it
at closure and I am going to prove that to you in a moment, and
the output from the render is the final HTML page ready to serve
to the end user. There is another templating system, which is
actually the one that really comes standard with Rails that is
called ERB or embedded Ruby. We are not going to use it because
as you know, I have an obsession with putting the fewest number
of marks on the page to get something done and HAML does a much
better job at that as I will show in a moment, but ERB ships
with Ruby and essentially it is very much like PHP where by
default you put HTML content in there but you have got a way of
saying for this part of the content substitute the result of
running some Ruby code or interpolating the value of the
variable from Ruby. Again, alternatively whenever you make an
architectural choice you are ruling out some other choice. What
would you do if you were not doing template views? Well, another
possibility is you get a transform view which is only a bit more
radical. In transform view, you have a collection of information
which is going to say a closure that represents what you want to
display to the user and you have a bunch of data items and there
is really no intermediate template that they are filled in with.
For example, what would be a way that you might use this.
Suppose that what you’ re really doing is generating Jsigner or
XML, both of which we are going to learn about a little bit
later in the course, but there are other data representation
that are portable across applications and across networks. In
that case it does not really make sense to have a template that
a fill- in, what you are really doing is getting data in one
form, the way it is stored in the database and converting it or
serializing it into a different form like XML that you might
transmit to another service. So the idea of a template does not
really make sense in that case. It is a really more
transformation from one format to another, hence the name
transform view. So, in fact, we can use both, right. When we are
creating our apps and again thinking of the app is a collection
of services when a user interacts with it template view is used
because we want to provide the user with HTML pages with what a
human being can interact but when that same set of services is
accessed by another program. In other words, when we are
participating in a service- oriented architecture really we will
end up using something more like transform view so that we can
feed a transform version of the raw data back to some other
service and we will show examples of how you can sort of
trivially with a one line change make your controller method to
do double duty on those things. So the markup system that we
recommend using and that we sort of settled on for the exercises
in this course is called HAML. I think it stands for HTML
abstraction markup language, but the creator’ s name is really
similar to the acronym HAML, so you might look it up. It is
pretty interesting. I think of it as HTML on a diet. What are
some salient features of HAML compared to regular HTML. Well,
instead of HTML tags with angle brackets we use percent signs to
indicate the tags and instead of nesting the tags we use
indentation. So if you have programmed in Python, this should
look familiar. The indentation level tells you what the scope of
each tag is. So for example here I have a table. What is the
scope of the thead element. It is basically everything down to
this point because that is where the indentation level resumes
and the entire table goes all the way down to write before this
last line that says link_ to, right. So indentation is used to
indicate scope. What else we saw how the CSS attributes or the
HTML attributes class and ID are very heavily used for page
styling, so HAML gives you a nice shortcut where you are allowed
to put a dot and a CSS class on an element or you are allowed to
put a hash mark and a CSS ID on an element. You got ways to
interpolate code into the HTML or into the HAML in this case.
You can put a hyphen in front of a line which means execute this
code or you can put an equal sign in front of a line which means
substitute the result of running this code directly into the
template. So what is the difference between those? In this case,
movie. title, well I want to actually get back a string
representation of that and make that part of the page, whereas
in this line really all I am doing is starting a for loop,
right. I am starting an iteration. The iteration itself does not
have any output that is interesting to capture. So, it allows
you to do both, right. The hyphen means do not interpolate the
output just run the code. The equal sign is do interpolate the
output, and if the code overflows on to more than one line you
can use of vertical pipe symbol at the end to indicate that
there is more than one line of code. HAML makes it deliberately
awkward to view that because the real thing is you should not be
putting code in your views at all. The code really doesn’ t
belong in the part of the MVC whose job is to show information
to the user. The code belongs in the controllers in the model,
really mostly in the models. So HAML sort of goes out of its way
to do a little social engineering about this. It is deliberately
awkward to do a multi- line bit of code because it is trying to
send you a signal but that code really is somewhere where it
should not be. So did I say, do not put code in your views. Do
not put code in your views. So technically you are allowed to,
and in fact the multi- line mechanism in the HAML, you could put
an entire novels worth of Ruby code in their but MVC advocates
for a reason that views and controllers should each be thin. The
view has a limited function in life. It is to present
information to the user. If the view is operating or
manipulating that information, you should ask yourself why is it
doing that. If it is doing it because there is a new computation
over that information that turns out as interesting that may be
should be part of the model because what models do is manage the
way the information is stored or manipulated. If all you are
trying to do is make it look prettier. For example, if you want
to display a price and it is coming back as a floating point
number but you want to have a dollar sign and the right number
of decimal places, well there is something called helpers which
are basically a special place to put methods whose only function
in life is to help make things pretty for views. They are not
central to do model they are not central to any computations you
do on your data. They are only there so you do not have to put
clutter code into your view and helper should also be pretty
small. As I mentioned, there are also the embedded Ruby
templates. They look a lot more like PHP which all by itself is
a reason not to use them, but the real reason to use HAML is, it
is fewer marks on the page. It is easier to follow the
indentation. It is easier to debug and once you get used to it,
it like reading Haiku. You get hooked on the elegance part. I
recommend it.