Okay, at the end of every chapter, we have a Fallacies and
Pitfalls section. We do a couple of those. The idea of fallacies
is it sounds right, but it's wrong and here's why it's wrong.
Pitfalls are these things that are warning you, learn from our
experience, and even though you're being warned, you can't help
but fall into these pitfalls. So the Agile life cycle is best
for software development. It's good for some things especially
softwares and service. I don't think NASA should be doing this
for moon shots or if you're doing something that's regulated by
the law, it's not the right thing that ... For you to do. It
doesn't have that flexibility that change. What we're going to
do is practice Agile. One valid way to do this is you get a lot
of good practices, but you're going to see the alternative like
we talked about today, we're always ... Every time we bring up a
topic, requirement solicitation, we're going to show you the
other way to do it so you'll have a broader background. You'll
deploy using Agile. You know, people ... When we talk to these
companies, like you wanted to sell a couple of things that Agile
is not used there. The other thing that I want to tell you is if
you're going to stick to this as a profession, you're going to
see new life cycles. New things are coming along every 10 or 15
years, new platforms and things and it'll be a different life
cycle than what we're talking in this class and you need to be
able to adapt, learn new life cycles so just keep that in mind.
Pitfall is ignoring the cost of software design since
manufacturing cost is 0 for software. It seems like it wouldn't
cost that much to remanufacture it, but you're forgetting the
time for design and test when you do that. I can't help but
think is this idea, well, if it's free to manufacture then it's
okay to steal it is explains a lot of behavior for all kinds of
piracy of things. This is an idea that no one should have to pay
for development and since some of you are going to be software
engineers, you should ... Before paying for software
development, that that's going to pay service. Okay, so wrapping
up this first chapter in this segment. This is what Armando and
I called the Virtuous Triangle. I think we ... I originally
called it the Golden Triangle, but we found out that that was a
cocaine region. It's some kind of golden triangle. It wasn't
good. Virtuous Triangle. These three things fit together
synergistically here. SaaS on Cloud computing and as of the
moment, how they fit together? Well, this allows the customer as
you're developing it to see it immediately. You'll be dealing
with your customer when you have these meetings and the customer
will be trying it out and trying it. SaaS on Cloud computing in
this highly productive frameworks like rails. Well, those design
patterns, what kind of architecture support built in their
framework that matches the needs of software, and finally, here
at the bottom Agile development in these highly productive tools
and frameworks. What's great about teaching this class is rather
we just get hey, you should be doing this. We can give you tools
to help you do this and we can see you using the tools and give
you feedback on the tools. This has been a very important
synergy here.