Thinking? Voting? Voting? Red and orange, and it's not quite
half and half, so, it's good to talk about. Okay, let's vote
again, vote again, voting again, voting again. Much okay. Much
convergence toward red. Let's go through the answers there.
Could we replace the call to should receive with the call to the
real find in TMDb? We could do that, but then we've coupled the
behavior of our controller test with the behavior of whatever
find in TMDb actually does. Now, this is a double- edged sword,
right? There's a very legitimate argument that says, " Well
look, if somebody actually change find in TMDb in a way that
breaks my test, that means that my test made some assumptions
about how you call that method. Somebody has now gone and
changed the methods so that my assumptions aren't true. If I was
calling the real find in TMDb, I would know that immediately.
That's true, but I think a counter argument, which is at least
as persuasive, is the role of functional and integration test
which touch multiple code paths, that's where the areas tend to
get flushed out. The goal of unit test is to really sort of
narrow down the scope, so you're testing a small piece of logic.
To do that repeatedly, over the long run it's better to leave
the seams in place and rely on integration tests and design
reviews to let you know when behaviors of change that make your
assumptions about seems obsolete. As you'll see, this is
actually a trade- off that we make a lot. Right? One of the
dichotomies between unit- versus- integration testing is the
granularity at which you're testing stuff. Unit tests are way
more detailed, you can catch more corner cases, but what you'll
find is in order to do that, you also have to make more
assumptions to isolate the test from other things that depends
on. That's how you make it controllable enough to test all the
interesting behaviors. But an unfortunate downside of doing that
is you might be faking out things that actually matter a lot. If
somebody changes these interfaces, that will affect you. You
can't really get away with focusing entirely on one of the other
kind of tests, and we're going to keep coming back for this many
times. Ensure the API to the real method matches the one that
you used in your tests. When you write your tests, especially if
you're mocking out, or if you're creating a seam for a code that
doesn't exist somewhere else, you have to make some initial
guesses about how it would be good for that code to work, and
you're making them from the point of view of the controller
who's going to call it. That's a good place to be. It doesn't
guarantee that you're going to be right. When the time comes to
write the real method, that's where the rubber meets the road.
That's the running code that's going to be in the app. Yes,
sometimes that means that you're going to have to go back and
change your test because your test began with assumptions that
were reasonable when you made them, but turned out just not you
to be borne out by the design. Totally normal. Keeping the seam
in place but if necessary changing the spec to match the real
API. That's exactly what I'm advocating. My choice would have
been number three and remove the spec because it's not really
testing anything interesting anymore. Unless it's testing dead
code that never gets called or code that has no variables or
inputs and always behaves the same way, almost every test is
testing something interesting. Among most of my coding friends,
there's kind of a proverb that could be paraphrased as, " Bugs
that you stop monitoring or that go away by themselves tend to
come back and bring all their friends." Keeping your test in
there to make sure that whatever bug you originally were trying
to prevent or trying to fix with that test, there's always a
chance that those bugs could recur. Something like twenty
percent of bugs that recur could have been prevented by a
regression test. There's actually a couple of studies we quote
in the book about that. It's very rare that removing a test is
the right thing to do, but you'll have to change them all the
time as your app evolves and that's normal. We have had students
in this class before who express shock at the idea that, " Wait
a minute. My tests were passing, I boot the code, the code is
passing, I'm all good. Now I have to make a change to the code?
You're telling me I got go change the test? But I already wrote
the test." Right? That's not the way to think about it. The test
and the code go together. Write the T in first is for timely,
that when you're changing code, you're also changing tests at
about the same time. So yes you're going to write great tests,
then you're going to write great code that passes all those
tests. Then you're going to realize that for other reasons
you've got to make a change to your code and yes, you've got to
change the tests so that they now reflect the way your code
actually works. Commenting on the test doesn't count. Removing
it from your test suite doesn't count. It's still going to be
there, right? It was there for a reason. You had some reason in
mind of what you wanted to guard against when you wrote the
test, so don't let go of that good intuition.