Now, to the official material. It's time to get into some code
and we're going to talk about Ruby in a pretty quick overview.
Of course, as you already know the best way to learn any
language is to write some programs in it. I'm going to start
with, " This is a for loop and this is a string." you guys
already know that stuff. This is an intro to Ruby at a high
level for people who have taken Java and in this specific case
of UC Berkley many of you have also taken 61A structure and
interpretation of computer programs, you're going to see some of
those ideas comeback. Those of you who are joining us out in the
wider world, don't worry if you haven't been familiar with those
ideas because they're cool and we're going to get to them, good
stuff. Let's start with just a laundry list here. What is Ruby?
It's an interpretive language, you don't compile it and run it.
It's objective oriented and as we'll see, it takes object
orientation to a whole new level beyond what many of you
probably are accustomed to because everything in the language,
even an integer is a real object. The only way anything gets
done in this language is you call methods on objects. It seems a
little bit weird but once you get used to it it's a very
powerful simplifying principle. It is dynamically typed. What
does that mean? It means that there are types in the language
but variables don't have types. Objectives have types but the
same variable can spend part of its life being an int, part of
its life being something totally different. It is a dynamic
language and hopefully in the rest of the next couple of
segments here, we're going to see some specific examples of what
that means. What it means on paper is that there's all things
you can do at run time after the program has already begun. You
can add or modify new code, you can change the definition of
existing methods after the code has begun. You can ask objects,
questions about themselves and you can create new objects based
on those properties. The only reason this matters is to the
extent that it makes programming easier to do and makes your
code easier to maintain. Whenever I try to show examples of
these things, the examples are going to be focused on how does
this feature help you write better code. How does it make your
code more readable? How does it make your code .... how does it
make you feel like you've done a better job like you've walked
away and polished a sculpture of elegance? That's really what
it's about. I'm into code beauty. Some very basic conventions to
get us started here. Names of classes. Yes, Ruby has classes,
you're going to find out that they don't actually count for as
much as you might think in other languages. In some [ elites
00:02:22] languages like Java, what class you are is all about
what you can do. What you can do is determine about what class
you are. Ruby is different, it's very meritocratic. What you can
do is really just based on your abilities. Your class doesn't
really matter all that much. This is actually true. Class names
use upper camel- case. If you've never seen the word before you
can figure out where camel- case comes from as a term. Methods
and variables usually use snake underscore case. Names of
methods, you might find that method names can sometimes end with
a question mark. It's idiomatic for a method that is supposed to
return true or false. Methods that you can use to ask questions
about objects. You'll sometimes find that are methods names that
end with a bang, not literally with a boom but with an
exclamation mark. The [ ask 00:03:07] bang character and that
usually means it's a dangerous method. Calling this method could
cause unintended side effects if you're not careful. You'll get
to seeing that. There are constants, usually constants are in
all uppercase, all upper- camel case. There are globals but we
know globals are terrible so we're not going to use them. There
are symbols. This is probably one of the first hang- ups people
get if they've not come from a language that has the concept of
a symbol. What's a symbol? The syntax for a symbol is just a
colon followed by a string of letters and underscores and
digits. A symbol really is like an immutable string whose value
is itself. The reason that in many cases you're going to find
that there are methods in Ruby and in Rails where it looks like
you could actually pass either a symbol or a string. Symbols
aren't the same as strings, it's very easy to convert between
them. There's methods two s and two [ sim 00:03:56]. When would
we want to use a symbol instead of a string? Why do they exist?
What we'll usually find is that when a symbol is involved that
connotes specialness. If I see a function that's being called
with a symbol colon rails, I should interpret that to me as
rails is one of a small number of special values that its
function might understand. It's not a function that is prepared
to deal with an arbitrary string. That's not always going to be
the case but very generally that's the case. We'll see a number
of examples of this. Variables, arrays and hashes, you're all
Java programs so this should be quick. There are no
declarations, you are free from declarations for the rest of the
semester. You can have local variables, you have to assign them
before you use them. As we'll see, when we're defining classes
and objects, the instance in class variables spring into
existence with the nil value which is also value that means
false in Ruby until the first time they're assigned. Remember, I
said that variables don't have types but objects do have types.
Here's a variable x that I'm assigning to an int and then I'm
assigning it to a string and that is totally cool. The int and
the string are different types, different classes. The variable
that refers to them doesn't have to have a type. This we can't
do because there is no declarations, right? There is a class
integer but we can't put the classes in front variables,
variables don't have classes. Some of this is just going to be
breaking out of habits that maybe you've gotten into if you're
coming from the Java world. We have arrays, plain old linear
arrays. As you can see from this simple example arrays don't
have to have all the same object in them. In Java you talk about
an array events or an array of foo bars. Ruby is just an array,
it can have whatever it wants and the elements can all be
different as a matter of fact. We can assign the elements using
a subscript, subscripts are zero based. We can also ask an array
how long it is and we'll talk about many more interesting
methods that arrays come with but they behave the way you'd
expect. We also have hashes, some languages call these
associative arrays. If you've programmed in a language like
Pearl, you're probably pretty used to this. Python has them,
they call them dict or dictionaries in Python. Here's an example
of a hash literal, you put it in braces. Again, hashes are what?
They are mapping of keys to values. Because variables don't have
to have types, they keys can be any type and the values of those
keys can be any type. They don't all even have to be the same.
Here's a hash that has two keys, one key is the single character
string A, another key is the symbol B. Remember, that's
different from the string. In fact, what is the value of the
symbol B key is an array. Again, just like with arrays, we can
mix up the types of the keys and values. We can dereference that
array and set it zero with element to something. We can ask the
hash what its keys are then we get back a plain old array which
is just a list in some arbitrary non- guaranteed order of what
the hashes keys are and there's ways to go through them as well.
Methods, everything is passed by reference, everything except
integers. We'll come to that in a minute. I can define a
single ... here's a function foo that takes two arguments and it
actually returns an array or a list of two things. I can define
functions that have arguments with optional values. This is,
when I call the foo function, the second argument is optional
and if I don't have the value supplied for the second argument
it gets zero by default. When I call a function like the one
I've defined here that actually returns a list of things, I can
assign the result either to an array and then I can dereference
it or I can just assign the result to individual variables.
Again, a lot of the stuff, it's in the reference manuals and so
on. I'm just trying to give you a very high level, a whirlwind
tour of the language so that you could use to reading code in a
language that you may be haven't seen before. Control flow and
statements, moving right along here. Statements end with a
semicolon or a new line but a new line is way more common. In
fact, getting back to the code beauty thing, a really nice thing
about ... one of the other things I do besides writing Ruby code
and teaching great students at UC Berkley is I'm a musician. I
do musical theater work, I do a lot of orchestration and if
anybody played jazz, one of the great things about putting
together a chart of jazz music for a jazz musician is you want
to minimize the number of marks on the page while still
communicating everything that the musician has to do. I tend to
think of programming the same way. In fact, I've gotten to the
point where I like using single quotes around strings instead of
double quotes because it's less pixels on the screen. I'm
serious. It's a compulsion. Where I'm going with this is that in
Ruby even though semicolons can be used to end statements, you
never see them. You put each statement on its own line because
that's easier to lead. It's less stuff per line. Now, does that
mean that you can't break a statement across lines? It means you
have to be careful with the parser. Here is two examples of a
statement, one of which will parse correctly where the line
break is after the word unless. I'm going to raise a boom
exception unless the ship is stable. It would be incorrect to
put the line break after raise boom because this statement by
itself, raise boom, is actually a legal Ruby statement all on
its own. In this case the interpreter would be confused because
it stops parsing the statement here and then I have this unless
and where am I. We have all the same basic comparison operators
you've already seen. As we'll see in a moment the equal tweedle
and bang tweedle are used for regular expressions among other
things. There is Boolean true and false. There is Boolean nil
which evaluates as a false value but isn't the same as false.
Don't panic. We have the usual control flow constructs. We have
if, then, else along with else, ifs. We have while or until and
what are these weird things down here? One up to 10 or 10 times.
You can try to think of these as loops but I'd really rather you
didn't. In a couple of more sections we're going to talk about
blocks and iterators. What these really are is a completely
different way of thinking about iteration. Instead of thinking
about loops we're going to think about objects that manage their
own traversal. Let me say that one more time, objects get to
manage their own traversal. If I am a binary tree I get to
manage how my elements are traversed. If I am an array, I get to
manage how my elements are traversed and usually that would be
in straight line order. In fact, I can define an arbitrary
object or data structure that if it has more than one element,
it gets to decide how those elements are traversed. As we'll
see, these examples containing up to and times are really just a
way of saying, “ I'm going to in place to find a sequence of
numbers and it's going to manage how it's traversed.” We'll come
back to that later. Strings and regular expressions. Regular
expressions are so your friend. This would be a great time to
start reviewing regular expressions. We'll do a very quick
review here and there's a great site called rubyler, seriously,
rublyer. com where you can test out regular expressions against
strings and make sure that they do what you want. How do you
express strings? We've got double quotes, we've got single
quotes, we've got % Q which means treat this string the same as
if it had been in double quotes. Why would you use that? For one
thing, you could put double quotes into the string. Similarly %
q, treat the string as if had single quotes around it. What's
the difference between those? One example is a double quoted
string, you can interpolate an expression. Noticed that I say an
expression. When you have a pound braces construct inside a
double quoted string you could put any Ruby expression there of
arbitrary complexity. It's bad form to put something in it
that's super complex just because you can do something doesn't
mean you should do something. In a single quoted string that
doesn't work, single quoted strings are like verbatim. What
about regular expressions? For reasons that you'll understand
better after you've done some Ruby programming, you can actually
put the string on the [ rejects 00:11:40] on either side of the
equal tweedle operator which is the matching operator. Here, I'm
going to take the string fox@ berkley. edu and I'm going to
match it against this regular expression. Now, as you all know,
because you all know regular expressions and I'm just going to
review it. As you all know this regular expression says, “ Match
zero or more of any type of character followed by an @, followed
by zero or more or any type of character, followed by a dot, the
backslash means this dot is not a wild card it's actually just a
dot, followed by the letters edu, followed by the end of the
string.” In this case, the regular expression match would
succeed. Now, what about the fact that edu is an uppercase on
the left side but lowercase on the right side? That's okay
because the trailing eye on the regular expression says, “
ignore case”. Again, if you've programmed at other scripting
languages like Pearl or Python, some of these syntax is heavily
overlapped with those languages. I could switch the order of
these on either side of the equal tweedle, that works just as
well. The return value of this expression is if there was any
kind of a match, I get a true value. If there was no match, I
get a false value. If the expression contained parenthesized
groups in the event of a match, the variables dollar one through
dollar, however many groups there were capture the partial
matches. In this simple example that I used, dollar one would
evaluate to fox because this first group of any characters
before the @ sign matches the first group of characters in my
name. Dollar two would match Berkley because the second group of
parents matches these group of characters, it's before the .
edu. Learn them, know them, love them. Lastly, other ways that
we can write regular expressions, the slashes are the most
common idiom, many languages including Pearl and Python also use
them. You can also construct them the long way by saying
construct a new [ rejects 00:13:35] and there's also this % R
brace notation which you don't see very often but just in the
interest of exposing you to all of these things.