Based on that, here’ s a question about migrations. Even though
you’ ve technically not seen them until five minutes ago but
based on what you’ ve seen about Rails, based on what you know
about Ruby and yield and how that stuff works, this is a snippet
of the up method that I just showed you in the example. The
question is when it has create table and something is yielded
back to this due block, what is probably the type of thing that
is yielded back? What would be a reasonable assumption of what
kind of a thing T is in this example? Is it an object that
represents the database? An object representing an instance of
the model? An object representing a database table or given the
information we have, it could be anything and it’ s not fair to
ask the question. What does everybody else say? What does
everybody else say? We have red and green appear to be the most
popular options among those who are voting. Those who are not
voting, you must be thinking about something else. Talk it over
for a little bit and let’ s see if we can converge between red
and green. Shall we try a revote? Revote says, I think red has
won the America’ s Cup of this question. Although there are
still people holding up for green. Let’ s go through the answers
here. What kind of thing might TB …? When you’ re looking at
code and you’ re not familiar with the code apriori, it is a
good skill for software engineers to have to try to infer intent
from the code that the program will route. If the program will
route their code well according to some of the habits that we’
re going to try to teach you all, then in some cases, you should
be able to use things about the code like method names and the
context in which things are used to make some inferences even if
you haven’ t seen it before. If we apply that in this example,
there’ s a couple of things we could say here. Could T possibly
be an object representing the database? What are we doing with
T? There’ s a method on it called datetime. There are methods
that you saw in my original code snippet like string and text
and integer. Does it really make sense to talk about calling
methods like that an entire database? I would be skeptical
because a database consists of a collection of tables. This
could apply to anyone of them. Could it be an object
representing an instance of a model? We’ re talking about the
attributes of models in general. We’ re saying that movies in
general have a release date, have a string, have a something.
These are statements that are about the class as a whole; they’
re not a statement about a particular instance of that class. It
seems less likely that it represents an instance of a model.
What about the hypothesis that it could represent a table? Let’
s see. It’ s an argument to the create table call. It’ s talking
about the kinds of things tables care about. Tables care about
attributes that have names and types like an attribute named
release date whose type is datetime. That in my opinion would be
the most reasonable assumption and it is in fact the correct
one. What actually is being yielded here is an object that
essentially represents the table that is going to be created and
is allowing you to set up things about that table. In one sense,
you could say this, “ It wasn’ t a fair question because you
weren’ t allowed to look at the documentation and so forth. It’
s also I think an opportunity to take a look at somebody tried
to write code and name methods and use them in a way that would
give you some clue as to what they’ re trying to do even if you’
re not familiar with that part of Rails. That’ s where we are
with that.