Which statement is not true ... I didn't realize that many of
these ended up in this lecture. That's okay, though. Which
statement is not true regarding the scalability of SaaS apps?
Shared- nothing clusters scale better generally speaking than
system built from mainframes, relational database scale better
than so- called " NoSQL" databases, the programming language
used isn't a main factor in scalability and scalability can be
impeded by any part of the app that becomes the bottleneck. One
of these statements is not true, other things being equal. Not
true. Initial vote says ... I think yeah, different people's
smartphones have different shades of green but I think it's ...
you're holding up a thing that's got four colors, you're not
allowed to do that. That's better. Green is indeed correct. This
was not the world's most challenging question, but it's really
an excuse to bust a couple of myths around the other ones. Given
that we just talked about one reason that you might use a NoSQL
database is that you run into scalability problems, that should
make it pretty obvious why green is the non- true statement
among these choices. Looking at the others, shared- nothing
clusters scale better than systems built from mainframes. The
first search engine that beat AltaVista by having a larger
vocabulary was built in this exact way. It's not uncommon for
large SaaS sites to employ hundreds of servers in a cloud
computing cluster, the average capacity of which dwarfs the
largest mainframes that ever have been built. In fact, there was
an interesting comparison about how much Amazon EC2 capacity it
would take to equal the computational capacity of Watson. As
Dave Paterson pointed out in Early Election, you could rent the
equivalent of Watson's computational capacity for less per hour
than many attorneys and accountants charge. It is absolutely
true that shared- nothing clusters do scale better. The trick is
that you have to architect your software so that it runs well on
a shared- nothing cluster and the kind of app architecture we've
been looking at is largely geared toward ... we have these great
scale clusters, what choices can we make so that our apps will
be able to be deployed on them? What about the programming
language used isn't a main factor in scalability? This statement
is true and I think doesn't get the recognition that it
sometimes deserves. For a long time, people obsessed over the
performance of languages, " Oh, you're using an interpreted
language, what a wimp. If you compiled it, it would be a lot
faster." Computers are what, a million times faster now than
when the C Language was invented? Moore's law has blessed us,
let us not squander the blessing. If you can scale your
application out by adding more computers in a cloud computing
setting, then the performance you're getting each computer is
not really that critical, as long as it's good enough. People
obsessed about performance way too much, and as John Ousterhout
and others pointed out, the best performance improvement is the
one that goes from the non- working state to the working state
of an application. The reason we've invented modern languages,
even though they have a performance cost, is that they allow you
to focus more on the what, as opposed to focusing on the gory
details of the how. The programming language used really is not
a factor in scalability, and if the other person is using a
better language and gets their app running faster than you do
and they beat you to customers, then so much for performance.
Lastly, scalability can be impeded by any part of the app that
becomes a bottleneck. Again, clearly a true statement on its
face, but it doesn't get the actual attention it deserves. When
the app is running too slow, people immediately start scrambling
for things like, “ Let's change the language we're using, let's
get faster servers, let's get add more memory.” A thing you
could actually do is measure the app. You could measure and find
out what part of the app is slowing things down, and when we
talk much later about operations and how to deal with dev ops,
there are tools that will allow you to run the app and say, "
The only reason my app is slow is these five lines of code are
really idiotic and they're written backwards, and if I just
change these five lines, the problem goes away." Scalability,
there's many ways that an app could fail to scale, and when it's
not performing the way you want or not performing the way you
want, the first thing you need to do is understand what's going
on that is breaking. It could be anywhere. People think, " Oh,
the database doesn't scale. My app is too slow. Therefore, the
problem must be that I'm running into the database limitations,"
probably not true. We're going talk about pivotal tracker later
on, which is a tool for letting you keep stories about your app
on the web and stuff. All of pivotal tracker for the whole world
runs on a single server with a single database. Most people who
say the database is the problem just haven't been in business
long enough. Look for the scalability bottleneck and sometimes
it's much easier to resolve. We're done on that question.