Which statement about teams in general is true? As compared to
scrum, plan and document, project managers act as both scrum
master and the product owner. Teams should try to avoid
conflicts at all costs. Plan and document processes can have
much larger teams than scrum which then the members report
directly to the project manager. As studies show that 84% to 90%
of projects are on- time and on- budget, plan and document
managers can promise customers a set of features for an agreed
upon cost by an agreed upon date. Which statement is true? Okay,
ready, set, vote. Alright, you should definitely talk this one
over. Let's vote again and then we'll go over this. Ready, set,
you should be voting as pairs. Okay, vote. It's red and orange,
looks like [ down 00:00:58]. What are they? Teams should try to
avoid ... let's do the greed one which somebody voted for. Teams
should try to avoid conflicts at all costs. You guys got that
right, that's false. Because while conflicts needs to be
resolved they can be helpful in finding the best fast forward
for a project. Blue was 84% of the projects are on- time. I'm
still stunned that that's the fraction of things that are late.
It's all based on being predictable and it's almost always not
predictable. They do, but nevertheless, if you're then planning
document manager, you go ahead and promise all these things.
Yeah, it's going to be on time, it's going to cost this much and
it's going to have all these features. Ninety percent of the
time this doesn't work. What's left? Plan and document can have
much larger teams than scrum which report directly to the plan
and document manager. Yes, they do hierarchically. They have
scrum sized teams but they put a bunch of them together and they
could build a big hierarchy, a much bigger team. The plan and
document managers do act as both the scrum master and the
product owner. They deal with all the interactions with the
customer so that they have the kit and they tell you what to do.
Let me move ahead.